A SENSE OF FAMILY
I did warn you, Hélène.
You can't have dialysis forever.
There's only one solution:
a transplant.
You mentioned a brother?
Two. I have two brothers.
That's even better.
Are they healthy?
Do you get on well?
Yes, of course, but...
It isn't a good idea.
- What time do I start?
- 7am.
Fuck! 7am...
- That's very, very early.
- Yes.
It won't be easy.
I'm not a morning person.
7am is the time
I usually go to bed.
I see. Sorry to remind you,
Mr Lopez, but...
- Perez.
You have no qualifications.
No high school diploma.
It was deliberate.
Or I'd have ended a teacher,
like the rest of the family.
I was dead bored at school.
No way am I going back!
Right.
What would you really like to do?
Write.
Writer, novelist,
songwriter,
anything to do with writing.
That's great, but publishers
looking for manuscripts
rarely call us.
You're taking the piss!
- It is my turn.
- Yes!
I understand.
OK. Right, well, I...
I'll go then.
No. Mr Perez, I'm certain.
It isn't skin cancer.
- Shouldn't it be removed?
- Honestly, it isn't necessary.
If it's removed,
will it be analysed?
Yes. Always.
But why analyse it
if it isn't cancer?
It's the rule.
One never knows.
- You're not 100% sure.
- Yes, I am 100% sure.
Don't contradict yourself!
If you're sure, you bin it.
Let's not bankrupt the system.
- Because you aren't?
- I contribute.
Mr Perez,
you have consulted me 4 times
for insignificant spots.
The last time it was a blue spot,
which turned out to be ink.
Right, I'll go.
How much do I owe you?
Nothing.
I don't dare ask
Yvan and Max myself.
I'm not up
to calling them.
- I'll tell them.
- They'll feel they have to.
- Look, darling,
they'll agree because
they're your brothers
and it's the only solution.
Your dad and I are sure.
But there's Alice too.
They're married.
They have to decide together.
Maybe Yvan will agree, but her?
OK. I'll talk
to Alice too.
Just stop thinking about it.
OK, my love?
Come on, be brave.
Love you. See you soon.
Alright, children, listen to me!
Nassim! Stop, Nassim.
Come on, stop!
Right...
I'll start again.
Thank you!
Thanks for waiting quietly.
We're going to discuss
a great French author.
Look and listen.
Voltaire.
Get out your books.
Hey!
Awesome, huh?
And... did he read it?
He read it.
And?
Right.
I thought it wasn't great.
He thought it was crap.
Hey, honey,
give me Max's lyrics.
"I'll take the plane or the boat,
even if I can't float."
- Fab!
- Powerful.
- Makes you want to travel, huh?
- Yeah.
"Our voices clash,
our bodies smash."
Sounds like you used a dictionary:
the pages with "SH".
You're saying it wrong.
Obviously, it sounds bad.
You're deliberately ignoring
the poetry of my lyrics.
I was aiming for something between
Verlaine and Boby Lapointe.
That kind of thing.
The approach of a poet, basically.
Poet, right!
I don't need a poet.
I need a songwriter.
But I'm a songwriter too.
It's so annoying!
- I work for loads of singers.
- Which singers?
Look, that really isn't the point.
Either you like it or you don't.
Tell me.
I can't talk about it.
For instance, Bénabar.
Bénabar writes his own songs.
- No, some of them...
- Goodbye.
Yes, it's bright green.
Did you drink a mint cordial?
- Last night.
- It's the colouring.
Sir?
- Excuse me.
- That's OK.
- Temerene.
- Do you have a prescription?
- No.
- You need a prescription.
- Lexenan, then.
- For that too.
Apanyl?
If you want to sleep,
I have verbena.
- Are you new here?
- Why?
- I don't know you.
- I don't know you either.
Olivier, this is Yvan,
my husband.
Olivier Lebrun just arrived.
A pharmacy student.
Alice, do you sell drugs
without a prescription?
No, never.
Or just by accident.
Make sure such accidents
don't happen too often in the future.
- Why does he speak to you like that?
- He's the boss's son.
Really? Shit!
I couldn't say so earlier.
He's got it in for me.
Why?
He tried chatting me up
and I ignored him.
But go easy on him!
Be nice to him.
So you can have your drugs?
No. But when a guy chats you up,
you can be...
See?
I'll sleep with him
so you can get your drugs for free!
You don't have to sleep with him!
Don't get carried away.
You could...
I don't know.
I could?
Kiss him.
Kiss him?
A peck.
- Are you serious?
- Only kidding.
What's the matter?
Yvan, you can kiss me.
Give me a kiss!
- He knows you're my hubby.
- I don't care.
Give me a kiss!
Hi.
- Your brother's here.
- Amazing!
- You look poorly.
- I went to bed late.
Thanks, Mum.
You're late.
Dad, it's Sunday.
2:10 pm. It's a new record!
You're taking the piss.
What is it? What's wrong?
Look at me.
Oh dear! Migraine,
tummy ache, and piles!
- Hi, Alice.
- Hey.
- Still together?
- I couldn't find better.
- You didn't look.
- We'll end up inviting you alone!
Stop moaning.
What's up?
- Sorry to disagree with you.
- You never agree.
It isn't the point.
We just stuff kids' heads with facts!
What would you know?
You got expelled three times!
Just because you're teacher...
Excuse me.
Could you listen to me?
Don't mention it.
We've something important
to tell you.
- It's your sister.
- Has she got worse?
- She's not improved.
- How is she?
The dialysis is wearing her out.
Her doctor has asked her
to think seriously
about a transplant.
I've always said she needed one!
She's on the waiting list.
- It could take years.
- There's another solution.
- A living donor.
- Of course.
Yes.
Where will she find a living donor?
In her family.
- "Her family"?
- Her family.
And the only family she has
is us, obviously.
And you're too old.
Yes. Unfortunately.
- Who would it be then?
- You.
Me?
Or your brother.
- We give a kidney.
- It's a transplant.
It isn't a problem!
- I'm just saying that it's us.
- How will we decide?
We'll see which of you agrees.
If it's for Hélène, it's yes.
There's no need to think about it.
We'll even give her two,
if need be. Yvan?
Er, yeah...
- There you go.
- Two.
And you, Alice?
You can have a say.
I, er... If Yvan agrees,
I agree.
Hang on, because I mean...
Is it a delicate operation?
- Could we die?
- No.
- Right, well, then.
- In theory, yes.
But in practice, medicine today...
When you're dead, that's it.
It's hard for those you leave.
- It's like for jerks, isn't it?
- Max!
We're not each giving her a kidney.
We agree on that.
So it's Yvan or me.
It has to be the healthiest.
Yvan, your results are perfect.
You're not a doctor!
I'm your wife. I know.
You have tests all the time!
We'd know if you were ill.
In any case, they check everything.
To donate a kidney,
if there's any problem at all,
you're eliminated.
I don't get it.
They could find something serious?
What kind of thing?
- I don't know.
- You look poorly.
- Maybe it's a blood clot!
- Don't pick on him.
I'd check.
You look a bit yellow.
Enough!
Hélène is moving in next week.
She can't be on her own.
She's stopping work
and doing her dialysis in Paris.
Well, boys?
Do you agree?
She'll die otherwise.
Don't worry.
No one's going to die. Huh, Yvan?
- Shall I run you a bath?
- Not right now.
- What's that?
- A forum on transplants.
Forums are nonsense!
"I spent a week in hospital.
"It took me a month
to recover completely.
"Living with one kidney
is no problem whatsoever.
"You're not more tired.
You can lead a normal life."
I said yes right away,
without hesitating.
When it's about saving your sis,
you don't hesitate.
- That's so brave.
- Yes, I know.
Right. To donating organs!
Don't try to impress me
with your quotes.
Give me your emotions.
Be personal.
Benaroche,
aren't you working?
- I've finished, sir.
- What's that?
Show me your essay.
It's blank.
You've written nothing.
- I've nothing to say.
- About friendship?
It's a crap topic.
Think about it.
Draw on your personal experience.
Don't you have friends?
I don't want to write bullshit.
Give me a zero.
- I don't care!
- Well, I do.
When I put zero,
it's a personal failure.
- Give me a break.
- What's your problem?
I've got a problem
with people who do my head in.
I forbid you to leave.
Benaroche!
- Why do you want my car?
- To go to Lille
to get Hélène.
She's got a big case.
They won't send her
by ambulance.
- Why are you going?
I have the time.
I'm on top of my work.
I'll go then return your car.
Besides, you've got a scooter.
- I'm free tomorrow.
- Yvan, you don't like driving.
- Why not let him go?
- Hi, Alice.
How are you?
What's cooking tonight?
- Spaghetti. Coming?
- I can't.
I'm not alone. Vanessa!
Come say hi.
My bro, Yvan.
His wife, Alice.
Hi, bro. Hi, Alice.
Hey!
Tell your fiancée to get dressed.
Hey, we're at home!
Come off it!
"Your fiancée"!
You're so old-fashioned, you are!
I'll pick up the car tomorrow.
- Alright?
- Are you deaf?
I'll go. She's my sister too.
I never said she wasn't!
I'm saving you a trip,
and you shout at me.
It's true. You're right.
Come closer, Max.
And don't move.
Don't move.
That felt good!
Yeah, right!
Why don't you show up
completely starkers?
Shake your butt in his face!
What time did you say we'd be there?
I didn't.
- At this rate, it'll be tomorrow.
- I'm going at my pace.
Yeah, it shows.
You're going at your pace!
No way are you smoking!
- There's an ashtray.
- Yes, but you can't smoke.
- A non-smoking ashtray?
- Precisely!
What crap!
No, Max.
Don't drop your ash outside.
It blows back into the car.
- Put it out!
- Stop, Yvan.
Put it out, please, Max!
OK, OK!
You're a fucking tyrant!
I can't not smoke
all the way to Lille!
If you'd said,
I'd have worn a patch.
Just quit. For the transplant,
they check your lungs.
Why are you hassling me?
I don't even smoke 10 a day.
For the transplant,
maybe they'll check your brain!
Even the lorries are overtaking us!
You drive too slowly.
70 is dangerous.
Come on.
Come on, Max!
Mind if I finish it?
I don't believe this.
Why didn't you go earlier?
I piss when I need to, not before.
Do you need a shit too?
What are you doing?
I'm taking the wheel.
- You don't have your licence.
- I do. And I want to drive.
- Can't I drive the car?
- Show me your licence.
- I've got it. Let me drive.
- Get out!
Let me drive.
Hurry up, I'm going!
Go on. Be very careful.
Max! Stop!
Max. Max! Stop!
It's deliberate.
- What is?
- You're doing 140.
No, I'm not.
I'm barely doing 135.
Your car needs to breathe.
Hear how happy she is.
Can you hear her purring?
She's loving it, for once!
Save your dumb euphemisms
for your bar buddies!
Now just slow down,
or I'll take the wheel right now.
What a pain in the ass!
What's up with you?
Have you got your period?
Slowly.
The police.
Fuck, they're after us!
- Belt up!
- Stop.
OK, I'll pull over.
Belt up. Quick!
- Blow in here, sir.
- It's 8 in the morning.
- I didn't ask you the time.
- I had a coffee.
I didn't ask you what you drank.
Blow. Blow.
Zero.
Your MOT expired a week ago.
It isn't my car, it's his.
- Didn't you do your MOT?
- I couldn't.
His car is perfectly fine.
It drives well.
- You committed an offence.
- He did.
We'll forget about the speeding.
But I'll have to fine you
for having no MOT.
That'll be 135 euros.
If you pay now, it's 90.
We'll pay now.
- It's fifty-fifty.
- What? But it's your car.
It isn't for speeding.
It's your fault.
- The MOT is important, huh?
- Obviously.
You check the car before driving.
It's irresponsible not to!
Absolutely.
What happened, sir?
I'm not to blame.
Sis!
- OK?
- Was the drive alright?
My darling Linette,
you live so far away!
I thought I was going to be asked
for my passport.
- It's sweet to come pick me up.
- It's normal.
- Look.
- What's that?
We brought food.
There's a bit of everything.
Your place is so cute!
It's a girl's flat.
You can feel a woman's presence.
What are these photos?
Where did you get them?
They're old.
Didn't Mum give you the same?
No way. Mum doesn't love us.
- Tony Danza in Who's the Boss?
- That's true.
You do look like him.
Are you sure Dad isn't Tony Danza?
I wanted to say
that what you're doing for me...
But you can still think about it.
If you change your mind, it's OK.
Listen to me.
We have no intention
of changing our minds.
Just so it's clear.
Huh, Yvan?
Are you nuts?
What would we do without you?
Remember what
she used to sing before bed?
- "Before bed"?
- You were a boys band fan.
- It was only for 1 month.
- It went on for 2 years!
You had the posters.
She wanted to go to the concerts.
- She made us learn the lyrics!
- What was that about?
Talk about a crush!
- What was her morning song?
- I'm not helping you.
Leave one day
And never look back
When love goes away
You gotta change tack
Come and sit down.
Sit down.
We haven't changed a thing.
You could have.
I wouldn't have minded.
What did I tell you?
Your dad never wants
to change anything.
You're lucky.
Our room has become a box room.
It is too!
Shall I close the curtains?
Want to rest?
It's OK, Dad.
It's 3 in the afternoon.
- Make yourself at home.
- It's good you're here.
How did you find her?
- Hélène?
- Yes.
- Fine. Why?
- I thought she looked poorly.
You think
the whole world looks poorly.
In any case,
we never agree on anything.
You're always so anxious,
you don't enjoy the good times.
This is a good time?
Our sister is ill,
one of us have to make a sacrifice.
My head hurts!
Shit, look!
And you say we're lucky!
It isn't about luck.
You park illegally, you get fined.
- What was that?
- Nothing. Get in.
You park illegally, you get fined!
You feel guilty about your sister
because she's always been ill,
and you're healthy.
Guilty.
Yes, that's right. Guilty.
Guilt.
As for my brother, I feel no guilt.
With him, it's more like jealousy.
Jealousy, yes.
You feel guilty
about your sister
and jealous of your brother.
- Now you'll say, "And love?"
- I'm saying nothing.
But there is love
and affection, for sure.
For my sister,
even for my brother.
The thing is,
I don't know if he loves me.
What do you mean?
It's like he looks down on me.
He's always thought I was crap.
Then again,
I've done nothing amazing.
I've written 2 stories for free mags
and a novel no one wants.
That's why
if I could donate my kidney,
if I'm chosen,
I'll feel I've achieved something,
served a purpose,
and he'll look at me differently.
- He'll look at you differently.
- Yes.
Is that important?
You're weird.
You know what?
We'll stop here for today.
- The session isn't over.
- Well, I'm done.
Stay if you like,
but I'm out of here.
See you next week.
Goodbye, Doctor.
I feel so much better.
Your blood tests show
you're both compatible.
Great!
But before I explain
what's going to happen now,
I'd like to congratulate you
for your gesture
and your physical courage.
- "Physical courage"?
- You need it.
It's an operation after all.
But you'll be saving someone's life.
Thank you.
It's an operation.
As you're both volunteering,
you're doubling
your sister's chances.
But as we will not remove a kidney
of a person in poor health,
you'll have a battery of tests
and we'll pick whoever
is in the best condition.
- He is.
- No. You are.
That's a lie. He is.
He's strong.
What kind of tests
are we talking about?
The heart,
the kidneys, the lungs...
Basically, we'll check everything.
Then the person who is chosen,
if one of you is chosen,
will go before a committee
which will agree or not
to the operation.
- Alright.
It's a formality
to protect the donor.
- OK.
- The living donor.
If we die,
our family can't sue the doctor?
- No.
- Alright.
But let's avoid hypotheses which...
Always the worst.
You've got a one-track mind:
the worst, the worst!
Yes, hello?
Really?
How did that happen?
I was sure it'd be fine.
I can't talk now.
I have patients.
No. I'll call you...
I'll call you after.
Call the insurance company,
the agency,
and turn the water off.
Sorry,
my wife panics over nothing.
I hear you!
Right. Let's get back
to our discussion.
- What's that?
- Homeopathic pills.
The first thing we'll check
is your lungs.
Hello, I'm here for a lung x-ray.
Your health card, please.
- Mr Perez.
- Yvan Perez.
Here. Perfect.
Take a seat, please.
Come here and place
your chest against the plate.
Put the chain in your mouth.
Press up against the machine.
An arm on each side.
We'll tell you to expand your lungs.
Expand your lungs.
Hold your breath.
You may breathe.
You may breathe, sir. Sir?
Let go of the handles.
Get dressed, please.
You can get dressed.
It's over.
It's bad, isn't it?
- Do you smoke?
- Not at all. Why?
How's my x-ray?
Jérôme!
Could you come here?
I'm a goner, aren't I?
No need to be a smoker
to have a lung condition.
Please, sir.
It isn't that bad yet.
- But it soon will be!
- Calm down, sir.
I am calm.
Tell me what's going on.
- Well, this area here...
- Yes.
We don't understand.
- We can't read it.
- What now?
We'll do another.
- Excellent! Your lungs are perfect.
- Thank you.
You had me scared.
I can feel my heart!
I have an appointment.
- Put that out, please.
- Sorry.
- May I?
- Go ahead.
- Your appointment?
- For a lung x-ray.
Your health card.
I wasn't told I'd need it.
- Your name?
- Perez, Max. Perez with a Z.
- OK. Can you wait?
- Of course.
"This Eastern splendour
Would appeal
"With its tranquillous native tongue.
"There, all is order and loveliness,
"Luxury, calm and voluptuousness."
Benaroche.
Knock before entering
and give me your note.
Don't do my head in.
Pretend I'm not here.
- I'll call you back.
- Your mobile!
I've put in on silent.
Continue your thing.
If you'd been on time, Benaroche,
you'd have heard my thing
is Baudelaire.
- Charles Baudelaire.
- Yes. Baudelaire.
I sent it to ten publishers,
and so far
four have turned me down.
For the others, I've no illusions.
But it's OK, I'm not demoralized.
I enjoy writing.
When I'm sick of it, I'll stop.
Seeing anyone?
Don't you start too!
Don't you think it's time
you led a more stable life?
I don't feel ready for that.
When you are, it might be too late.
You sound like Mum.
- Introduce me to your girlfriends.
- Like you need me!
And you?
I feel ready,
but men don't seem to.
How's...
What was his name?
The big funny guy with a beard.
Thierry.
- Why aren't you with him?
- That was 5 years ago.
He's fine.
He got married and had a kid.
And since then?
- Do you want coffee?
- What time is it?
11. No. I'll have a beer.
- We're pretty lucky this year.
- No troublemakers.
That's rare.
You're lucky.
I've got a really tough one.
Verging on aggressive.
- I don't know how to handle him.
- Who is he?
- Benaroche.
- He's a special case.
He was well behaved.
His mum got sick.
He's really disturbed by it.
- For sure.
- What's wrong with her?
A kidney disease, I think.
If he makes trouble,
you have to report him.
Yes...
- See you.
- OK.
Philippe! You're home.
I wasn't expecting you.
How are you?
Thanks.
- So what's new in your life?
- Oh... And you?
- Still a writer?
- Yeah. Trying to be.
- How was Burma?
- Bolivia? Great!
Yes, Bolivia.
I meant to come home sooner.
You know how it is.
Jesus, you'll have to find a crib.
- No?
- Yes.
- Seriously?
- Sure.
But, Philippe,
this is a really bad time.
I don't have a plan B.
I don't give a toss, Max.
We had a deal.
I come home and get my flat back.
You haven't given me any warning!
There's loads of room.
We won't get in each other's way.
Yeah, yeah.
There's loads of room,
but I don't want to.
Philippe, you've changed.
You're acting like a bailiff!
Give me time to sort myself out.
2 or 3 weeks.
You've had a month.
That's enough.
48 hours, come on.
No.
- Why are you doing here?
- Surprise! Is the box room free?
Good evening!
You're here
and I'm alone in my huge flat.
It's silly.
That smells good.
What's for supper?
For next week,
think about donating organs.
- What organ, sir?
- Your willy.
Stop that.
Who would agree
to donate their kidney, for example?
It depends which.
Who wouldn't?
Right.
Those who didn't answer
must be undecided.
Benaroche, may I have a word?
I heard about your family problems.
My sister is sick,
and I might be giving her my kidney.
- Want to talk about it?
- No.
- Why?
- It's boring!
If you change your mind, I'm here.
- Is this room 20?
- Yes.
- Thanks.
- Ah no, there's a queue.
- Obviously!
- I didn't see. No need to get mad!
Ah, you're here!
We're together.
Have you been here long?
- About an hour.
- An hour?
They're taking the piss.
I've got stuff to do.
"Stuff"? What stuff?
Nothing, but it's really slow.
They can't do this.
They ask us to be on time.
We're together.
I'll go there.
- You're jumping the queue!
- I'm just leaning.
The problem, with my brother,
is I represent
everything he hates.
- What does he hate?
- My lifestyle,
my job, my need to be useful,
the desire to have a family.
He can't attack that,
so he attacks other things.
Such as?
My fear, my anxiety, my worries.
Once
I told him I was seeing a shrink.
He made fun of me.
He'd never go see a shrink.
- How do you know?
- It's obvious you don't know him.
But if I end up on
the operating table, well...
he won't see me in the same way.
He won't be able to say
what he usually does.
"Feeble", "hypochondriac",
"scared of everything"...
He'll have to respect me then.
You're agreeing to the operation
so he respects you?
That's rubbish.
Actually, I don't know.
Why not? Of course.
Yes, it's true.
- Professor.
- Do we have an appointment?
No. But I needed
to ask you something.
- I'm in a hurry.
- It'll only take 30 seconds.
But don't mention it to my family.
You can tell your wife.
Yes. Go ahead.
Would it be possible,
for the results of the tests...
I'm just asking.
Couldn't we maybe, for instance,
disqualify my brother?
- Disqualify him?
- Kick him out of the competition?
We say I'm in better health,
which is true,
and say he has
a minor heart condition.
When he stresses,
his heart beats fast.
Tell him he has tachycardia,
and that's why you've selected me.
You want to fix the results?
Fix them, no.
Enhance them.
Mr Perez, in my profession,
there's a code of ethics.
It's a kind of professional honesty
which forbids such things.
In 35 years,
I've never heard anything like it.
I'm not asking you
to do anything serious.
You won't get sent to prison.
I know who you are.
I'm asking you.
Just say yes or no.
The answer is no.
- Think about it.
- I said no.
- Think some more.
- I've thought enough.
I never spoke to you.
This conversation never happened.
I'd rather forget it too.
I didn't ask you to favour me.
- Done this before?
- No.
Put this on and remove your chain.
- It's a lucky charm.
- Put it on later.
I can't take it off.
It's a lucky charm
and I'm having a scan.
You can't have a scan
with a thing round your neck.
Your chain.
I'll give it back.
Expand your lungs
and hold your breath.
That's it. Great. Don't move.
OK, you can breathe.
OK, darling? I forgot my keys.
You had a call.
- Who was it?
- The professor.
The professor?
What did he want?
He wouldn't say.
You're to call him tomorrow.
- It must be bad news.
- Why?
The scan must have been terrible.
He wanted to discuss it.
- You always think the worst.
- I always think the...
- Where's the number?
- On your desk.
Shit!
- Yes.
- Hi, Max. You OK?
Did Professor Legendre
try to reach you?
No. Why?
He did me.
There's no reason
for him to call me.
- And?
- Well, I'm worried.
- That's par for the course,
isn't it?
Is that all? I'm busy.
See you, bye.
I don't like this.
Calm down.
He sounded very relaxed.
Precisely!
Doctors are always relaxed
when they announce a disaster.
I'm making dinner.
Are you hungry?
"Hungry"?
How could I be hungry?
No, no appointment.
But he called me
at home. It's urgent.
I can fit you in next week.
You can't be serious!
"Next week"?
He called me.
- Really?
- Yes!
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Mr Perez, good to see you!
Come with me.
Thank you.
Cécile, this won't take long.
Have a seat.
I called you yesterday.
It's a delicate matter,
serious even.
- Go on, just tell me.
- I'm bound
by my oath,
but sometimes one has
to bend the rules.
- But this is about me.
It isn't about you.
You're OK.
- Really?
- Yes.
I met David Benaroche.
He's one of your students?
Yes, of course. Why?
His mum is in my department,
and he heard you were going
to donate an organ.
He is very affected
by his mum's illness
and wants to give her a kidney.
I told him he was too young,
and you know what he said?
- No.
That he would go
to one of these countries where...
"Where" what?
Where with a bit of cash,
you can have an op.
You can have an op,
and even buy an organ
in conditions you can imagine.
Unbelievable!
Yes. Right, well...
He said the money
wouldn't be a problem.
Yes. His family is wealthy.
- Actually, no.
- I don't understand.
He's going to do something stupid,
you know, like rob a bank.
He's 17.
So I'm very worried
and I thought that...
maybe you could talk to him.
He really admires you.
- Admires me?
- Yes.
He isn't exactly demonstrative,
but he thinks you're very brave.
He wants to do like you.
He wants to be like you.
OK. That's fine.
That too.
Everything's perfect.
Absolutely perfect.
You just have superficial keratitis.
- What's that?
- An inflammation of the cornea.
Right! When I was small,
I was made to wear contacts
and I had a reaction.
I had big red eyes like a rabbit!
It was awful.
Wear glasses.
- No.
- Why?
They wouldn't suit me.
It would ruin my charm.
- Don't you think?
- If you say so.
I'm a thinker.
Glasses should be part of the look!
I'm a novelist.
Novelist, songwriter,
playwright and...
OK.
That's it. This is for you.
And we're done.
- Is that it?
- Yes, that's it.
Already?
- Have you seen my brother?
- Yes. He's fine too.
That's kind of surprising.
Right, well, thanks.
- Goodbye.
It's fabulous what you're doing.
- Stop! Don't be stupid!
- What are you doing, Mr Perez?
I'm taking money out.
- Really?
- Um, yeah.
- Ah! OK?
- Er, yeah.
- Come chat.
- No.
Just two minutes. Come on.
OK?
I spoke about your mum
to Prof. Legendre.
Listen to me. He never said no
about a transplant.
But you have to be fully grown.
You're only 17.
- How long will it take?
- A few years.
In the meantime,
your mum can continue the dialysis.
My sister had it for 12 years.
And your mum's renal insufficiency
is much less serious.
Forget the idea of going abroad.
Your mum will get
the best treatment here.
- Want her to risk her life?
- No.
Well, that's it then.
I know you and I
don't get on very well in class,
but we can talk outside.
When's your operation?
At the end of the year.
There's me and my brother.
I don't know who'll be chosen.
- Do you have siblings?
- A little brother who's 11.
- You're lucky.
- Yes.
Go on, more, more, more...
- How do you feel?
- Great!
Good.
You'd have made an excellent runner.
Of course!
Go easy though. Easy now.
Right, I think that'll do.
Yes! Absolutely.
Maybe I have heart trouble.
It isn't always obvious.
I'm a doctor.
I'm here. Carry on.
When Goscinny died,
his doctor was there too.
- Whose doctor?
- Goscinny's!
Asterix!
Look, I saw your brother.
He did very well.
Come on, pedal, pedal.
Me and my brother are different.
The machine
doesn't agree with you at all.
Like your brother,
you have a young man's heart.
Thanks.
Thank you, Doctor.
- Alright?
- Tired.
I feel like a lab rat.
Another day wasted with their crap!
You have important stuff to do?
What's with the dumb remarks?
I work too, you know!
It interests me to know how I am.
My body, my organs...
What else do you have to do?
What else to do I have do?
Write!
It's my job. I write.
- Ah yes, you write. I'd forgotten.
- Yeah!
You should quit.
Sorry?
You've been trying for 15 years.
You're nowhere.
It isn't your thing.
Don't be ashamed.
Talent isn't something you decide.
Who are you to judge anyway?
I go by results,
and you're not making a living.
Not yet.
- Forget it.
- Change your tone!
I'm just being straight with you.
- May I be straight with you?
- Yes.
Want to know
why I chose to write?
To not be like you.
When I see you
with your briefcase,
I'm happy I chose another life.
- There!
- What life, Max?
You live off other people.
You ask Mum and Dad
to pay your bills.
Keep your money.
This is on me.
- Got anything smaller?
- He does. But I'm paying.
For the next tests,
we won't go the same day.
I don't want to see your face.
That's for you.
I told him everything
I've held back for years.
Actually...
I regret it.
You regret it?
You don't have to tell the truth
all of the time.
It had no effect on him whatsoever.
He doesn't give a damn.
He just hates me a bit more...
He isn't going to change.
"He isn't going to change."
No. I was wrong.
I was wrong.
He's right.
Of course he's right.
What he said is true,
but I refuse to accept it.
I know I'm lazy,
a parasite, a good-for-nothing.
- I know that.
- Yes?
- Please switch it off.
- Shush.
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
When do you want to see me?
Right away?
Yes. I'm not doing anything.
Nothing important.
Yes, I have your address.
See you soon.
- Bad news?
- I have to go.
Goodbye, Doctor.
It was great.
Great!
I've read your manuscript,
The Peppercorn.
It's original, but way out there.
It lacks dramatic effect,
there 40 incomprehensible pages,
it's full of spelling mistakes.
How many publishers
have you sent it to?
- About twenty.
- Had any replies?
Yes. 5 or 6 are quite interested.
But you know what it's like,
we then have to agree.
- Who?
- I don't recall all the names.
Who was there?
There was... Le Peuplier Editions.
They were quite interested.
Cerisier literary review.
Well, it's...
- Why are you asking?
- Because I want to publish you.
- I'm hardly surprised.
- I said,
I want to publish you.
- What do you mean?
- We're publishing your book.
- Is this a joke?
- I have no sense of humour.
Alright. After what you told me,
I don't really understand.
We get rid of the 40 pointless pages,
correct your spelling
and bring out the book.
You have that little something
I'm looking for.
Um, thank you.
Thanks. It's...
I've never been published.
You have to start somewhere.
I didn't understand!
Great. Awesome.
Honey?
You're filming me?
You're late.
Anything serious?
- No, but I'm late.
- 55 minutes.
More. Much more. 20 days.
I'm 55 minutes late
because I'm 20 days late.
Hang on!
The doctor says we did a good job.
- Oh shit!
- Nice!
Is that all you can say? "Shit"?
But it's...
- You're pregnant?
- Yes.
For sure?
Sure, sure, sure!
- Isn't it great?
- It's awesome!
- We wanted a kid, huh?
- We'd stopped talking about it.
Only because of your sister,
but we never said
we'd forget about it.
Or have you changed your mind?
- When's it due?
- January, February.
Do you realize if things go wrong,
it'll be a little orphan?
The birth?
- Not the birth, the transplant.
- Don't talk nonsense.
I don't want to die
without seeing my son.
You're not going to die
and no one said it's a boy.
The sex is the 4th month.
- Who have you told?
- No one.
- I will on Sunday.
- Why "Sunday"?
It's your parents'
wedding anniversary.
Had you forgotten?
Oh no.
I got scarf for Mum
and a cap for Dad.
I'm giving them a home cinema.
- You're not?
- I am.
They're ruining their eyes
with that old telly.
It'll be delivered this week.
Plasma, full HD, 138 cm,
200 MHz, DVD player, Blu-ray,
Dolby 7.1, great sound, the works!
- They cost a bomb!
- Sure do.
- But I've made some money.
- What?
Surprise.
I just spoke to Yvan.
He didn't sound keen about coming.
Why's that?
- Max.
- What?
- Are you getting on?
- Yeah. Why?
- He asked if you were here.
- Jerk!
Where else would I be
on your wedding anniversary?
In church?
René, are they coming or not?
- They're coming, Sonia.
- The food's burning!
- So everything's fine.
- Yes, it is!
- There's a napkin missing.
- In the sideboard drawer.
- Which?
- What do you think?
- Are you parking like that?
- Yes.
You'll be able to make up.
Let me handle it.
- Don't argue at lunch.
- My brother is my business.
- You're so complicated!
- Stop defending him.
I'm not. But you're going
to spoil the atmosphere.
Wait for me!
Yvan, could you pass the sauce?
Thanks.
- Alice, bread?
- Thanks.
Me and Yvan have some good news.
- You're divorcing?
- I'm serious.
- You're pregnant.
- Yes!
- Who by?
- Very funny.
- That's fab!
- An Aquarius.
- Like me!
- I hope not.
- I've been waiting so long.
- I'll be an auntie!
It's the best gift
you could have given us.
We were despairing.
It's great. Well done!
Gramps and Nan!
- I've got some good news too.
- You're having a kid?
You're not far off, but no.
My novel is being published.
I've signed a contract.
- I got an advance. Look!
- I am.
To anyone who thinks
there's a jerk in the family
who writes crap,
well, this crap is being published
and is bringing in money.
So there!
- I'm so proud!
- Don't I get a kiss?
Right, I'll raise my glass.
- My glass, Dad.
- Mine is empty.
- Careful.
- Thanks.
Watch out. Here.
Right...
Two pieces of good news
in one day, we're spoiled.
- Thanks, kids!
- Happy anniversary.
That's right, it's our anniversary!
What a joke!
He thinks he's a writer now!
If he knew how many books
sink without a trace!
It's mad.
He thinks he's Flaubert!
- Money, success!
- It's still good news.
It will be
when he's sold 10,000 copies.
Not everyone can do that.
If it's being published, it's good.
"If it's being published, it's good"?
You can be so naive!
You haven't read it!
I've read everything.
I told him I found it
trivial and immature, like him.
Hello?
Yes. It's me.
- OK?
- Yes.
- You left in a hurry.
- I had homework to correct.
I just wanted to say
I'm really happy for you.
- For us?
- About the baby.
That's kind.
- Are you happy about my book?
- Which book? Yes. Sure.
Very happy.
I'll sign a copy
for you.
- There's no need. If you like.
I'll be the baby's godfather.
You're its uncle.
It isn't bad already.
Yeah. It isn't bad already.
Did you call just for that?
- Are you mad?
- On the contrary.
- I'm really pleased.
- Me too,
I'm really pleased.
Love you.
Ciao.
There!
Happy now?
Right.
Hello, Doctor!
Sorry to have rushed off,
but it was really important.
My book is being published.
A publisher loved it. I'm thrilled!
- Lie down.
- I haven't come to lie down.
The couch is over.
I feel good.
I've made up with my brother.
All's well. I'm cured.
- You weren't sick.
- Don't mince words.
I consulted you
because I wasn't well.
By the way, this is for you.
- How many sessions is it for?
- It's your special bonus.
When I'm happy, I show it.
- You did a good job.
- No, Mr Perez.
I have a code of ethics.
You don't want my 500 euros?
You shrinks have a real problem!
- 50 for today's session.
- If you like.
May I hug you?
When I'm happy, I show it.
I'm going to praise you.
People will be queuing up!
In a year, you'll have a Rolls.
With a chauffeur!
Next!
All the tests are done.
You're both in perfect health.
Glad to hear it!
I was sick of your tests.
- I found them instructive.
- Obviously!
The scan shows
excellent renal function
and it's identical.
- Amusing, huh?
- Very.
Very, very funny! So?
Which of us is...
- That's just the problem.
- So there's a problem.
No. Both of you are suitable
for this type of operation
without it weakening you.
It's impossible
to decide either way.
That's why I thought the decision
should be made by you.
Meaning?
You will designate the donor.
Him or me?
You're saying you want us
to decide together
who is willing
to have the operation?
From what I understand,
you're both willing.
- Yes.
- But surely one of you
is more willing than the other.
Yes. Well, yes.
- Yes.
- Of course. Yes.
It's understandable though...
you weren't ready for the question,
but you have time
to think about it.
Precisely.
When do you need an answer?
There are two important steps.
Let's say...
tomorrow.
- Ah, right!
- Or the day after.
- The day after tomorrow?
The operation is in 3 weeks,
on June 21.
June 21?
World Music Day.
- You can't smoke in hospital!
- We're outside.
- There are sick people.
- There aren't any outside.
- There are sick people everywhere.
- Where?
Everywhere!
Is that yours?
Awesome, huh?
Did you borrow it?
Yeah, I borrowed it!
No, dummy. I bought it.
Oh yeah, that's right!
I had to borrow some dosh.
Some dosh!
Can't you say money?
Right.
What about the transplant?
- You or me?
- I don't know.
We have to decide.
- Got an idea?
- I have no idea.
- What do we do?
- I don't know.
- No idea. We wait.
- You know what?
Let's toss a coin.
- You're kidding?
- No.
- Why not? Like that, we'll know.
- We'll know!
- Seriously?
- Yes!
The winner donates his kidney.
End of story!
OK. Go on, then.
Heads or tails?
I have to choose?
Hails, then.
Tails.
Tails?
- You're tails, I'm heads.
- Go on.
Heads! I want heads.
- Heads or tails?
- Heads, heads. Tails.
Nothing!
I don't want anything.
Nothing at all!
Heads or tails for a kidney.
It was heads!
It was me.
- Where is she?
- In her room.
Hélène,
it'll get cold!
What were you up to in there?
Sorting things out. Writing.
- Writing what?
- Well, I...
I wrote a note
to my friends in Lille.
I just upped and left,
without saying goodbye
to loads of people I'm fond of.
If ever anything...
Will you send it to them?
It's clear. I wrote the addresses.
It's very simple.
You just have to post it.
- When?
- After the operation. In case I...
- You're nuts.
- You must be mad!
I'm not saying it'll happen.
- It's just if ever...
- "If ever" what?
Why are you angry?
Want me to dance?
- Can't we discuss it calmly?
- No! We can't.
Sorry.
I shouldn't have asked you.
I'll ask someone else.
- Because you think...
- I'm just planning.
Alright, then.
We'll do it. OK.
No problem!
- René, you...
- Dad!
There.
That way, it's sorted.
After the operation,
you'll go back to Lille
and your friends.
You won't say goodbye,
you'll say hello.
You're already up?
It's 6:30.
I haven't slept.
Have you decided?
I'm not strong enough.
I'm not brave enough.
I can't do it.
Max doesn't care.
He isn't afraid.
Why take the person who's scared
when the other isn't?
I'm a coward.
You married a coward.
No. No, you're not a coward.
So what am I?
- Only fools are never afraid.
- Really?
I must be very, very smart!
- Have you told Max?
- Not yet.
He'll thank me.
He'll jump at the chance
to play the hero!
I've worked hard.
I've replaced the 40 pages
you wanted to cut
with a short chapter.
I'm not one to boast,
but I think it's awesome.
What's this chapter about?
I'll read it to you.
Do you have 30 minutes?
"If you assume
"everything has a meaning,
"the fact the human body
has two of every organ,
"is no coincidence.
"We have two eyes,
two upper and lower limbs.
"This binomy is..."
Binomy.
The word doesn't exist.
Who cares!
I know it doesn't exist.
I invented it so the reader
would understand me better.
That's the reason.
Binomy is evocative.
"This binomy is intriguing.
"Two organs means
there's a spare for someone.
"We can live with one lung,
one eye, one ear or one kidney."
- What's the link the book?
- There isn't one.
That's what's great about it.
It's a shambles, a patchwork,
full of digressions.
All great writers digress.
Alright, but what's your point?
That nature is perfect.
We have two of everything.
- We don't.
- We do.
- No.
- Yes!
We have one heart,
one stomach, one liver.
- You're wrong.
- Your theory,
I'm sorry to say, is feeble.
I believe in it.
I can talk about if I like.
It's my bloody book!
But I'm publishing it.
Now if you would like
to explain this crazy idea...
It isn't crazy!
Being an organ donor is important!
I'm leading the operating team.
There are six of is.
We will start with Mr Perez.
- With me?
- Obviously.
First we must remove the organ.
Yes. Of course.
It will start at 8 am and last
2 to 2 and a half hours.
- In all?
- Just for you.
We'll remove the kidney
and stitch you up.
The professor must have said
the scar won't be visible.
He didn't mention it.
How do you go about it?
We perform a laparoscopy.
We make a 5 to 7 cm-incision
to remove the organ.
Then it's your sister's turn.
Your operation will last 2 hours too.
Alright.
We'll know right away
if the transplant is a success.
- The kidney should function.
- How will you know?
To be crude, you'll start peeing.
Urine may appear
before it's stitched up.
Then you will all wake up,
and it'll be over.
What if the transplant is no good,
and you realise right away?
In such a case,
do you put the kidney back?
You return it.
That's never happened
to me or any colleague
on this planet.
When you operate on my sister,
as I'll be next to her...
Seeing as I'll be right there!
I understand your apprehension,
but it's never happened.
Have there ever been cases
- I'm just asking -
of donors not coping well?
Of donors actually dying?
You know, in surgery,
there's always a risk.
How high is the risk?
- 3 out of 1,000.
- 3 out of 1,000. That much?
There are 3.
It's best not to be one of them!
I have another question.
When I wake up,
will I know if my brother's alright?
He'll be awake, no?
Indeed, when you wake up,
you'll be able to see
how your brother is
as he'll be in the same room.
That's all.
Just one step left:
the living donor committee.
It's crucial.
- What's it like?
- It's an oral.
It's a group of doctors
who assess your suitability
and can cancel the operation.
They can cancel it?
Actually cancel it?
Everything I've done,
they can just discard it?
- Yes.
- How should I be?
Natural and determined.
Like a court jury.
If they don't like me, I'm out!
Natural and determined.
Natural and...
You OK?
- Did you sleep there?
- No. I was waiting for you.
- It's cold.
- Yes. Come on.
Get up.
You OK?
I didn't sleep a wink either.
- Here we are, Max.
- I'm scared.
I'm not up to this, Yvan.
I can't do it.
I'm not a hero.
I'm a loser.
I'm scared stiff.
No one can count on me.
True or false?
I'm not about to change now.
I love life, you see?
I feel great.
Things are starting to go well.
I don't want to be butchered.
I can't go! Not now.
I'm just a big loser.
No, Max.
I don't know if you remember, but...
Max.
I must have been 10.
Dad went to see Hélène in hospital.
While they were gone,
you made a cake for Mum.
They got home late.
You were asleep.
I said I had made it.
I remember, you bastard!
Forgive me, Max.
What are we going to do?
- I'll do it.
- You?
Yes, me.
Aren't you scared?
Of course I'm scared
but not enough not to do it.
We're going to save Linette.
OK, Max?
Thanks.
We're going to do it.
- Could you help me?
- Try me.
Don't tell me it's what I wanted.
It isn't what I wanted at all!
I want to call it off.
- You want to call it off?
- I'm having a baby!
I'm absolutely convinced
I will never know him.
When he's older, he'll be told,
"Your dad was a great guy.
"He was perfect."
Yeah, right! I'm a shit.
Sit down.
- Got any whisky?
- I don't serve alcohol.
You're not in court.
Have a seat.
Allow me to introduce Dr Lantier,
Dr Prévin, Dr Catala, Dr Bernard.
I'm Dr Giraud.
Yvan Perez.
Don't be overawed.
We're here to protect you.
You may speak freely.
It isn't a test.
We will guide you
and answer any questions
you might have.
Tell us about your family
and professional life.
My name's Yvan Perez.
I'm a French teacher,
married, with no children.
Actually, yes!
My wife is pregnant.
- Congratulations. When's it due?
- February.
- Boy or girl?
- We prefer surprises.
How's your relationship
with your sister?
Excellent.
We adore each other.
She used to be my little sister
and she still is.
- Did you take this decision alone?
- Yes.
Well, I spoke to my wife, who agreed.
And with my parents.
They agreed too,
which is normal because
they're my sister's parents.
I wanted you to know
I see a psychotherapist.
I discussed it with her.
I wondered about it.
Why do you see a psychotherapist?
Do you have problems?
No. I'm perfectly fine.
It's just that...
I've been seeing her for years.
It balances me.
Have you been told about the risks?
Yes.
Not during the operation,
but afterwards.
Your life could be different.
What do you mean?
I see you drive a motorbike.
No.
It's a scooter. It's small.
- A small scooter.
- You'll only have one kidney.
Mister Perez, you don't have
to give us ready-made answers.
There are no good or bad answers.
Just be sincere.
You're expecting a child.
Imagine he needs a kidney later,
you won't be able
to give one to him.
Yes, but my wife has two kidneys.
She's in good health.
I have your weight and height here.
Have you gained weight?
Why?
Your body mass index is fairly high.
With one kidney,
you might have weight problems.
I imagine you were told.
Yes, I was.
It isn't a problem.
Do you have any questions?
No.
I don't have any questions.
- He told you I'd agreed?
- Isn't it true?
Of course it isn't.
I'd turn the clock back if I could.
- Go on. You still can.
- How's that?
- He hasn't seen the judge.
- "Judge"?
- At the High Court.
- When?
- Right now.
- Thanks!
LAW COURTS
Mr Perez,
the judge will see you know.
Please come with me.
I would like you to sign
the organ removal form.
- Yes, of course.
- I must ask you a question.
Yes. Which question?
Are you aware you are consenting
to the risk of death?
Sorry? Could you repeat that?
I must be sure
you are aware of the risk.
It's a matter of informed consent.
It's something I must ask.
Alright.
Because actually Prof. Legendre...
Are you well aware
you are consenting
to the risk of dying?
Sorry, Your Honour,
I have to visit the bathroom.
I will ask you again.
Are you aware you are consenting
to the risk of dying?
- Actually, Prof. Legendre...
- I don't know him.
If you would please sign here.
Here.
There. Where my finger is.
It's here. Go settle in.
Please go in.
Thank you.
Actually,
this is your brother's room.
Yes.
- Are you OK, honey?
- Yes.
- Miss Perez?
Come on, I'll show you your room.
We'll come too.
- Could you take my bag?
- Yes.
Be right back.
I'll go too.
What's he up to?
What are you doing?
As you can see, I'm shaving.
At 2 am?
It'll be fine.
Are you alright?
Any morning sickness?
Alright, son?
OPERATING ROOM
Hello!
I've got good news.
It went well.
No complications.
There.
We were part of the statistics.
In other words,
the 99.97 % success rate.
My first memory
in the recovery room
was Yvan giving me
a confident look.
His eyes told me he was fine.
And I thanked him with mine.
Yvan couldn't believe he was alive!
We had loads of visitors.
Yvan had to tell each of them,
but he seemed happy to.
Max is a real writer now.
His book was published.
It won't win the Goncourt,
but he has the confidence
to write the next.
And he has a fan.
Glasses too.
Alice gave birth to baby Basile.
Yvan wasn't anxious at the birth.
He was serene.
He's like a new person.
There...
I guess that's a sense of family.
As for me,
my life isn't dictated
by dialysis now.
Despite the anti-rejection drugs
I take every day,
I don't feel there's
a foreign body in me.
My brother gave me
what was missing from my life.
I can think long term now.
Like a writer with a block,
I  have a fear of blank pages.
I don't know where to begin.
Subtitles: Eclair Group