- [birds chirping]
- [sirens wailing in distance]
[Chris Colbert] ♪ Whoop! Whoop!
It's the sound of the police ♪
♪ Whoop! Whoop!
The belly of the beast ♪
I was a street kid, beating niggas up,
robbing people, stabbing people.
I used to do all that. Carried a gun.
These people in the streets don't fight
no more. They shoot you.
[grunting]
That was the path, in the wrong direction.
♪ I ain't hating now
We the next superstar boy ♪
The whole point of this sport
is hit and not get hit.
Don't take no unnecessary punishment.
It's how long you can last.
And, you know,
how smart you can be in this game.
[Cam F. Awesome]
You don't need to be angry to fight.
Boxing, to me, is a tactical game.
Everything I do is based off logic.
It's, "Can I be smarter?"
And manning up when it needs to be done.
But there's so many variables in boxing
that there's really no such thing
as a right thing to do,
just a bunch of wrongs.
[Peter Quillin]
To express myself is through a fight.
I watch for your mistakes,
try to beat you to the punch.
There's no formula to winning.
It's a window I'm looking for.
That window closes in one second.
[buzzer rings]
[announcer] Three two-minute rounds.
In the gold corner...
- Jay Bulger!
- [crowd cheering]
My name is Jay Bulger,
and boxing saved my life.
I was just an angry kid,
getting into fights,
headed in the wrong direction.
Then, I walked into a boxing gym,
connected with the trainer,
and I found something to fight for.
To become a New York City
Golden Gloves champion.
It was so simple and honest.
You get up into that ring...
and you're exposed.
- You find out what you're really made of.
- [crowd cheering]
Years later, I've set out to capture
the state of boxing in America.
Only to find that so many of the gyms
I boxed at...
have closed their doors.
Today, most kids would rather
play basketball or football.
Do anything but get in the ring.
You can't play boxing.
It's not a game.
It's a test...
of how much you can hit...
without being hit.
The brutality is inherent...
to both its appeal and to its demise.
Now, there was a time in America
when everybody loved boxing.
When fighters like Dempsey,
Louis, Marciano, Ali and Tyson
were kings of the world.
So, for the American fighters
who still believe in boxing,
why do they do it,
and what does it take to be champion?
All I know is that there
will always be the next kid
who needs to fight their way out...
by stepping into the squared circle.
[sirens wailing in distance]
[indistinct chatter]
[Colbert] I don't know what I would
be doing if not for boxing.
I think I would have been dead
or some shit.
I've been through shoot-outs.
I've been through shelter homes.
My life was never easy.
My life's still not easy up to this day.
[indistinct chatter]
- [woman] Get out.
- Yeah, a'ight.
[woman] Get the fuck out.
[Colbert] Shit is hard, like...
I don't let it stress me, though.
Not one of them people
that let that shit bother me.
I take that shit
and I use it as a motivation
to push me to be better at what I do.
I'ma be the big champion of the world
and take my family out of the hood
and get them into a better place.
[Bulger] Eighteen-year-old
Christopher "Lil B-Hop" Colbert
is the best amateur boxer
in New York City.
He rides the subway, two hours,
every day to Flatbush, Brooklyn,
so he can train at the very last
free boxing gym in New York City,
Atlas Cops and Kids.
[man] Let's go.
I'm ready.
Welcome to Brooklyn.
[Pat Russo] What we do with the kids,
it's quiet prevention.
If the kids are in the gym,
and they're off the streets
and they're staying in school...
They'll all tell you that
the program's changed their life.
It cost us about $50,000
to run one gym, to run one gym.
A mere 50,000...
What's $50,000?
It'll cost $67,000
to put one kid in jail
for a year in this city...
which is insanity.
[coach] Come on, baby, come on.
Let's go.
These boxing gyms that created
legends and boxing champions...
seem to no longer exist.
I find it quite disturbing
because boxing has given me so much.
It has given me such a life.
And if it wasn't for boxing,
I'd, more than likely...
I would be in jail or dead.
[Bulger] Sergeant Russo, Teddy Atlas,
and the NYPD Boxing Team
understand that every kid
kept off the street
is a kid who doesn't end up in trouble.
And so, when the Police Athletic League,
the staple community boxing gyms,
shut down their programs,
they started Atlas Cops and Kids,
which has quickly become one of the most
successful boxing programs in the country.
Thank God for a program like that.
It takes a lot of those kids
off the streets.
Within six years, we built
eight national champions,
eight New York Golden Glove champions,
and now we've got a couple of pros,
you know.
[Colbert] I'm 116 fights. 113-3.
I'm a four-time national champion.
A Golden Glove champion,
ranked number one in the country.
I'm not letting nobody beat me.
One day, I'ma turn pro.
I'm destined to be world champion.
I gotta be world champion.
Jab, jab!
B-Hop absolutely can become
champion of the world.
He's got a gift, he does.
He's got something special about him.
He has the potential, he has the talent.
But it's gonna be no cakewalk.
[indistinct chatter]
[Colbert] Whoo!
The name B-Hop,
it came from the legend Bernard Hopkins.
He was like me. He came off the streets,
straight off the streets, winning.
He's the best, man. Just like me.
You know how it is.
Biologically, he's not my son.
Because people were like, "Wait a minute,
you got a son in Brooklyn?"
He's my son, but not of...
You know what I mean.
Not of my son.
[grunting]
[Sosa] Once he stepped in the ring
and learned how to fight,
he never had a fight in the street.
Five, six years
But before that,
every other weekend, every other week,
fight, fight, fight.
Now he's good.
[Colbert] Me and Sosa been rocking
since day one. He changed my life.
A lot, a lot.
He's like a father figure in my life.
You see this?
[Bulger] What's that?
Sosa Crew For Life.
You see it.
[Bulger] Who made that?
My dad.
It's a little rewarding, I mean, 'cause,
you know, saying like... that I'm his dad.
I mean, it, um...
I'm making a difference, you know.
Everything on you,
so you gotta pay for me,
- [chuckles] What?
- Wayne...
[man laughing]
my girl, and then I'ma pay you back.
Your girl?
Your girl makes more money than me.
[Colbert] Nah, you crazy.
[Sosa] Boxing got him off the streets,
but I always tell him,
"You got to be careful, man.
A lot of bad stuff happened in front
of this building, you know, but...
They don't care if you fight or not.
Remember, a bullet
is faster than your hands."
[rap music playing on headphones]
[Sosa] Yeah,
that's how my day starts, man.
Get up at 5:30, get ready for work.
Be at work by 7:00, 7:10.
Start work at 8:00.
We should be finished by 2:00.
And then, um, head out to the gyms.
[Bulger] Someone's living
the Mexican-American dream.
I don't know if you wanna call it that,
but let's say hard work pays off.
I mean, unfortunately,
I didn't realize I was a coach
until almost ten years ago, you know.
I wasted a lot of my time just...
doing nothing.
Just working, you know.
Twenty-six years of my life in this place.
It is difficult to try to manage work
and the kids.
Yeah, I have, like, 30, 40 that compete.
And to train 30, 40 kids, it's hard.
It's hard.
And if I could do boxing 24/7,
I would do this 24/7.
But at this time,
making $200 every two months,
three months, can't do it, can't do it.
You know?
B-Hop, he's been getting better
and better and better.
And if B-Hop turns out
the way we think he's gonna turn out...
four years I think I'll be out.
- Time to get to work.
- [indistinct chatter and laughter]
[Colbert] I won my last
amateur tournament.
So I was like, "Yeah,
I'ma just go pro now. Time to go.
Waste no more time."
He wanna go to the Olympics.
I'm not pressing to go to the Olympics.
When I first started, I always wanted
to be an Olympic coach.
Like, I want to be up there when...
At the Olympics, I want to be one of the
head coaches of the United States.
[Colbert] I don't care about the Olympics.
I never...
Like, that never was really my mindset,
to go to Olympics.
My mindset was always
to be world champion, to be rich,
like Floyd Mayweather.
[Hopkins] Boxing and gold medal
and being in Olympics
is dead in America right now.
Fighters, they look at Floyd Mayweather,
they look how much money he's making.
[scoffs] "Why would I go in Olympics
and get nothing,
but maybe some sponsorship from Nike?
And I can go right to the pros,
and buy me a Bugatti."
Think about it.
[Bulger] The Olympics used to be where USA
beat the crap out of the world,
where we proved we were the best boxers.
Winning the gold medal,
nothing surpasses that.
There are people who can say,
"I was a world champion
professional boxer."
But to be an Olympic gold medal winner,
very few people can say that.
It's the biggest prize
that I've ever experienced.
[cheering]
[Bulger] But in 2012,
the US men's boxing team,
the team that's won more
than any other country...
didn't win a single medal.
[announcer] The worst showing in history
of the storied United States of America
Amateur Boxing Program.
[Oscar De La Hoya] In today's era
of fighters, winning the gold
and having the responsibility
of representing your country...
it's not in their mind anymore.
The passion is gone.
[Bulger] So the question is,
who has the ability and the desire
to get USA men's boxing
back on the podium?
The answer is a lot more complicated
than you might think.
[Awesome] I started boxing in about 2005.
I was in 11th grade.
11th-12th grade, and I just did it for...
just to lose weight.
Then I started fighting, and I just kept
winning and winning and winning.
And I was like,
"Ah, maybe this isn't that hard."
Tyler, step in.
[Bulger] Cam F. Awesome is America's
all-time winningest amateur boxer.
And his trainer, John Brown,
is the president of USA Boxing.
[John] To box for America,
you know, he gave up a lot,
because, unfortunately,
the way our system is,
we don't have much money for these guys.
[grunting and panting]
So now he has to live on $1,000 a month
that USOC gives him.
And his fixed costs for his car,
his rent and his utilities is $900.
So that gives him $100 a month to live on.
I mean, I help him,
but he goes to the blood bank
about once every two weeks
and gives blood.
[breathing through teeth]
[Awesome] You do whatever you can
for money. You pick up side jobs.
You personal train people when you can,
but it's pretty tough.
A lot of people don't understand
why I haven't turned pro.
My mission, my goal, my ambitions,
it's not the money.
I want that feeling of sitting next to
two dudes from other countries
who have to sit there and look happy
while they play my national anthem
and I get a gold medal.
That's what I'm chasing.
That's the dream that I want.
[Bulger] Cam should have had a shot
at realizing his dream in 2012.
He qualified for the US Olympic Team,
but then was suspended from competition
when he failed
to make himself available for drug tests.
I have to inform someone
when I'm leaving town, and I didn't.
And that wasn't because
I was doing any drugs or anything.
It's just I had
so much going on in my life.
I was getting ready for the Olympics,
I was traveling, leaving the country.
Although I tested negative that same week
that they were gonna drug test me,
I still needed to inform them,
and I messed up.
During my suspension,
I learned a lot about myself,
I learned a lot about
the people around me.
I decided to legally change my name
and become a new person,
new attitude, new way of life.
February 16, 2013,
Lenroy Cameron Thompson Jr. died,
and then arose Cam F. Awesome.
[Bulger] With his new name, Cam F. Awesome
is giving the Olympics one last shot.
The road begins here, in Tennessee,
at the first Olympic trials qualifier.
- [bell rings]
- [man] Yeah, good work.
- [grunting]
- [indistinct chatter]
[man 1] Good job!
[man 2] Cam, you da man!
This guy is...
To me, he box crazy...
Crazy, but he wins.
And everybody would be so mad and upset,
but he's like,
"Cam F. Awesome. What do you expect?"
People are like, "What is he doing?
That's ugly. That... What?"
They don't understand that kind of style,
but the boxers he's fighting...
- [grunts]
- they understand it.
[announcer] Right, our winner,
out of the blue corner, Cam Awesome.
[crowd cheering]
[Bulger] Cam F. Awesome
got his first win tonight.
He'll have to fight three more times
over the next three days
to earn a spot at the Olympic trials,
a year from now, in Reno, Nevada.
As if it wasn't difficult enough,
this road to the Olympics
will be more dangerous than ever.
For the first time in 32 years,
Olympic competition
is taking place without headgear.
[groans]
They want to give you
the pro atmosphere... right?
But the amateur benefits.
[Tom LeGan] We've been told that safety
of the boxer is the primary concern.
There is a bit of a conflict
with the no headgear.
'Cause, obviously, this wouldn't
have happened without it.
[Bulger] There are two clear distinctions
between amateur and professional boxing.
Headgear and fighting for prize money.
Now, AIBA, the famously corrupt
International Boxing Association,
wanna make the sport more entertaining.
But here's the thing.
If one of these fighters gets a bad cut,
even from something like
an accidental head-butt,
they're out.
It's dangerous, and it's stupid.
It's not setting you up for the pros,
it's fucking you up for the pros.
You're losing a couple of brain cells
before you even turn pro.
[De La Hoya] If I didn't have headgear,
and I was getting cut,
and beat up, and bruised up,
and knocked out,
I would turn pro.
I mean, might as well get paid for it.
[John] You know, even pros don't fight
five days in a row.
Maybe the best guy
doesn't win all the time,
whoever's the luckiest wins.
That doesn't get head-butted.
A guy can't box five days in a row without
headgear without getting banged up.
It's impossible.
[groans]
Cam F. Awesome,
he's the only male we've got
that has a shot at winning the Olympics.
Winning a medal at the Olympics.
He's the guy.
And the problem is,
the rest of the world is way ahead of us.
You know, the rest of the world,
amateur boxers make a living boxing.
Ours don't.
In 2016, you're gonna
see the true amateur
that we develop here in the United States
and we've done since
the early 1900s for the Olympics,
you're gonna see them
competing against pros.
And so, that's gonna be
a big challenge for our athletes.
[Mirko Wolf] We have the impression...
Everyone in the world,
we have the impression
that USA is the number one nation
in everything.
- You are, like, the big brother. Yeah.
- [Bulger] We have so many athletes.
Like, you take care of it.
Like, you... [chuckles]
- You just know what you're doing.
- Yeah.
And you come here, and you see
the level of competition, and it's like...
If you send those kids against Russia,
man, it's gonna be sad for you.
[Bulger] At the Rio Summer Games,
our fighters will be competing with pros
without headgear.
USA Boxing is awarded funding
from the USOC based on their medal count.
At this point, they can boycott
the Olympics and protest,
or continue to send our amateur fighters
and hope for the best.
[crowd cheering]
[Awesome] The good boxers have to turn pro
because they need money.
So, we won't get medals
until we get funding.
- This is it. Ali's in the house, right?
- Thank you.
Yeah, we won't get funding
until we get medals,
so we're chasing our tail.
- If I can bring back home a medal...
- [bell rings]
I can change that.
[man] There you go!
[clapping]
[indistinct shouting and cheering]
- [bell rings]
- [referee] Time!
[crowd whistling]
[John] Beautiful.
- I think he's heartbroke already.
- Yeah.
Okay, let's keep that show going.
I like that Ali shit.
- [bell rings]
- [indistinct chatter]
[John] A little Tyson going on.
Come on! Move your hands!
Go forward! Go forward! Go forward!
[man 1] Breathe! Breathe!
- [crowd cheering]
- [John] That's enough.
[man 1] Breathe! Breathe!
[John] Good call.
[announcer speaking indistinctly]
From the 201-plus pound weight division,
by TKO,
Mr. Cam F. Awesome!
[crowd cheering]
[announcer] Great job, guys.
Congratulations. Great job.
[Bulger] It's Cam's 12th
national tournament championship,
and it qualifies him for
the US Olympic trials, a year from now.
If he wins that, he'll go on to fight the
best fighters in North and South America.
And if he places in the top three,
he'll earn a spot at the Olympic games.
All in hopes of becoming
the super heavyweight gold medalist.
[Awesome] All right.
See you guys again... soon.
[beep]
[video game music playing]
[Bulger] I grew up playing
Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!!
A game inspired
by the baddest man on the planet.
One of the most famous athletes
in the world.
But as we began filming,
we hadn't had an American
heavyweight champion in over a decade.
People always say, "Steve,
where are the great heavyweights?"
I said, "They're on the football gridiron,
or they're posting up in the paint."
And there used to be a saying, years ago,
"As the heavyweight division goes,
so goes the game of boxing."
[loud cheering]
[Bulger] We're a long way from
the Mike Tyson heavyweight-knockout era,
and the popularity that came with it.
But for the last decade,
Floyd "Money" Mayweather
has been the face of boxing.
The master counterpuncher
changed the game,
as he mitigates risk
and maximizes profits,
putting his undefeated record on the line
when the money is right.
[Paulie Malignaggi] Times change.
It's the Mayweather era now.
It's not the Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! era,
it's not the Ali era,
it's not the Joe Louis era,
the Rocky Marciano era.
Things change and the eras move on along.
[Mike Woods] So Floyd Mayweather
will tell you that he is the best ever.
"I made more money
than anyone else in all of sports."
And I'll say to that,
I don't really give a fuck.
I don't really give a shit.
That doesn't make you TBE, The Best Ever.
So, is he the perfect athlete
for this new age of narcissism?
And if he is, is everyone
gonna follow his lead,
be a boxing businessman
and say, "I pick who I want to fight"?
These guys enter into this, remember,
to prove something to themselves
and to everyone else.
And that's their legacy,
and what will his legacy be?
[Bulger] With Mayweather's
undefeated career coming to a close,
who will take his place
as the next American boxing superstar?
[announcer] All right, fans, here we go!
Twelve rounds of boxing for the WBO
middleweight championship of the world.
Introducing Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin!
[loud cheering]
As a kid, I used to dream about the title.
Or big fights,
or big money and stuff, you know.
I had a sense of hope...
I was gonna be able to, like,
see something better.
- Do you want this title?
- I do.
- I want this title.
All right, show me you want this title.
[Sam Watson] Peter Quillin, Kid Chocolate,
is one of the hottest fighters
in the business at this time.
[Quillin] I did everything in my power
to try to make this work.
[announcer] Coming in left,
and down goes N'Dam!
I got to where I wanted to be.
I set a goal for myself,
being the champion.
[announcer] And the new WBO
middleweight champion of the world,
Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin!
[cheering]
I want to thank Grand Rapids, Michigan,
for making me a fighter,
and New York City making me a man.
I hope, through this,
I inspire people that hard work
can get you anywhere in life.
[birds chirping]
[Quillin] Balcony looks pretty good to me.
- [whirring]
- This is a property that I bought.
The house is shitty right now,
but I own it.
And now, I'm inspired to own
as many cribs as I can, if possible.
- I want a new door.
- [Papi Yordan] Okay, man.
Yeah, let's get a new door.
[Quillin] When I was younger, we grew up
in a house that my dad owned,
till having that house taken away from us
when my dad did his time in prison.
That's the way I grew.
I gotta give him money,
I give my mom money,
my little brother get money.
[Bulger] That's a lot of people
to take care of.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying,
but he think I take care of my friends
more than I look out for them.
- Because I can't--
- [Yordan] I know--
Can you send an e-mail out for somebody?
Can you send an e-mail?
I don't know.
Now, that's what I'm trying to say.
So he want me to do more for him,
but he don't know
what he's not able to do.
So, I just let him be my dad
and get a little bit of bread.
If you want to help me flip the cribs,
I want it done the way...
I'm the boss, not him.
- Yeah, pero--
- It's my house.
- But I'm the boss.
[Quillin] I'm making
life-changing money for myself
to be able to secure, like, my family,
jobs for people that helped me,
trying to increase my capital
by making sure that I won't retire broke.
[Bulger] Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin
grew up here in Grand Rapids, Michigan.
Just two doors down
from Floyd Mayweather's family.
Currently, their street
has a combined record
of 78 wins and zero losses.
He never gave up.
He could've turned out... another way.
Peter was really a troublemaker.
I mean, he'd get suspended in school
because he's always fighting.
So, well, you know, I said,
"He needs to be in the gym."
'Cause I used to get Peter's ass, too,
so, I think I had
a big part in that because,
from him weaving and dodging
and ducking from me
and running,
and I'm getting out of breath...
Man, that boy was something.
[man] One, two, three.
[all] Kid Chocolate!
[Quillin] Who knows what
the "C" in champ stands for?
[all] Confidence!
- What does the "H" stand for?
- [all] Hard work!
- What does the "A" stand for?
- [all] Attitude!
- What does the "M" stand for?
- [all] Motivation.
Y'all don't sound motivated. What?
[all loudly] Motivation!
- What does the "P" stand for?
- [all] Patience!
Okay, you take those words, I promise you,
you can very, very much be successful.
[Bulger] Against all odds, Kid Chocolate
made it out of Grand Rapids,
reaching the pinnacle of the sport
as he won the middleweight
championship of the world.
- But then, he just gave it up.
- [baby cooing]
[Bulger] What happened to his belt?
Why isn't he the champ anymore?
- Do you know?
- Who knows?
Those things happen. Real fighters win,
lose, lose their belts, get them back.
[Bulger] He's undefeated, though.
Then something must have happened.
I think he, uh...
Let me think. I think he went
to the monastery for a while.
[gulls cawing]
[man 1] Peter Quillin announced
that he would be vacating his title.
I'm sure you guys heard.
[man 2] Allegedly,
he's gonna make $1.4 million,
so I don't understand
what his motives are.
[man 3] All right, Peter Quillin,
a lot of people want questions answered.
[Bulger] Kid Chocolate wasn't defeated,
he wasn't injured.
His decision left the boxing world
in a state of confusion.
After all, wasn't becoming a champion
what boxers dream about?
What could possibly compel someone
to give up their championship title
they fought so hard for?
- I'd like to thank Al Haymon.
- Thank you, Al Haymon.
- Al Haymon.
Al Haymon didn't want
him to fight the fight,
he didn't want him
to fight my guy, Korobov.
So what he did was,
he just paid the guy not to fight.
Literally paid him not to fight,
and promised him another fight
if he didn't fight this fight.
Paid him half a million dollars because
he didn't want to take a chance on losing.
[Kim]
Basically, he is like the puppet master.
Think of The Wizard of Oz,
he's that guy behind the curtains.
And he's just pushing
all the buttons and levers.
[Bulger] I've heard the name Al Haymon,
but I've never seen him.
He's like the opposite of Don King.
He doesn't do interviews.
He's just lurking behind the scenes.
And with unprecedented pay days,
he's earned his fighters' loyalty.
[Quillin] When I had my son, my kid,
Al Haymon said,
"If you wanna fight for this belt,
we can make that happen.
Or you can not fight for the belt
and get what you said you want,
which is time with your family,
which, I would say,
you don't get that time back."
- [baby cooing]
- [speaking gibberish]
♪ Are you cold? ♪
[singing gibberish]
So I took some time off.
If you wanna say
that advice is bad for somebody,
then people can say what they want,
but I feel like I made
the right decision for me.
[Hopkins] He gave up the belt
because he was told to.
These guys ain't their own boss.
I made 20 defenses,
so I don't believe in givin' up belts.
If you ask me "Would I give up my belt?",
I will say "No."
I worked too hard, I sacrificed too much.
That belt will still be with me.
[De La Hoya] The fighters are not fighting
for the glory, for the honor,
for the respect.
It's all about the business.
I mean, who in their right mind
gives up a championship title
because they don't wanna face
the best in their division?
That's just unheard of.
In my era, you just don't do that.
You see people shitting
on Peter Quillin, saying,
[tsks] "He ain't a fuckin' warrior.
He don't wanna fight the best."
And Peter Quillin can answer you and say,
"I'm listening
to my trusted advisor, Al Haymon.
It's gonna be pretty good for me."
[Gallagher] It's about money.
It's about making a living
so you can take care of your family.
- [Bulger] Fuck the glory?
- Huh?
[Bulger] Fuck the glory?
Glory's bullshit.
You can go in your bathroom
and have glory.
Close the door
and tell everybody who you are.
You think the easiest route
to do, like, in life,
like, between being a boxer
and then going to college,
which one would you choose?
I mean, in boxing, if you turn pro,
if you got the right people around you,
you can turn... you can make money
in a heartbeat, you know what I mean?
Peter Quillin is one of the luckiest,
blessed, talented fighters we have.
He listens to Al Haymon.
They talk.
They always make sense
on what they're doing,
when they're gonna fight,
who they're gonna fight.
And that's great.
[Bulger] Unlike other professional sports,
boxing doesn't have
a single controlling organization,
which is exactly what Al Haymon is after
with his Premier Boxing Champions league.
With half a billion dollars
of venture capital,
he has the sport back on prime time
for the first time in over three decades.
And he's signing
a lot of the best fighters...
but Haymon rarely does business
with competing promoters
and their fighters.
And in boxing, the best
all too often don't fight the best.
[Dunkin] You know, there's a lot of money
being thrown around.
Can you imagine half a million dollars
to not fight my guy? To not fight!
[Quillin]
I want to set myself up for life.
So, I'm gonna go out there and train
like I'm trying to win,
like my life is dependent on it
and my son's life's depending on it.
[kid] Atlas Cops and Kids, baby!
[Bulger]
You shouldn't be surprised to hear
when Lil B-Hop signs
his first pro contract,
it's with Al Haymon.
Signing with Al Haymon,
ain't nothing better than that.
[Bulger] Why is that?
'Cause there's nobody
that's gonna get you to the top,
where you need to be,
and make the right money
that you're supposed to be making, but Al.
[Sosa] Congrats. Hard work pays off.
You know what I mean?
Gonna show this world
that the new superstar is on his way.
Yes, sir.
[Gary Stark Jr.]
Al's the best in business.
He has the best fighters now.
If you fight with him,
you fight in the best shows.
He's the man.
[Sosa] Jay, you're getting
a glimpse of the future, Jay.
A glimpse of the future.
The Sosa Crew be taking over soon.
[electric guitar music playing]
[Colbert] In this sport people think
it's all about the money.
I mean, the money's
gonna come regardless.
Like, right now?
I'll fight for $100, if I had to.
No problem.
To build my record, build my résumé.
Let a lot of people see who I am.
I'm in this to make history.
A guy like him is supposed to be
right now in some institution.
Think about it.
He had no good start to be successful.
You know what it is, right?
I'ma tell you something.
God gives grace to humble people.
Remember that.
This is gonna be your spotlight right now.
When it's your time, it's your time.
I'll tell you how good he may be someday.
His nickname is Lil B-Hop.
- Chris Colbert.
- [crowd cheering]
[Woods] Al Haymon is spending money
hand over fist, and it's great.
The fighters are getting paid
like drunken sailors wanna be paid.
But are the right fights being made?
Are the fans happy?
They're the ones that have to congregate
to lift this sport up.
[Sosa] If you wanna
do things the right way,
you always have to get
the right opponents.
And the right opponents, sometimes,
are not the best opponents.
You know what I mean?
But that's how you build them up.
[Marquis Pierce] It's the first time
he's ever gonna go four rounds,
and I don't think he's ready
for this shit.
He's not even fighting
for the same cause that I'm fighting for.
You wanna be famous
and some superstar athlete.
I'm fighting for my life.
I'm fighting to make sure
food get put on my fucking table and shit.
As I'm standing there,
he's up in my face,
you know, trying to talk down to me.
He's like, "This is gonna be an easy win."
And "I'm not worried about nothing."
Dude, you're 18 years old, bro.
Your balls barely dropped, my man.
[Awesome] Professional boxing,
it's all about perception.
This pro boxer's 25-0.
But if you look at the 25 fighters
he fought, they're literally nobodies.
They're guys with 1-7 records
and guys who've never boxed before,
guys making their debut.
And they build someone's record
to make them look
like a great, undefeated boxer.
[announcer] 122.6!
[Dunkin] Yeah, undefeated is so important.
In boxing, the second you lose,
everybody's off of you.
We've come to a world now
where winning is all that matters.
As long as there are fighters out there
who think that they need to have
an undefeated record to be relevant...
I think they're very misguided.
I contribute that to Mayweather.
That's the Mayweather effect,
thinking about business
and thinking about the fight second.
[Bulger] After years of anticipation,
negotiation and hype,
here in Las Vegas
on the first Saturday of May,
Floyd "Money" Mayweather
remains undefeated.
Earning an estimated $300 million
in one night
as he defeats Manny Pacquiao
in the fight of the century.
But I'm across town
at a place I always dreamed of reaching.
The National Golden Gloves Championships.
[Jim Beasley] Golden Gloves,
which started clear back in the 1920s,
and throughout the history,
most everybody has been
in the Golden Gloves.
And many of our successful champions
like Sugar Ray Leonard
or Evander Holyfield or Mike Tyson,
all those kind of people,
Oscar De La Hoya, you can name 'em all,
they were Golden Glove champs.
And so this is the beginning
for the next breed of champions.
[indistinct yelling]
- Dig down in there!
- [exclaims]
Aim to the body. Both sides, baby.
[Leonard]
Winning the Golden Gloves was huge.
But then you win
the National Golden Gloves?
[scoffs] Forget about it.
It was everything.
Ask any boxer.
[Bulger]
So what's the plan tonight, champ?
Packing up shoes, socks,
shorts, cup, shirt.
Headgear.
[inhales deeply]
Mouthpiece, check. Got all the stuff.
Tonight fighting a dude
from, uh, South Carolina, I believe.
Don't know who he is.
Uh, don't know what he looks like.
Uh, well,
I'm sure he's a really nice guy, so...
let's go break his dreams.
[Bulger] The Golden Gloves
is one of the few things
that has stayed constant
in amateur boxing.
It has nothing to do with the Olympics,
but it is the most prestigious tournament
in the country.
[Awesome] Golden Glove National Tournament
gets you no ranking points.
It gets you no international competition.
Gets you nothing.
But there's... It holds weight.
It holds weight in the world with people.
They like Golden Glove champions.
This tournament, it's a big deal.
I'm gonna be takin' it very seriously.
I'm fighting every fight
like it's the gold medal fight
in the Olympics this week.
[bell ringing]
[indistinct shouting]
- [man 1] Go, baby!
- [man 2] Go!
[talking indistinctly]
[man 1] Whoop his ass!
[man 2] There you go!
- [indistinct laughter]
- [bell ringing]
- [Bulger] Coach, how did he do?
- [John] Excellent.
Perfect first fight.
For all these other monsters,
I saw about seven monsters out there.
They are getting bigger
every goddamned year.
What happened to real heavyweights
like Joe Louis, 202 pounds,
Joe Frazier, 204,
and "Big" George Foreman, 220?
Ali, 217.
[announcer] We have a winner,
boxing out of the blue corner...
- [applause]
- Cam Awesome. Cam Awesome.
- [Bulger] Yo, Awesome.
- [Awesome] Yo, yo.
- [Bulger] How did that go?
- [Awesome] It went pretty well.
My plan was just to land some jabs,
every so often throw an overhand left
to land-- to get some respect.
I figured I can win the fight
with no real risk
of exchanging punches with him.
[woman] Good job, Cam.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Good job. Good job. Good job.
- Bye, guys.
- Thank you, young lady.
We'll see you at the craps table.
[Bulger] One hundred and thirty-eight
people eliminated on day one.
But Cam F. Awesome advances,
needing three more victories
to earn his fourth
National Golden Gloves Championship.
And maybe even the Golden Boy award,
given to the best overall fighter
in the tournament.
Weigh-ins.
I think I'm over 200 pounds.
[Bulger] For years,
Cam F. Awesome has dominated
the amateur super heavyweight division.
But here in Vegas, he's got competition.
Darmani Rock, from North Philadelphia,
is 19 years old,
and he's also qualified
for the Olympic trials.
At 260 pounds,
people are talking about him
like he's the next great
American heavyweight champion.
[indistinct chatter]
How's he doing?
He's got a nice little right uppercut.
Yeah, I'm moving to my right--
I mean, fuck this.
You gotta start to do more.
[Awesome] Yeah.
[John] So, everybody thinks
they can beat Cam
'cause he's a little awkward
and different...
- [Bulger] Right.
- And they don't see the traditional boxer.
So they think,
"Oh, boy, I can probably beat him."
And then they find out
it ain't what it looks like.
So, I think we're gonna...
I suspect it's gonna be fun.
[crowd cheering]
[announcer] Cam Awesome.
Cam Awesome. Kansas City.
[Bulger] Four days later, sure enough,
Cam and Darmani find themselves
in the championship battle
to determine who is the best
super heavyweight in the country.
I don't... I don't get sucked into
all the hype of who I'm fighting.
I haven't lost a single round
this tournament.
I'm going for the Golden Boy.
[man] It's a pretty unique opportunity
for both these young men.
When you have a multi-day tournament,
so much can happen.
You know, you can get an injury...
They could've met in a draw,
and they could've met
in the preliminaries.
So, it's really great for the boxing fans,
it's great for the storyline,
and it's only gonna
elevate their fight game.
[announcer] This will be our last bout.
Two warriors at 201 pounds plus.
Boxing out of the red corner, Cam Awesome.
[applause]
- [bell rings]
- Fight!
[indistinct shouting]
[man] You can't do that with that jab...
[grunting]
[bell rings]
Is he hurtin' you?
Then, fuck him.
Get in there and fight with him.
If he's not hurtin' you...
Do some feint, and then, boom, come in.
You feint, boom, come in.
- [bell rings]
- [referee] Fight!
[crowd gasping]
[man cackles]
[referee] No. No, no. Stop!
[bell rings]
Let's hear about the 2015
National Golden Gloves champion...
- at 201 pounds plus...
- [applause]
he happens to be boxing
out of the blue corner.
- [cheering]
- Darmani Rock.
Darmani Rock.
[Awesome] I regret walking out
of the ring like that, but...
I fuckin' wanted the Golden Boy award.
God, I never fuckin' get it.
I've fought... I've won
fuckin' 12 national championships
for this goddamn country,
and not once have they given me
fighter of the tournament.
Statistically, I'm supposed to get it
one out of every ten times.
I fuckin' won it 12.
This is my sixth time
in the Golden Glove finals...
and, uh, six times I fought
in the Golden Glove finals and uh...
[panting]
and I'm going 50-for-50.
That's disgusting.
Fuckin'...
[rap music playing]
- [man laughing]
- [Colbert] I already see it in my head.
First round, I'm just gonna
let him chase me.
Second round, B-Hop.
I'm gonna just start fuckin' him up,
taking it to him.
Every time I hit him, "Got him!"
I'ma tell him that. "Got him!"
[laughter]
I'm gonna be like, "Lil bitch."
I'm gonna be fuckin' him up.
And after the fight,
after I knock his ass out,
stomp him, or beat the shit out of him,
either one...
Mmm-hmm.
I'ma be like,
"Good shit, bro. I'm proud of you."
[laughs] So, you took that...
- Yeah, after--
- "Took that loss like a champ, bro."
After the fight, it's all love.
I ain't got no hate on him.
I don't hate him.
[Colbert] He just gotta get ass-whooped.
I don't know why he signed that contract
like a dickhead.
[barber] "Don't take it personal.
It's business, bruh. Sorry.
Hope you're a fan after."
- [barber] See you later.
- [Colbert] See you tomorrow.
Be good, man. Good luck, bro.
- You're leaving?
- See you tomorrow, man.
- [Colbert] I look good.
- [man 1] Yeah.
[man 2 laughing]
[horn blaring]
Greatest thing you can do
is get that diploma, okay?
I am. I'm trying to.
I'm not tryin', I'm gonna get it. But...
People keep stressing me about
school, school, school, school, school.
I'ma stop going.
- You're not gonna stop.
- Who? Me?
- I done stopped going before.
- Uh-huh.
I done stopped going before,
and then I just went back.
Don't do that. It'll just...
make you have to keep starting over.
Bang it out.
Soon I'ma get tired of it and not go back.
Just bang it out. Get rid of it.
You know what I mean?
And you'll never have to go back again.
- [chuckles]
- Never.
And then you'll start thinking
about college, right?
You can hear me?
- Right?
- Huh? Say that again?
Then you'll start thinking
about college, right?
- [laughing loudly]
- What?
College is easier than high school.
- [man] He's a fighter. Look at you.
- I'm ready, man.
I ain't even worried.
I just wanna get this shit over with.
[grunting]
[man] Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Let's walk, guys!
Showtime! Come on, let's go!
Camera guys, you're holding me up.
Let's go!
- E and G, move!
- [man] Showtime!
[crowd cheering]
[indistinct shouting]
[Hopkins]
Everybody believes he's talented.
Only thing that's stopping him
is his age and the fights.
And that's something that comes with time.
[bell rings]
There you go!
Jab again! Jab again!
[indistinct chatter]
[crowd gasps]
[whooping]
[Sosa] Let's get a little more...
a little more physical.
Let's make this physical. Come on.
- Let's make this shit happen.
- [bell rings]
[shouting indistinctly]
[crowd gasps]
[cheering]
[Malignaggi]
You win in impressive fashion,
the bums will be less bums.
Maybe they'll go from two tomato can level
to one tomato can level to,
you know, half journeyman level.
The motivation is
to mow through these guys,
dismantle them in every way possible,
so that people step you up the ladder
until you reach the guys
you have your eye on.
[Colbert] It feels good to be a pro now.
I always knew that I was gonna be
something great in my life.
If it was either football, basketball,
it don't matter what it was,
I always knew
I was gonna do something great.
[Elie Seckbach]
Lil B looked phenomenal down in the ring.
His pro debut, no jitters.
The haircut took longer than the fight.
It's gonna sound crazy,
what I'm about to say,
but he reminds me of Floyd Mayweather.
He reminds me of Floyd.
A young Floyd Mayweather.
[man] One, baby, one.
[Colbert] In the beginning of your career,
you always have that little hill
you've gotta get over.
I didn't get over that hill yet.
I'm still standing on top of it.
I feel like I'm the man.
And when it's time
to really step things up,
that's what's gonna happen,
I'm gonna go over that hill,
and do what I gotta do,
climb the next mountain.
Four more years,
I'll be champion of the world.
And that's a promise.
Yeah. Four more years.
[barking]
[Quillin] What they say about a fighter
when he's, like,
he got all the talent
but he ain't in shape?
[trainer] He's a lazy motherfucker.
[all chuckling]
[Quillin] And they say hard work...
- Hard work always beats talent--
- Yep.
Talent can only take you so far.
- What if you talented--
- Get that hard work in. Huh?
What if you talented and you...
hard-working?
You're destined for greatness.
[Bulger] After a year of inactivity,
Al Haymon is putting Kid Chocolate
back in the ring
against Andy Lee, an Irish fighter,
who just so happens to have won that same
WBO Middleweight Championship belt
that Kid Chocolate gave up.
[Quillin] I took a year off.
People would've never thought
I could fight for a belt
right away in my next fight
after giving in, vacating the same belt.
And now I get to
go in there as a challenger
for even more money for the same belt.
[grunting]
[Hopkins] Al Haymon is happy.
He showed loyalty by giving the belt up.
Al Haymon gets him the next fight,
close to the same amount of money...
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
He promised him, he had to fulfill
the promise, or whatever it is. Bam!
You're back to square one.
[Bulger] So, what is the significance
of these belts?
And do they still define a champion?
In boxing's heyday,
there were only eight weight classes,
each with one undisputed champion.
But then came the sanctioning bodies,
organizations that created
their own championship belts
and received sanctioning fees
from the fighters wearing them.
Now there are 17 weight classes,
each with an upwards
of four different champions.
The values of all those belts
have dwindled,
making an undefeated record,
that purest proof of dominance,
more important than ever.
Jab-uppercut.
Yeah, but throw that uppercut.
Throw it. Throw it right here.
It don't matter if you land it or not.
The thing is
to make him react to it, okay?
[Eric Brown]
The belt doesn't make the fighter.
The fighter makes the belt.
He'll have more belts as time goes on.
We're gonna get a belt on April 11.
Once we get that belt,
we'll get a couple more belts.
[Debra] He's got a strategy of weaving.
You know, he will move around, and dodge,
and come in, and squeeze out of there,
and move back and forth...
[Eric] That's it.
[Debra] He's gonna do what he's gotta do.
He's gonna come out courageous.
He's still gonna be what he is,
and he's gonna be the champion.
And he's gonna get his belt back.
[Peter Berg] Peter Quillin had
a reputation of being
just one of the meanest men in the ring.
Now he's on the cusp of real greatness
but he hasn't really hit it yet.
And the only person that can change that,
and the only person
that can fix that is Peter Quillin.
[Quillin] I did some sprints
on the beach today.
Ain't gonna hear no complaints
about that.
[Eric] I understand.
- But I'ma remind you of my rule.
- Okay.
[Eric] On sparring days, what do we do?
We put it all over here.
[Eric] So, we run afterwards.
Yeah, yeah, but--
- [Eric] Not before.
- I don't have the time.
- [Eric] No, I understand, but...
- So I have to work through it.
[Eric] I can't let you limp.
I need your leg, okay?
Last time that's what I was doing.
- [Eric] Yeah?
- Yeah. So, I'm okay doing that.
Just, like, you got to hit that wall
and this is when I do.
- I did eight rounds all day.
- Knock that motherfucker down.
- Today.
- [man] Hiciste bien, hiciste bien.
[Eric] Knock that motherfucker down.
[grunting]
[Leonard] With one year of inactivity,
it's extremely difficult
being who you were...
because you become civilized.
It's hard to come back to work.
And there are no shortcuts.
Boxing is beyond work.
It's war.
Damn.
I felt it.
I think that was bad luck
letting y'all film today, motherfuckers.
[Bulger] No, you did great.
"I did great."
You hearing me?
Look, I got a busted lip.
I feel... I don't feel good.
[Bulger] You were tired already
when you came in.
You had a long day, right?
Yeah.
I mean, every other day was a long day.
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
stepping to the scales,
Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin.
One-sixty-one-point-four,
161.4 pounds
for Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin.
Peter Quillin will have two hours
to lose 1.4 pounds.
There's a title fight tomorrow night,
trying to get to a weight of 160.
The kids I had used to
take 10 to 12 pounds off in two days.
What the fuck is two pounds?
What are we talking about?
[Malignaggi]
I think when you accept the fight,
you have to make the weight.
You get a little bit civilized
as you sit back on your money
and enjoy life,
and, suddenly, the months pass
and you haven't fought.
But if a belt was that important,
you probably would've made the weight
no matter how much you suffered.
[Bulger]
It's one of boxing's craziest rituals.
Fighters virtually starve themselves
and sweat out pounds
to make weight the day before a fight.
Kid Chocolate gets down to 160.5 pounds,
failing to make the 160-pound
middleweight limit.
According to any of the belt rules,
you have to make weight
in order to fight for the belt.
You can't be one ounce,
one quarter of an ounce over.
You have to on weight or under.
So, this fight now went
from being a title fight
to being a non-title bout.
They don't take
the Super Bowl trophy as a joke.
They don't take the NBA trophy
at the end of the championship as a joke.
Like Quillin did,
you live and die with those decisions.
[Quillin] I mean, I'm 31-0.
That record got me to that title.
It got me to the title.
You know what I'm saying?
And then, for me to...
not lose sight of that,
lets me know
that I appreciate the work I did.
I mean, trying less than your best
is never good enough.
I will feel bad about myself
if I didn't give it my all,
but I know I gave it my all.
[crowd cheering]
[announcer]
Introducing first, the red corner...
As a professional,
he stands undefeated, 31 victories,
22 by knockout, with no defeats.
Introducing Peter "Kid Chocolate" Quillin.
- [crowd cheering]
- [bell rings]
[man] Whoo!
[announcer] Across the ring,
his opponent tonight, Andy Lee.
[bell rings]
[crowd cheering]
[man] Get him!
Get him, Pete! Get him, Pete! Fight!
Get him, Pete!
[man 2] Hook him, Andy!
[crowd cheering]
Get after it! Get after it!
[crowd roaring]
[man] Come on, Petey!
[bell ringing]
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
having gone the distance inside the ring,
we'll go
to your official judges' scorecards.
[Bulger] If a fight goes
the full 12-round distance,
the outcome is determined by three judges.
The advantage
to knocking out your opponent
is that you keep it out of their hands.
They all see it from a different angle.
[announcer] Your third
and final judge at ringside
scores the fight 113-113.
- He has it even.
- [crowd roaring]
The fight is declared a split draw.
- [man] What happened?
- [Brad Bose] That's no draw.
No draw there, I'll tell you that.
[man] Kiss his ass.
[Bose] This is the problem with boxing,
right here.
[Watson] Kid Chocolate beat him
fair and square.
Knocked him down three times.
Beat his ass good.
But... the white boy was strong.
He was tough.
Andy Lee's a tough guy.
He's a great fighter.
[Quillin] This was just a chess match.
This wasn't checkers. This was chess.
You know, with the year off,
I never like to look for excuses
for why I did bad.
I like to look for excuses
why I should do better.
And this is just part of my chapter
that I'ma always remember.
[indistinct chatter]
[Awesome] When I lose a fight,
it bothers me more than anything else
in the world bothers me.
I just really like winning.
[Bulger] I mean, you can't win
everything, though. You know?
Mmm... You can't win everything is...
I feel like that's a cop-out.
'Cause if you can't win everything...
Actually, technically,
you can win everything.
It's hard to win everything.
And you have to strive for perfection,
and perfection is almost impossible.
But I think saying,
"You can't win everything,"
is just a cop-out for losing sometimes.
[trainer] Yep, yep, don't give up.
No, no, no. Five more. Max it up.
Five. Come on.
[Bulger] After losing
the National Golden Gloves Championship
at Super Heavyweight,
Cam F. Awesome made a decision
to lose 20 pounds
and try to qualify for the Olympic trials
at the next weight class down.
[exhaling]
[Awesome] Moving down in weight,
I get to fight guys my own size
and I feel so much better.
[John] He's 20 pounds lighter,
he's in better condition.
He doesn't have a belly like I do.
He hasn't really looked
like a top athlete.
Now he does.
[whistle blowing]
[Bulger] In winning this tournament
in Colorado Springs,
Cam F. Awesome becomes the only American
to qualify for the Olympic trials
in two different weight classes.
[Awesome] I'm smarter, I'm more mature,
I'm more disciplined.
I've got my mind right,
I've got my body right.
I'm emotionally there.
I'm a lot more secure now
than I used to be.
And I'm confident in myself
and my abilities to bring home a medal.
♪ My heart cold
'Cause I grew up without my father ♪
♪ But it really made me smarter
It made me grind harder ♪
♪ I would make my dreams a reality ♪
♪ Own family thought
They was gon' have to bury me ♪
♪ Took my mama nine months
Just for her to carry me ♪
♪ So I was brought to the world
To live like yo majesty, nigga ♪
[Colbert] Atlas Cops and Kids really is,
like, the best gym.
A lot of us is at the top of the sport,
like in amateur-wise
or, like, making our way up in the pros.
Me and Sosa, we're rising superstars.
It's great.
And look at me now.
Now I'm a Mexican. A black Mexican.
[Sosa] We're like a family.
He wants to be part of that.
He tells me, you know,
"I'm gonna wear the Mexican hat.
I'm gonna wear the poncho."
Yeah, you could say
he's a black Mexican now.
- [in Spanish] The Black Bean. [chuckles]
- [Bulger repeats in Spanish]
[bell rings]
[crowd chattering indistinctly]
- [announcer] Chris "B-Hop" Colbert!
- [crowd cheering]
[bell ringing]
[Sosa] The potential is there.
And if he continues to listen
and train hard and all that,
he will be a champion.
He could be a great champion, too.
One of the elite ones.
- How'd you get there?
- Took a cab.
Waste of money.
'Cause y'all take too long.
He talks too much.
[Russo] I gotta just make sure
he realizes that it's a business,
that it's how you're gonna
feed your family.
And how you gotta handle your money.
It's like a business.
Why do you need $200?
- [Colbert] I need it.
- For?
I gotta get something.
What? Stupidity?
No, I gotta get some sneakers
for somebody.
- Oh, get the hell outta here.
- Not for me.
I have to buy these sneakers, though.
- I ain't giving it to you.
- They're like $50, though.
I thought you needed it for the ID.
Yeah, the ID, too. The ID's not that much.
The most is gonna be, like, $50
for the cab and the ID.
So, I'm only giving you $100.
- What?
- I'm only giving you $100 then.
No, no, no. $200.
Then the extra $50
is gonna last me for the week.
Still need a ride?
- It's $1,000, right? It's $1,000 left.
- Mmm-hmm.
$1,500--
[chuckles]
Nobody makes money overnight. It's...
Nobody. Nobody has done it,
made money...
It takes... it takes years.
You build up a record and get well-known
and stay out of trouble.
[Colbert] All aboard!
[Bulger] You could say in boxing,
to be the best,
you've got to get beat up by the best.
So after four wins and little prize money,
Lil B-Hop drops out of high school
and heads down to Florida,
taking a job as the sparring partner
for the bantamweight champion
of the world, Carlos Payano,
who's preparing to defend his title.
Fort Lauderdale Beach.
[laughing]
[tires squealing]
[exclaiming]
[gun firing]
[Bulger] You took the day off
today and chilled?
So what? I'm not fighting.
I just came out here to spar and chill.
I ain't come here to work out.
This not my camp.
I'm not with these people.
My coach is not here.
[video playing indistinctly]
[Bulger] So you're not really
taking it seriously?
No. It's sparring.
That's it.
[Bulger] Right.
- [man] Do you believe in vacation?
- [Colbert] No.
[man] Shut the hell up!
This ain't vacation, boy.
You're a sparring partner right now.
- This ain't no vacation.
- I don't give a fuck about no sparring.
- I don't give a fuck about this, nigga.
- Yeah, right.
I could be on vacation and still go spar.
I'll go on vacation, a real vacation,
and still go to the gym.
I'll find a gym and hit it.
This man don't believe in this shit, bro.
Chris, you know, I mean,
he could do everything wrong right now
and still probably fight and do well
in four-round fights.
But you get to six, eight,
ten and twelve-round fights,
it don't matter how old you are,
it catches up to you.
Your body's putting out
what you put into it.
So if you got Snickers and McDonald's,
that's what's coming out.
There's no room in this business
for half-assing.
[Colbert muffled]
I'm the motherfucking world champion.
- [man] What? What'd you say?
- I'm the motherfucking world champion.
- [man] That's right.
- That's me.
Hup! Twelve, go! [whistling]
[indistinct chatter]
[grunting]
[Payano in Spanish] In the end,
I am responsible for my training.
To prepare physically and mentally
for my fight.
You need to sacrifice yourself
and have the desire to be a champion.
[whistling]
[Herman Caicedo in English] As you saw,
my champ runs guys out of the ring.
If I just use Chris for traditional
six or eight straight rounds,
he probably right now wouldn't get it.
He'd get hurt
or he'd just get demoralized.
Every time, for this fight, every time,
work, work hard, work, work.
[Caicedo] This is where the champ lives.
This is his chamber.
And he has to clean the bathroom
twice a week.
And that's his job
and there's no getting around that.
And he's got photos of his family
and this is...
And he's the world champ and he's making
a decent penny on his next fight.
And he's not moving out.
- You wouldn't come move in there.
- Hell no.
Of course.
That's the mentality.
[Caicedo] That's our generation today.
They feel like they're entitled.
I tell my guys in a minute,
I tell my champion, "Stay humble."
And if you don't have people around you
that tell you these things,
and tell you, "You're not shit..."
Can you buy me a house, a car,
and a freakin', you know, an island?
Can you do that?
You can't do that, right?
[indistinct chatter]
[Colbert] I struggled a lot.
He got the best of me.
I ain't think he had that much skills.
But that's what happens when you
play around and you take shit for granted.
I just realized that
when you make your way up,
you gotta start stepping it up.
One round at a time, one day at a time,
one step at a time.
I'm not at
the world championship level yet,
but I know I can hang
with a lot of world champions.
To be honest, I don't know the best in me.
But, you know, it takes me.
I could bring the best out of me.
[Leonard] It's a certain mentality
that it takes to be a great fighter.
And it's there. It's there in all of us.
We all possess that thing.
But what separates us
is there are people who can activate it...
and become champion.
[announcer] Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen,
and welcome to
the Silver Legacy Hotel Resort and Casino.
This afternoon, 28 men will continue
their quest for the Olympic dream.
[Bulger] After a year
of Olympic trials qualifiers,
the top American Olympic boxing hopefuls
are here in Reno
to compete to make the US team.
The group includes Darmani Rock,
Philadelphia's super heavyweight
who beat Cam F. Awesome in
the National Golden Gloves Championship.
- But tonight, it only takes one punch...
- [crowd exclaims]
to end Darmani's Olympic dreams.
What, I can't fight?
Right.
[camera beeping]
[camera shutter clicking]
[John] This silly rule for boxing
without headgear.
People get hurt,
Cam got cut a little bit last night.
But we got it fixed up, so...
But he's gotta worry about that a little,
he's got to protect it.
So that just adds another dimension to it.
[beeping and clicking]
[woman] Can anyone, like, have
a serious conversation with you
[laughs]
with your freaking drawn-on eyebrow?
So ridiculous.
[Bulger] At his new
201-pound weight class,
Cam F. Awesome, he looks awesome.
But with the cut over his eye,
and three fights left,
he'll have to proceed with caution
or risk medical disqualification.
[bell ringing]
[man] There you go.
- [bell rings]
- [announcer] Cam Awesome.
[John] You're a fucking magician.
Your eye is perfect.
I have never been so impressed
in my fucking life.
[announcer] Your winner by split decision,
boxing out of the blue corner,
Cam Awesome!
[applause]
[Mike Martino]
Watching Cam in his skill set
get to this level is incredible.
He's invested so much into this.
If he wins, it was all worth it.
[Awesome]
I've waited too long to fuck this up.
It's a great honor
to be able to go to the Olympics
and represent a country and all that.
I have to win. I'd be way too disappointed
chasing this for 12 fucking years.
- Oh, you're not who I thought you were.
- No?
Doesn't mean you're not
a quality person though.
Oh, thank you.
- If you're up, best of luck.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- What weight class are you in?
- [chuckles]
Heavyweight.
You guys coming to the fights?
[woman] Oh, hell, yes. All week.
Are you a 201 or 201-plus?
201, I used to be 201-plus.
- [man chuckles]
- [woman] Oh, wow.
What did you do? Go on a damn diet?
Yeah, I actually did. I'm a vegan.
And I started working out, and running,
and working out, and running...
- You're vegan?
- Yeah.
- Good luck to you.
- Thank you. Thank you.
I'm a protein guy.
[both chuckling]
- Where are you guys from?
- [woman] Here.
- Here?
- [woman] Yeah.
You guys know anybody fighting?
- [woman] We do now.
- So I'm your favorite fighter here?
- [woman] Pablo, but he lost.
- It was Pablo.
Well, I'm your favorite fighter
left in the tournament.
[woman] But you're my favorite fighter
- I'll take that.
- [man laughs]
[Awesome]
I'll take that ten times out of ten.
What are your names?
Nancy and Jim. What's your name?
Nice to meet you. I'm Cam.
- Oh, I know you. I've watched you, yeah.
- Oh, you are Cam?
- Hey, I got a question for you.
- Yes, sir.
Is your last name really...
No, it isn't. You changed it.
Oh, I did change it,
but I took the legal procedures.
It's on my passport,
credit card, my license.
- Because, why not, right?
- [man] Why not?
[Bulger] Cam F. Awesome might not be the
prettiest fighter to watch in the ring,
but he knows how to land a punch
without receiving a punch,
and that's all that matters.
[announcer] Boxing out of the red corner,
he comes from Lenexa, Kansas,
Cam F. Awesome!
[crowd cheering]
[announcer] Red corner, Cam F. Awesome!
Tell the people
what you did out there tonight.
[laughs] I dominated.
[announcer] Cam F. Awesome, everybody.
Great performance.
United States Olympian, well deserved.
[Bulger] Awesome has now qualified
for the US Olympic men's boxing team.
But that's not saying
he's an Olympian yet.
He'll still have to go on to fight
internationally to qualify for the games.
[Awesome] I'm just emotionally exhausted
at this point.
But I'm happy,
the way everything turned out.
[Bulger] So, was this all worth it?
It was definitely all worth it,
but all today is...
is just basically me
getting back to where I left off.
[trainer] Ready?
[yells]
One.
[trainer] Go.
There you go. That's it.
[Eric] The Andy Lee fight
was a great test.
And I'm not being biased,
but I thought he won that fight.
Nonetheless, it is what it is.
We're moving on.
We're looking for the next one.
[clanking]
[man] Whoo!
[Quillin] I'm in the gym, working hard,
just to make sure I secure
what a win could look like for me.
If I'ma die, what I'm doing,
it's gonna be me dying trying to win.
[beeping]
You can't just be good at something.
You can't just go up there and make music
and think it's good enough.
You have to always go
the extra length to want it.
Like, I was willing to sleep on,
fucking, a mattress I found in the trash
to make my success work for me.
You know what I'm saying?
Wasn't about girls,
wasn't about nothing else in life.
You know what I'm saying?
So, in life, you have to figure out
what you're motivated over.
- [Bulger] When you realize your situation.
- Yeah.
You realize where you're at
and your situation
and how you're gonna get up out of it.
'Cause you notice that
you be in a pool full of crabs
and you don't know
why you keep getting pulled in,
it's because you have no plan to get out.
You know what I'm saying?
And then eventually, you'd be, like, 35,
and you're like, "What happened?"
And you was so much in the fucking moment
all the time that you...
Sometimes motherfuckers
don't never come out that moment.
[grunts]
[growling]
[Bulger] The latest fight
in Kid Chocolate's return
gives him another chance to regain
a middleweight championship belt.
Though, this time, it's the WBA title,
held by Brooklyn fighter
Danny "The Miracle Man" Jacobs.
[Woods] This is a 50-50 fight.
For Peter Quillin, he's taken
a wicked beating from hardcore fight fans.
If he wins and looks good,
all is forgiven.
[indistinct chatter]
♪ So when Peter get in the ring
He's gonna do the thing ♪
♪ Kid Chocolate, hey, hey!
Kid Chocolate ♪
♪ Peter is his name
Boxing is his game ♪
♪ He hit him with the right
Then he knock them out the ring ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Kid Chocolate
Hey, hey, hey, yes! ♪
Peace. And I'm out.
[cell phone ringing]
Floyd.
- [Mayweather] What's up, champ?
- Man, I'm good. I'm blessed, man.
Thank you. 'Cause I'm here right now.
You undefeated for a reason.
So it's obvious you've been doing
something right thus far.
So, you know, go out there
and just be at your best.
[Quillin] Thank you, Floyd, man.
Appreciate that.
Good looking.
Thank you for that, man.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [Quillin chuckles]
[cell phone ringing]
[Eric] Showtime.
Ugly motherfucker you.
[both laughing]
Thank you very much.
[man] Yes, that's real right there.
[bell rings]
[crowd cheering]
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
we welcome you to Barclays Center
here in Brooklyn, New York,
for the much anticipated
feature bout of the evening.
- Peter's about to be whipped.
- Yeah.
[bell rings]
[crowd cheering]
[inaudible]
- [bell rings]
- [crowd roaring]
[announcer] The referee has already
stopped the fight! Mamma mia!
Your whole life, your whole history,
your whole career changes with one punch.
You cannot play boxing.
[Hopkins] When you see an art,
and you see a painter,
and you see someone that's
doing something of the sweet science...
They hit and not get hit,
they take away and disarm a guy,
and make him look...
Reduce him down from a killer to nobody.
From a beast to nobody.
How did you do that...
in that squared circle?
Hey, man.
[Quillin] This fight was meant to happen.
No matter what I could have did wrong,
what I could have did right.
It was all supposed to happen
the way that it did.
[man] Yeah.
It's all part of your story now.
Walk out of here
with a smile on your face.
[man mutters indistinctly]
[De La Hoya] I believe
that if a fighter goes in there
and fights his heart out,
and just leaves everything in the ring,
he's gonna live to see another day.
He's gonna live to see another fight.
People are gonna wanna see him again,
regardless if you lose or win.
[Bulger] Being undefeated, does it matter?
It doesn't matter.
It happened the way it happened.
Somebody asked me,
"Are you scared to get in the ring?"
I said, "I'm not scared to fight,
I'm not even scared to lay down.
The only thing I'm scared of
is to see how many people
that's here for me right now,
in this moment, after I lost, disappear."
The only thing I could do
is go back to the gym,
reassess myself with my team
and try our best in the next go round.
[engine starts]
[Bulger]
Two years in the life of American boxing
will teach you a lot about
the sport's issues and problems...
but mostly about its champions.
Boxing has never been a perfect sport
and it never will be.
But it is about people
who can rise to the best of themselves
when they put on the gloves.
[indistinct announcement]
Like my mom always said,
it's not about how many times
you've been knocked down.
It's how fast you get up.
Boxing is about kids like me,
who, wherever they're from, need
something only this sport can provide.
Whether it's direction, or discipline,
or glory and fame and fortune.
A champion is someone who,
despite tremendous odds,
in a brutal, corrupt pursuit,
proves that the impossible,
what most of us might never dare,
could actually happen.
These dreams are still born every day
in gyms like Atlas Cops and Kids.
And as long as there are kids who need
to fight their way out of somewhere...
that squared circle will be calling.
[cheering] Hey, hey, hey!
The strategy remains the same, in this,
the most elemental of martial arts:
hit and don't be hit.
[announcer] And still undefeated,
Chris "Lil B-Hop" Colbert!
- [crowd cheering]
- [man] Let's go! Let's go!
[bell rings]
Who's that?
Who is that?
[speaks indistinctly]
[hip-hop music playing]