Synced and corrected by Chitorafa
www.addic7ed.com
CHIAPAS
MEXICO - GUATEMALA BORDER
[car engine running]
[Chío] If they ask why
we're here, what do we say?
Leave that to Toño.
WANTED! REWARD $5,000,000
Good morning.
IDs, please.
Open your trunk.
[opening the trunk]
[closing the trunk]
Jorge Ramos Pérez.
Why are you going to Guatemala?
To visit some friends in Barillas.
Welcome.
Thank you, officer.
WELCOME TO THE REPUBLIC OF GUATEMALA
[Chío laughing]
[Joaquín shushing]
♪ I feel the warmth
from my boiling blood ♪
♪ I feel the fear,
sweat dripping away ♪
♪ There's a stillness
that nothing transmits ♪
♪ I'm a breeze that
grows stronger ♪
♪ Even when the
clouds drift away ♪
♪ Even when my
skin dries away ♪
♪ I'll be back someday ♪
♪ To unleash my return ♪
♪ I have the dust that
protects the road ♪
♪ I have the branches
of a leafless tree ♪
♪ I'm the guardian
of the tired night ♪
♪ There are silhouettes
that come to meet me ♪
♪ Even when the
clouds drift away ♪
♪ Even when my
skin dries away ♪
♪ I'll be back someday ♪
♪ To unleash my return ♪
Relax. Come on, drink one.
They're here, boss.
Bring me the check!
GUATEMALA CITY GUATEMALA
Hello.
Toño.
The man of the hour.
Be careful.
I don't want my fans to recognize me.
How's Guatemala treating you?
Let's see how it treats us.
HERRERÍAS' HOUSE GUATEMALA CITY
[Rosado] Up there.
That's Herrerías.
Your organization is the
strongest around here.
And this will be my
new operation center.
I want to be your partner.
HERRERÍAS DRUG LORD IN GUATEMALA
They warned me that you're
really full of yourself.
[Herrerías laughing]
You're fucked, Chapo.
You should be asking to be
my employee, not my partner.
WANTED, JOAQUÍN GUZMÁN
LOERA REWARD $5,000,000
Takes so little to scare you?
Don't try to convince me, Chapo.
You're up shit creek and you
have nothing left to offer.
I have five tons of blow in El Salvador.
40% of the profit is yours.
That's over $40 million.
It's a good amount to start
our partnership, right?
That's if you manage to bring it in.
It'll come in.
Seeing is believing.
[Joaquín] I need you to gather
me some people in El Salvador.
- When do you need them?
- For tomorrow.
I need a big group.
But I don't want to draw
attention at the border.
We have to smuggle that
shipment no matter what, Toño.
The business with the
Colombians is at stake.
Amado must already know.
I'm sure they are
waiting for us to kill us.
We have no choice.
Either they kill us or we kill them.
I'm finally visiting another country.
I'll show you the whole damn world.
[laughing]
[moaning]
[police officer] How
many of them were there?
There were three Mexicans.
Two men and a young woman.
They drank some beers,
and then they left with some
people who seemed from the military.
Did they mention where
they were heading?
[opening trunk]
No.
Did you hear any name?
One of the men called
the other one "boss".
Any other detail that comes to mind?
- No.
- Look, Commander.
It has a hidden compartment.
[telephone ringing]
- Please, go ahead.
- Thank you.
[in English] General.
[door closes]
We've got intel that El Chapo managed
to cross the border to Guatemala.
El Chapo is your problem, General.
He has to pick up five tons
of cocaine in El Salvador.
That would be the biggest seizure
made by the DEA in Central America.
What about the Salvadorean government?
They are aware that we need your help.
They are helping too.
We've only asked them to wait
until Chapo arrives
to get his shipment...
and to turn him in eventually.
[mariachi music playing]
[agitated]
MEXICO CITY PRIVATE HANGAR
[in English] That's great,
guys. Let's go. Come on.
Good, pay my debt. Thank you.
MEXICO CITY
OFFICE OF THE MEXICAN ATTORNEY-GENERAL
FILE
[restaurant noises]
I didn't think you'd have the
balls to get me this information.
I've risked everything
on my part of this.
Now, it's your turn.
The men I sent will be on watch 24/7.
I need another favor.
I'm bringing my operations
center over here.
But before that, I need to
finish something in El Salvador.
- [opening the briefcase]
- We're here to help.
[closing the briefcase]
This is a bombshell, Saavedra.
Is your source trustworthy?
Yes.
I only need a witness's testimony.
Find one and we can move on.
What about the board? What will
the board say at the meeting?
Leave them to me.
You find the witness, and
I'll get you the authorization.
[doorbell ringing]
- [Saavedra] Mrs. Magnolia?
- Yes?
Nice to meet you. Gabriela Saavedra,
from the El Global newspaper.
Some years ago, Ms.
Márquez filed a complaint.
I only want to ask her some questions.
[woman] I'm sorry. She
doesn't live here anymore.
I'm carrying out an
investigation on General Blanco.
- I think...
- No.
- I would like to... Only...
- No, I'm not interested.
- If only you...
- I'm not interested.
[sighs]
CHIAPAS
BORDER OF MEXICO-GUATEMALA
- [Chío sighs]
- [Joaquín] Like it?
It's beautiful.
I'll buy you a bigger one later.
Once I finish that
business in El Salvador,
you'll know how it feels
to live like a queen.
Hmm.
[door opening]
[Toño] We're ready, boss.
Be careful.
Take this.
Make this house nice.
[door opening]
Chapo, Rosado is asking for more money.
He's never satisfied.
The price on your head
is tempting for anyone.
Protecting you is expensive.
Give him what he's asking for.
- [car engine starts]
- Good luck.
[tapping the trunk]
- What do you think, Toño?
- It's safe.
It may work.
How long does it take
to get to the border?
About 40 minutes.
[car moving]
Do you know if he already
got to El Salvador?
No, boss.
But we have people at the border.
They'll let us know as soon
as he sets foot in there.
If they find him...
tell them to kill him.
And then they can let us know.
[car moving forward]
[car stopping]
BORDER CHECKPOINT
GUATEMALA - EL SALVADOR
[police officer] IDs, please.
[footsteps]
[police officer] I'm
going to check your trunk.
[opening trunk]
[cars passing by]
[police officer] Why are
you going to El Salvador?
[Toño] To visit some
friends in Barillas.
You may continue.
Welcome to El Salvador.
[closing the car's trunk]
[car engine starts]
[car moving]
PORT LA LIBERTAD EL SALVADOR
[groaning]
Welcome to El Salvador.
Thank you for coming.
[Conrado] Did you
get what you needed?
I have all the pieces to
start building the puzzle.
Great.
See you soon.
[Saavedra] You are really brave
for wanting to relive the past.
I was brave when I reported him
to the district attorney's office.
But just as he'd warned
me, it was useless.
Your story will be invaluable.
If I may, I'll record this.
[woman] I'm not
afraid of him anymore.
At that time I was afraid.
I was only 18 years old.
He threatened me to kill
my family if I spoke.
Thank God, I had the
support of my family.
I gave them the description,
everything they needed,
but nothing happened.
That bastard never
paid for what he'd done.
[automated typing]
I have the men Rosado asked for.
The shipment is protected.
I need to know how many
people are keeping watch.
This is the address.
And this is what we've
agreed to pay you.
SAN LORENZO NEIGHBORHOOD
SAN SALVADOR, EL SALVADOR
[in English] Anything?
[in English] Nothing. All quiet.
CHAPO'S WAREHOUSE SAN
LORENZO NEIGHBORHOOD
Who's that? [In
Spanish] Do you know him?
Yes, he lives in the neighborhood.
[in English] Should I take a look?
[in English] No, it's okay. He's clean.
I'll go fetch some
empanadas. Do you want some?
[in English] Yes, please.
Five without chili.
We call it ají here.
Well, same thing, right?
We'll take the blow from here.
We'll take it to Cuba...
and then directly to Miami.
We have to make this
route something big, Toño.
Do you think we'll go
back to Mexico some day?
Do you want some sauce with that?
No, the gringos
cannot eat spicy food.
I'll just put tomatoes, then.
- How many are there?
- He just said they were gringos.
Tell me, kid, what did they buy?
Empanadas, no chili.
How many with no chili?
Eh... five.
[drug trafficker] The situation
is worst than we thought.
The DEA is watching your shipment.
Are you 100% sure?
Yes, sir, there are at least five.
And I checked with
my contact in Customs.
They entered through Mexico.
Damn it.
What do you want to do, boss?
Get your men ready.
I'm sorry, what?
Let's get the shipment.
But sir...
We cannot go against the DEA.
- [cocks gun]
- You'll do as I say!
That's why I'm paying
you, son of a bitch! Eh?
Get out of here.
We'll call you later.
I know we need that shipment,
but we cannot mess with the DEA.
Remember what happened
to Quintero and Neto
over the Kiki Camarena issue.
There's always a way, Toño.
Nobody believed in my tunnel,
but there's always a way out.
[shooting]
[shooting continues]
Stop! Come on! Come on!
[police officer] Secure the area!
[police sirens wailing]
- [car passing]
- [sirens recede]
[sighs]
It will be published tomorrow.
Thank you for coming.
I wanted to say goodbye personally.
Say goodbye?
I'm leaving Mexico as soon as possible.
Once your article appears
in tomorrow's newspaper,
General Blanco won't
stop until finding out
who leaked that information.
I won't say a word,
you can rest assured.
I don't betray my sources.
I know that.
And I'm really thankful.
I'd like to ask you for a
personal favor before leaving.
Mm-hmm?
Can you give me a copy of your article?
I'm afraid I won't have access
to your newspaper after I'm gone.
And I wouldn't like to
miss the chance to feel
the pleasure of reading the article
that will finish the General.
[Toño] Yes, sir.
I'll tell the boss.
This is all I could get for you.
I gave Lora all the instructions.
We'll have to give Herrerías
all the money we have
so we can work for him.
It'd mean going back to square
one, but if he takes us in,
we'll be protected by his organization.
If you want to go back to
Mexico, you're free to do so.
I'll always have your back.
You managed to be at the top over
there, and you'll do the same here.
Well, then...
Let's find another way
to cross the border,
even if we have to become moles.
[laughing]
And I won't get into that trunk again.
Not even for 30 minutes.
- [keys clink]
- Come on, let's go.
GUATEMALA CITY GUATEMALA
[Rosado] When do you
want to meet Herrerías?
[Lora] As soon as possible.
Things didn't go as
planned in El Salvador.
[sighs]
They should have arrived already.
[door opening]
Finally.
What happened with the meeting?
It's settled.
Rosado and Herrerías will wait
for you in the Panamericano Hotel.
Boss.
Thanks for everything, Lora.
I'm sorry I have to go, but
I need to go back to Mexico.
Call me if you need anything.
We have 1.5 million.
[Joaquín] What's with all the security?
PANAMERICANO HOTEL GUATEMALA CITY
You don't trust Herrerías?
Herrerías is like that
when he leaves his house.
He wants extra security.
Go ahead.
- Where's Herrerías?
- [cocking guns]
[Rosado] He's not coming.
Let's do this the right way,
Chapo. I don't want you to get hurt.
It's a shame that your business
in El Salvador didn't work, but...
this is your new reality.
The price for your head is
an opportunity we cannot miss.
If this is about money,
let's talk about it.
I can be more generous
than the government.
If you let me go, I'll
give you 1.5 million.
[Joaquín] 500,000 more than the reward.
With that money you can retire.
[knocking on door]
- [punch and moaning]
- [Joaquín] Hey! Hey!
[frightened panting]
[groaning]
[Joaquín] You fucking
traitor! Son of a...!
[Toño groaning]
[Rosado] I need to
speak with the President.
From Lieutenant Rosado.
Good evening, Mr. President.
I'd like to inform you that
we've captured El Chapo Guzmán.
Thank you very much, from the President.
We won't forget how helpful you were.
General Blanco will
coordinate the operation.
I don't want any information
leaked to the press.
I want the news to be out tomorrow,
once I'm at the border with him.
All right, General.
Amado.
El Chapo was detained
in Guatemala.
GENERAL BLANCO, THE PRESIDENT'S
RIGHT HAND AND UNPUNISHED CRIMINAL
[President] What's this?
I found it by chance.
My contact informs me that
it will be published tomorrow.
We have some time to stop it.
[intercom]
Lucía, please, telephone the owner
of the El Global newspaper.
[Lucía] Of course, sir.
- [intercom]
- Good job, Conrado.
You deserve a promotion.
[telephone ringing]
[President] Peralta, what's
going on in your newspaper?
I've just read an article
by Gabriela Saavedra.
What's that all about?
It's not important how I found out.
What's important here is
the content of that article.
It's unacceptable.
- [airplanes taking off]
- [radios buzzing]
Good morning.
[sighs]
[explosion]
- [shooting]
- [in English] Go, go, go, go!
Put your hands up!
- Everybody, that's right.
- Get down, get down.
Get down, motherfucker.
Put him down.
Everybody start making this.
Yeah, that's right, punk.
Load the van! Load the van!
- Come on!
- Get up! Get up! Get up!
MILITARY HEADQUARTERS
GUATEMALA - MEXICO BORDER
[Rosado] Put those two in that truck.
El Chapo goes in my truck.
[groaning]
[Rosado] Let's go!
[Joaquín] Rayito.
- What's up, buddy?
- A toast to this great life!
[laughing]
Here you are, Güero, take
it. This is pure power.
This is freedom, Güero! Look!
This is great!
[Joaquín] Keep
playing, my friends!
Keep playing, man!
[opening the airplane's door]
[Joaquín] This
is the real power.
This is freedom!
Synced and corrected by Chitorafa
www.addic7ed.com
Subtitle translation by Mariana Taguchi