[girl] Hi. Or should that be:
[in British accent] How do you do?
[chuckles] [in normal voice] I'm Zoe.
I'm 15 and...
Uh, guys? Guys? Wrong girl.
I'm the out-of-place American over here,
and this is England.
Beautiful, isn't it?
This place smells of cow.
[Zoe] Yeah, now you come to mention it,
there's a definite aroma.
That's my little sister, Rosie.
She's more LA than a wannabe actor sipping
on kale juice.
We've been walking for days.
Are we lost?
I know these roads
like the back of my hand. I'm not lost.
[Zoe] That's my mom. She's totally lost,
in more ways than one.
- Ooh, look at that.
- [bird squawking]
Is that a buzzard?
[Zoe] And that, my friends,
is a really big horse.
- Excuse me.
- [Rosie gasps]
[Zoe] Sorry. Hope my sister didn't get
in the way of your massive horse.
[Rosie] Oh!
My party shoes.
Did someone say party?
- Gramps!
- [Frank] Zoe!
But how wonderful to see you!
Ah. I thought you were going to camp.
Where's your dad?
Long story.
Dad, you're not supposed to be driving.
I'm not supposed to be driving a car.
This isn't a car.
- Now, who wants a lift to the house?
- [Rosie] Me.
Get on the back there. Right, that's it.
Welcome home.
Ding, ding!
[Rosie] Hit the gas, Gramps.
[Maggie] Don't encourage him.
Dad, slow down!
[Zoe] Things in LA
got kind of complicated kind of quickly.
And I figure a summer vacay
on a tiny island off the coast of England
is just what I need.
Zero parental stress,
zero weirdly possessive friends
- and absolutely zero drama.
- [tires squealing]
[Rosie] Gramps, watch out!
[cart crashes]
[Rosie] It's okay, I'm fine.
Hmm, I'll get back to you
about that whole zero drama thing.
♪ No matter what you're doin' ♪
♪ No matter what you're playin' ♪
♪ It's no matter what you're sayin' ♪
♪ 'Cause we're doing it all the same ♪
♪ No matter where you are
Where you're coming from ♪
♪ Put your hand on your heart
Don't wait ♪
♪ Yeah, you know that I, we, me, us
We're doing it all the same ♪
♪ No matter where you are
Where you're coming from ♪
♪ Put your hand on your heart
Don't wait ♪
♪ Yeah, you know that I, we, me, us
We're doing it all the same ♪
♪ Yeah, ooh ♪
[door creaks]
[Frank] Come in, come in, come in,
come in.
Yeah, yeah. Put it down.
It's all exactly the same.
[Frank] This is new.
["God Save the Queen" playing on speaker]
[music stops]
["God Save the Queen" continues playing]
- What do you think?
- That is very British.
[Zoe chuckles]
So, what happened to Huck?
- Oh, Dad's working.
- Yeah, really hard. [chuckles]
- It's all good, though. I have his ticket.
- You'd really rather spend the summer
with your old grandpa than your friends?
Yeah. They'll be there when I get back.
Probably.
Mmm. Smells good, Gramps.
What are you cooking?
- Rabbit.
- Mom, Grandpa's cooking Peter Rabbit.
[laughs]
- Couldn't you have done egg and chips?
- She should know what real food is.
I suppose it's all rehydrated tofu burgers
in LA.
Are you really going there already?
[Frank] I'm just saying, it'll be good
for them to spend time somewhere real.
Somewhere with a bit of soul.
- [Maggie] LA has soul, too.
- Oh.
[Maggie] If you'd get on a plane,
I could show you.
- [Frank] The last thing I need is LA.
- Perfect.
[Frank] I'm doing fine.
[Frank and Maggie speaking indistinctly]
[Zoe] "Dear Maggie. The light will come
through again. Love, Mama."
Cryptic. I like it.
[Rosie] Mom, why isn't the Wi-Fi working?
- [Frank] What's a Wi-Fi?
- [Rosie] Mom!
That's it. That's it.
I'm calling the embassy.
Wi-Fi is a basic human right.
[Zoe] This is what I wanted,
what I needed.
Just peace and quiet and...
Oh.
Hello, jet lag.
[Maggie] Zoe!
- Rosie's missing.
- [sighs]
- [Maggie] I've looked everywhere.
- She's probably gone... ugh! For a walk.
- Rosie doesn't do walks.
- [Maggie] She doesn't know these roads.
- She doesn't know the dangers.
- We're getting a little hysterical.
- She's only been gone five minutes.
- Grandpa, please, not helping.
Mom, relax, breathe. [inhales]
Remember your Yogalates. [exhales]
Right, yes. My breathing. Uh...
I'll go wait by the phone.
I'll find her. She couldn't have gone far.
- Is your mother always this...
- Recently, yes.
You're not really here to nurse
your invalid grandfather, are you?
- No, Grandpa.
- Thank goodness for that.
- I gotta go find Rosie.
- Yeah.
Rosie!
[Zoe] This place is so beautiful.
It needs a coffee shop right there,
but other than that, all good.
[sighs]
[girls speaking indistinctly]
Ow. Excuse me, hi.
Hey, um, I don't suppose you've seen
a ten-year-old girl about yea high,
resembles an angry ball of glitter?
- You're American.
- Oh, no, no, no, I'm French.
Really?
[Zoe] Is she serious?
I've never met a French person before.
Bonjour, stranger.
[Zoe] Oh, she's serious.
Okay, so, you haven't seen her?
Just because she's my little sister
and she's on the loose.
No, but we'll keep an eye out.
- Okay, all right. Thank you. Thank you.
- Wait, wait, wait. Um...
What are you... Why... Um...
Translation: Who are you
and what are you doing here?
Oh, well, I'm Zoe.
I'm staying here for the summer
at my gramps' house, over there.
That's right by the stables.
You should totally come and hang out.
You know, I'm not exactly
what you'd call outdoorsy.
It's not all outdoorsy.
Some of it's indoorsy.
Yeah, it's pony camp soon.
Which is gonna be horsesome.
Horsesome's my word.
- It's a combination of horse and awesome.
- Got it.
[woman] Girls!
Raven's escaped.
- What?
- I want everyone back in the yard now.
- He's been stolen. He must have been.
- You don't know that.
The security
in this place is utterly inadequate.
- I'm gonna call the police
- Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
- I'll drive around, see if I can find him.
- [Zoe] Am I in a Jane Austen novel?
Have I gone back in time?
- What is this place?
- [Sam] Marcus.
[Zoe] You've got to be kidding me.
No one looks like that in real life.
- Did I say that out loud?
- Huh?
Let's hope Raven comes quietly.
Who's Raven?
- He's...
- Just a horse.
- [Becky] A scary horse.
- I'm really worried, Daddy.
He's totally out of control.
I'm sure your sister will be fine.
- Can I borrow this?
- [Becky] Of course.
Uh, that's my bike.
Be careful.
That girl is the definition of horsesome.
It'll catch on, Jade. Just you wait.
[Zoe] Okay, detective mode engaged.
Where would a very small,
very angry little sister hide?
Okay, let's see.
Pier, picturesque.
But no Rosie.
Woods, whole lot of trees.
No Rosie.
[sighs]
Rosie!
[horse galloping]
[whinnies]
Oh, God, no.
Oh, no.
[whinnying]
Oh, no, please don't hurt her.
- That's the girl looking for her sister.
- Rope and sedatives now, Marcus.
Just stay very still!
[Zoe] No, no, no. Okay.
You must be Raven. Okay.
[whinnies]
It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
- Shh, shh, shh.
- [snorts]
Okay, okay, okay. Relax, relax.
It's all okay.
It's okay.
Wait, wait, wait. Look.
I've never seen him so calm.
Rough day, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
Just stay very still.
- [whinnies]
- Hey, hey, no, no.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Here.
Stop it, don't be like that.
Your friends are here to take you home.
- [whinnies]
- Whoa, whoa. Hey, hey, hey,
Britain's Next Top Model...
I don't think he likes that pointy thing.
- Easy, Miss America. It's just a sedative.
- We just need to get him under control.
- [whinnies]
- [Zoe] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
He was under control.
No needles. No sedatives. Just back off.
[whinnying]
I said, back off.
Okay, I get it, I get it.
You like to be free. I get it.
What's your name?
- Zoe.
- [Sam] Okay, Zoe.
Raven seems to really like you.
Could you help us
get him back to the stables?
Uh, look, I would love to help you
with your scary horse,
I really would,
but I need to find my sister.
Thing is,
it's kind of you or the sedative.
Listen. If you help us out,
we'll help you find your sister.
- Okay, what do you want me to do?
- We need to get this rope clipped on him.
- [whinnying]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, shh.
Okay, okay.
Hey. Okay.
[snorting]
Oh, hey, hey. Shh, shh. Come here.
That's great. We need you
to walk him back to the stables,
and we'll be right behind you.
If he does anything, we are right there.
Okay, okay. All right.
Okay.
Shh. It's okay, it's okay.
Couple of horse thefts on the mainland.
It could be related.
[Mia] Horse thieves?
- I knew it.
- He only said it could be.
It must have been a gang.
It'd take at least four men, four big men,
to control that horse. He's utterly wild.
[Mia] Daddy.
[Becky] This is so going on my blog.
Thank you so much, Zoe.
We've got it from here.
[Marcus] Ted, can you give me a hand?
[Ted] Steady, boy.
Steady, boy.
[Sam] Take him to the stables
and get him checked over.
[Zoe] See you soon... I guess.
[Sam] Okay, everyone, show's over.
Let's get back to work.
- It was a false alarm, Officer.
- It's Derek.
- [Sam] I'm so sorry to waste your time.
- No time wasted.
It's always good to see you.
I mean, to see the yard.
Although I'd advise a review
of your alarms and CCTV.
We'll look into it.
Yes, you will.
[sighs]
How's my favorite horse whisperer?
I'm okay. I just need to find my sister.
Right, of course.
Girls.
Wait, wait, wait.
These are Rosie's.
She's not out there. She's in here.
Somewhere.
[Zoe] Seriously, I'm like some kind
of wilderness tracker, right?
We'll help you look.
We know all the best hiding places here.
- Thanks, girls.
- We were playing hide-and-seek once,
and I got stuck in a Portaloo.
- I thought she'd gone home.
- I was in there for six hours.
I got the best photo of you and Raven.
Totally posting it.
"Mysterious Frenchwoman
hypnotizes crazy horse."
I didn't hypnotize him.
[Jade] And she's not French.
- [Becky] It's still huge.
- [Jade] Rosie?
Raven's the wildest horse in the yard.
What's his problem?
No one knows for sure.
He never lets anyone close enough
to find out.
[Jade] Rosie?
Apart from you.
Maybe he's your destiny.
- [Jade] Rosie, are you in here?
- Maybe.
Rosie, are you...?
Oh.
Hey, boy.
This really isn't
a very good hiding place.
- Raven's in here, for starters.
- It's okay. It's okay, it's just me.
We should probably go.
- Careful.
- It's okay.
So, I'm looking for my little sister.
She's a runaway, like you.
Here. See if he wants one of these.
Ah, so, that's how you brought Raven home.
- You bribed him with sweets.
- Told you it'd be something like that.
I mean, it is pretty impressive.
You know, you are the talk of the yard.
- [chuckles] I am?
- I'm Mia.
- I hope these two aren't bothering you.
- No, no, they're cool.
We were helping her look for her sister.
- I suppose you think Raven's eaten her.
- Of course not. [chuckles]
- Have you?
- [Mia] Run along.
I can take things from here.
My dad practically owns the stables.
[Susie] We can show you
how things really work around here.
- Take my number. We should hang out.
- Oh.
Are you two still here?
[Jade] Bye, then.
- I hope you find your sister.
- Wait, wait.
Uh, you know, my phone died.
- Oh.
- Yeah, it does that sometimes.
Especially when people are being mean.
- I don't think I get your meaning.
- No, I think you do.
Suit yourself.
Oh. Uh...
Girls, would you mind staying away
from my horse?
He's had such a crazy day.
Raven is your horse?
That's right, he's mine.
But don't worry,
there are plenty of other horses
in the stables suitable for tourists.
[whinnies]
I can send you that photo,
so you have something to remember him by.
Oh, thank you.
We'll have to go to the haystack.
The Wi-Fi's strongest there.
You guys have Wi-Fi?
[dance music playing on headphones]
- What are you doing?
- Oh.
Hey, sis.
I was just texting Angela and she said
that they're having a really good time.
We thought a wild horse
had run off with you.
A wild horse? Get a grip, sis.
- You found her, then?
- [Zoe] Yes. Now we're leaving.
Why the rush?
Hi, my name's Rosie,
but you can call me Rosie.
- Or just call me.
- [chuckles]
Ignore her. Home. Now.
- Call me.
- I'll see you around.
Oh, my God.
Hot Marcus totally looked at your face.
Don't most people look at your face
when they're talking to you?
I'd steer clear if I were you.
Mia's basically cocked her leg
and peed on him.
- That's disgusting.
- Excuse me.
What happened to "Home. Now"?
I'm coming.
Thank you guys so much.
I'll see you later.
Wait.
Um, just wondering... Maybe not.
You've probably got way better offers...
- She's asking for your number.
- Oh.
You told Mia your phone was dead.
Give me them digits.
[keys jingling outside]
Make sure you put all the sedatives
back in the medical cabinet.
- Can't afford to buy more right now.
- Yeah, of course.
- Luckily, we didn't have to use any today.
- I know. Thanks to that girl.
- Zoe.
- Right.
- I still can't get over it.
- I know, she was amazing.
I put Raven in the field.
He was going crazy in his stable.
I'll bring him in before it gets dark.
Better safe than sorry at the moment.
[Zoe] Mom was really worried.
[Rosie] Mom gets worried
if I walk under a ladder.
[Zoe] Just because you can't get Wi-Fi,
doesn't mean you can go off and disappear.
You know I feel funny
when I can't get online.
You are not a baby, Ro.
Then stop treating me like one.
Dad chose not to come with us, didn't he?
No, he had work. You know that.
- He's busy.
- Whatever.
As soon as we get to Grandpa's,
I'm Googling the Constitution.
[Zoe] What the...?
- What?
- Nothing.
I'm wondering
why you didn't use the gate.
Spying, are you?
Spying? No, I'm not spying.
I'm just passing.
- I'm staying with my grandpa.
- I know.
Hmm.
Have a look.
- What?
- You obviously think I'm up to something.
So, go on. Have a look.
- No, thanks.
- Suit yourself.
[Zoe] Mysterious bags
and boys coming out of bushes.
Ah, this place has got it all.
Looks like Frank's got guests up
at the house.
- A woman and...
- The girl who brought the dark horse in.
- There's something about her.
- Ah.
- The way she handled Raven, I mean...
- [sighs]
She's different.
A girl like that will break your heart
given half a chance.
- Who said I'd give her a chance?
- I mean it, son.
- Leave well alone.
- What's it to you?
Her family are trouble.
You think everyone's trouble.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
[Maggie] Right, that's one
very grubby daughter in the bath.
- Where exactly did you find her?
- The stables.
- The stables?
- [Zoe] Mm-hmm. Yeah, they had Wi-Fi.
[chuckling] Poor you, having to deal
with a bunch of pony princesses.
No, they weren't...
Tomorrow I'll go into the village
and set Grandpa up with the Internet.
Oh, no. I don't need you coming over here,
bringing all your new-fangled LA ideas.
[laughs] It's not an LA thing.
It's the whole world.
- It's about time you caught up.
- [sighs]
[Rosie] Mom,
where's my strawberry glitter shampoo?
So, you liked the stables, then?
Yeah, yeah, I did.
[Frank] Bright Fields is a good place.
I just hope young Sam can keep it going.
- Mom doesn't seem to think much of it.
- [mutters]
Maggie's always been more of a city girl.
- [alarm ringing]
- Oh.
[phone chimes]
[chuckles]
Now, where were we?
[Maggie] What are you doing up here?
This better be good. I'm about to dive
into a world of knights and ghosts and...
Vampire cats?
Myths and Legends.
I used to love that book
when I was your age.
[sighs]
I wanted to say thank you for today.
You've been a star.
- I'm sorry for being such a...
- Massively overprotective drama queen?
I was gonna go with "concerned mom."
[Zoe chuckles]
Having Rosie to chase round the island
will give you something to do this summer.
Mm, right after I come up with new
and interesting ways to lie about Dad.
- I'm sorry, Mom...
- It's okay.
Your dad and I just need a bit
of time apart to figure out...
where we're going wrong.
Yeah. Yeah.
Enjoy the book.
Thank you.
[Zoe] And now, finally,
the total peace and quiet can begin.
No more panicking moms,
no more lost sisters,
and no more dangerous wild horses.
[horse nickers]
[Zoe] I said, no more wild horses.
[Zoe] Check me out, totally resisting.
Nope, mnh-mnh, not interested.
[horse neighs]
[Zoe] Ah... who am I kidding?
Hey.
Hey, boy. Hey.
I just wanted to come
and say good night.
We're famous.
[lens whirs]
[shutter clicks]
[Raven snorts]
Hey. What's wrong?
Is someone there?
Hey.
Tch. It's okay. It's just you and me.
There's nothing to be scared of.
I promise.
[shutter clicking]
[chuckles]