Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
[Scandal's "The Warrior" playing]
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Who's the hunter? Who's the game? ♪
♪ I feel the beat call your name ♪
♪ I'll hold you close in victory ♪
♪ I don't wanna tame your animal style ♪
♪ You won't be caged
In the call of the wild ♪
♪ Shooting at the walls of heartache
Bang, bang ♪
♪ I am the warrior ♪
♪ Yes, I am the warrior ♪
♪ And victory is mine ♪
- ♪ Shooting at the walls of heartache ♪
- ♪ The warrior ♪
♪ I am the warrior ♪
In this world...
there are good guys...
and there are bad guys.
And we... are the good guys.
You see that name on my door?
It's my father's name, son of a bitch.
But this isn't about him.
This is about justice.
This is about holding on to what's ours.
This is about my company and my name.
And I will not be bullied into submission.
Whoo! [Laughs, sniffles] Oh...
I just wanna say thank you so much
for bringing me in for this.
There aren't roles like this
for women right now.
It's really... ooh.
[laughs] It's really great.
You were reading the man's part.
Oh, God. Uh... [chuckles]
Sorry. That's...
'cause I just thought Mel
was short for Melanie,
and then the other part was...
- Would you like to start over?
- Yes, I would.
Okay.
This is about my firm and my name,
and I will not be bullied into submission.
Sorry to interrupt.
Your wife is on line two.
Okay. Thank you, Ruth.
[urinating]
Hey, Mallory.
It's Ruth Wilder.
I was hoping to get
some feedback on my audition.
Have you been hiding in here for an hour?
[toilet flushes]
Can you at least tell me who got the part?
Was it Jeanie Barton?
She's... in the mix.
You bring me in a lot.
And you never cast me.
If there's something I need to change,
I wanna change it.
[sighs]
Every director says,
"Bring me someone I don't know.
Someone I haven't seen.
I want a girl who's real."
So, I bring you in so they can see
that they don't actually want
the thing they think they want.
[sighing] Look...
I do cast some experimental projects
on the side,
if you are open to that kind of thing.
- What kind of thing?
- Would you consider erotica?
[scoffs] Porn? Like, in the Valley?
Obviously, I'm not suggesting
you go have sex on camera...
unless that's something
you're interested in.
What I'm interested in are real parts.
Not secretaries telling powerful men
their wives are on line two.
You read the man's part on purpose,
didn't you?
It's the better part.
No shit.
That's why we gave it
to Steve Guttenberg.
Five, six, seven, eight! Feel it.
[dance music playing over speakers]
Find it.
Do it.
Want it.
♪ You make me feel ♪
To the right.
Hip, hip, hip.
♪ Mighty real ♪
♪ Make me feel mighty real ♪
Get loose, ladies.
Hi.
- You missed half the class.
- Sorry.
[instructor] And looser.
- Thought we're supposed to be tightening.
- Some things are never getting tighter.
[instructor] And squeeze.
And squeeze.
♪ And I feel your body
Close to mine ♪
- Debbie.
- What?
Debbie, boob.
Oh, my God.
Oh, make it stop.
♪ Make me feel ♪
I'm a fucking bovine mutant.
- Maybe if I do this?
- Here.
[laughing]
♪ You make me feel ♪
- That's good.
- Whoo!
Did I tell you the casting director
offered me porn?
Uh... you?
The girl who changes under her shirt?
I don't do that anymore.
Well... [groans] Oh, Jesus.
Obviously you shouldn't do porn.
Unless it's, like, porn Shakespeare.
Since you're such a nerd,
you'd probably enjoy that.
You know, I miss you making fun of me.
Why don't you come visit me
in Pasadena, then?
- Ugh. It's so far away.
- Come on.
I've called you like a million times
to hang out. What is going on?
Ruth, are you okay?
It's just... little, stupid stuff.
You know, like,
don't know if I can pay my gas bill.
I've got $83 in my bank account,
and I'm waitressing all weekend.
And I've eaten Cinnamon Toast Crunch
for my last...
six meals.
But, hey, you know, I'm gonna do porn.
So, things are looking up. Heh.
Can I tell you something
that I realized recently?
- What?
- When I first got Paradise Cove,
I was... God, so excited.
And then they put me
in the year-long coma.
And I would lie in that hospital bed,
just feeling powerless.
And then season three,
I graduate to a wheelchair
- with, like, a sad blanket...
- I'm sorry.
- How is this supposed to help me?
- I'm getting there.
Everything changed when Mark was like,
"Deb, don't be unhappy.
Let's have a baby. I'll support us."
And I was like, "Yes. Yeah.
Why am I working?"
Getting pregnant
and written off that show,
best decision I ever made.
I choose work.
But you're not working.
I... [chuckles]
Don't you wanna be happy
and have a family?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Uh...
I think I need to get a boyfriend first.
Isn't that how it works?
[chuckles]
- [Debbie] Okay.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
- Witness is playing at the Dome.
- I can't leave my mom with Randy all day.
She'll feed him Funyuns and Fresca
and government conspiracies.
Go.
Go, I get it.
Um...
I, um...
- I miss you, too.
- [scoffs]
Randy only loves you
'cause your boobs are full of food.
- [clicks]
- [tape rewinds]
[beeps]
- [Mallory] Is that... Am I...
- [sighs]
Oh, I didn't... I didn't hear the beep.
Ruth. Hi, it's Mallory.
- [gasps]
- There's an audition. I'm not running it.
They're looking for unconventional women,
whatever the hell that means,
and I thought of you.
I'll have my girl follow up
with the details.
It's not porn.
If you ever accost me
in the bathroom again...
you'll be blacklisted
from every casting call in Los Angeles.
Good luck.
- [line disconnects]
- [machine beeps]
Whoo!
[rock music playing over stereo]
♪ I've been finding my way
For a long, long time ♪
♪ You know I'm dying to get ahead
But falling way behind ♪
[women chattering and laughing]
[chattering indistinctly]
Have they started the audition?
I don't know. I've actually never done one
of these before.
Are you SAG?
What? I...
I'm part Cherokee.
Well, it's not porn. Just so you know.
Oh.
I didn't know we were supposed
to wear costumes.
[sniffles, clears throat]
Okay.
I said I'd do anything,
so, here we fucking are.
Okay.
Hello, ladies.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I'm Sam Sylvia.
Today we're just gonna be doing
first looks and first cuts.
- Are there sides?
- I didn't get any sides.
This is how this is gonna go, all right?
No more talking. Just sit there...
and look at me and smile.
Okay?
Tell us what the hell we're doing here.
Oh...
- Hi, Cherry.
- Hey, baby.
- How you doing, baby? Mm-hmm.
- Good.
This another one of your
trashy vampire movies?
What? No.
This is not a movie.
This... is GLOW.
Sorry, what's GLOW?
Gorgeous Ladies of Wrestling.
This is a wrestling television show.
Only ladies. Lady wrestling.
Just like the big guys, but girls.
Get it? Girl on girl.
- What?
- So, like, Hulk Hogan?
If one of you turns out to be Hulk Hogan,
I've hit the fucking jackpot.
All right, take it easy.
This is what's happening.
Yes, this is a wrestling show, and yes...
you're all gonna have to actually wrestle
on cable television
for thousands of people.
That means...
- tit grabs...
- [woman] Tit grabs?
Cunt punches, shrinky dinks.
That move that looks like a catfight,
but fancy.
Did I say cunt punches?
- Yeah.
- [Sam] Okay, good.
- [chattering]
- So, if any of you have a problem
with, uh, doing a wrestling show...
I suggest you leave now.
[chattering indistinctly]
[Sam] Thank you.
Really? You're going?
Thank you.
[woman] Bye.
- [woman 2] Bye.
- [woman 3] Good luck, guys.
[chuckles]
What happened there?
You just... decided?
- Yeah.
- All right, for those remaining,
congratulations, you made it
through the first round of cuts.
- Pretty painless, right?
- [laughing and chattering]
I guess what we gotta do now is,
I'm gonna sit over there...
and you guys are gonna line up,
get your headshots out,
and I'm also gonna have to have you sign
a waiver...
in case of, uh, serious injury,
and/or death.
[women murmuring]
You seem to be very versatile
with window coverings.
Well, I'm from London, so... [chuckles]
- I don't know what that means.
- Yeah.
- Your eyes are closed.
- That's what happens when you blow.
- Can you blow with your eyes open?
- Okay.
Resume gets a little thin after 1979.
- Movies get a little white after 1979.
- Mm-hmm.
You've seen my stunts.
I can kick. I can punch.
I can do horse work, car work...
Yeah, I know you can double,
but can you act?
Freeze, motherfucker.
- Next.
- Wow.
Yeah. I'm gonna need you to do that, too.
[chuckles]
What is that?
- Here.
- Look at you. You're like the parade.
- Oh, my goodness. Thank you so much.
- Yeah.
I throw things.
- Do you think you could throw people?
- Yeah.
All right. Well, come back tomorrow.
- [Reggie] Yeah.
- [Sam] Whoa.
We're hairstylists at the Carlton Salon
at the Beverly Center.
Our clients think we're funny
and should be on television.
- You get two for one.
- I'm exhausted.
[Sam] How old are you?
Nineteen.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Okay. We'll see.
Yeah. Come on.
Ruth Wilder. Looks like you.
Yeah. It's a headshot.
Oh. Strindberg. Who the fuck is that?
- Oh, it's a playwright.
- I'm kidding. I know who Strindberg is.
I'm not an idiot.
So, what are you, like a...
Like a real actor?
Yeah.
I've done a bunch of plays in Omaha,
at a little spot called
the Blue Barn Theatre.
I did a film a few years back.
I've also done extensive mask work
and clowning workshops.
How much acting will there be?
As opposed to what?
Hair pulling?
- You don't like wrestling?
- Well, I don't really know wrestling.
You don't think wrestling is acting?
It's not, is it? It's...
It's more like a sport with costumes?
Or... Sorry, are you...
Are you hiring actors
to play wrestlers,
or are we the wrestlers?
Yes.
Which one?
Do people think you're pretty?
Because, like, I'm looking at you...
One second, I think,
"Fuck, yeah, she's hot,"
and then the next second I'm like,
"I don't know. Is she? Really?"
I mean, you just have one of those
faces that kind of... changes.
Like, "Eh... Hmm."
I don't know.
- What the hell does that mean?
- It means I don't know.
Ruth.
That is not a great name.
[sighs]
Hey, guys. It's me.
I really didn't wanna do this again,
but, um... I need you guys to...
wire me $200
so they don't turn off my phone...
and so I can eat.
I'm really sorry.
I swear this is the last time.
I love you.
Oh, I, uh... got a call back.
So, fingers crossed, again.
Okay.
Bye.
[panting]
Hello? Hello?
I have mace!
Wait. It's me.
[gasps] Oh, my God!
What are you doing?
Why are you climbing in my window?
You said you didn't want anyone
to find out about us.
- I took that seriously.
- No, no. Climb out. Go.
Are you kidding me?
You know how hard that was?
You ever tried to climb a trellis?
Wh...?
[exhales deeply]
I'm pretty proud of myself.
For trying to cheat on your wife again?
[sighs] Let's not... Don't...
Please, can we not use those words?
This isn't normal behavior for me.
[sighs]
I just... I can't...
- I can't stop thinking about you.
- So?
It was a huge mistake.
And those drinks were free and...
And I was feeling sorry for myself,
and you took advantage of that.
I think we both took advantage of that.
Please, go home to your family.
I keep thinking about what you said
that night. About how there are...
shiny people who have everything,
and then there are people like us
who have to go to parties
with those people
and watch them get their pictures taken,
and it's not fair.
Because we deserve stuff, too.
We deserve attention.
And...
like...
sex.
[both moaning]
Oh, my God.
Ruth.
You're... You're amazing.
Yeah, thank you.
You're so real.
Mm-mm.
You... Ow. Ah. Ha!
You are the most real person
that I've ever been with.
Okay.
Shh. Shh.
[both shushing]
[both moaning]
[Sam] Okay, over the next two days,
I'm gonna be casting a squad of 12 women
to play wrestlers on TV.
Based on one, can you move,
and can you follow basic direction?
And two, do I like your face,
- or do I not like your face?
- [murmuring]
All right.
If I call your number and say,
"Thank you,"
you've been cut.
So, dry your tears
and leave the ring quietly.
Now, this hulking specimen over here
is what...? What is it?
Salty "The Sack" Johnson.
You've heard of him, right?
He's the two-time champion
of... some stuff.
All right, if you don't wanna leave here
with a broken spine,
I suggest you listen to what
he has to say very carefully.
All right, go ahead.
Ladies...
we're gonna go through the basics,
so, you need to focus.
You heard the big man.
Go ahead.
First up, forward rolls.
- [Sam] Whoa.
- Just like preschool.
Not like preschool.
Everyone off the ropes. Let's get to work.
[Sam] You heard him.
Oh, shit.
What... What the fuck?
Who even, like, watches this sport?
- I feel like...
- Uh, everyone.
Even my nani watches WWF Superstars.
She's 85, and she only speaks Hindi.
Okay, number 18.
Ugh.
You remind me of my ex-wife. Thanks.
He's already cutting people?
I thought this was just a warm-up.
- Better make it count, then, right?
- [Salty] Next.
Let's go. Come on.
Oof... Ah!
Yes.
Hi.
[Ruth exhales]
[sighs]
Attack... the ropes.
Do not be afraid.
First two, get in.
[Reggie] Good. All right.
Let's go.
[grunting]
Ouch. Floor girl.
Can't see your number... Bye.
Yes! Still in the fuckin' game.
Fuck yes!
[yells]
Oh, Christ.
This throw is called the hair mare.
[all gasp]
Exactly.
Let's go!
Your turn, ladies.
So, what's our backstory?
Our what?
What's motivating this?
Why are we fighting? What's...
What's driving you to come after me
and grab me by the hair
and throw me to the ground?
It has to be something.
He told us to.
Look, there's still a lot of girls,
which means anyone could be cut.
We have to go above and beyond.
Trust me.
- I'm an actress. I know what I'm doing.
- Okay.
- Honey.
- [chuckles]
The victim does all the work.
You just gotta tug
on my hair a little bit.
I'll do the rest.
[women gasp]
Nice. Good job, Cherry.
- Cute outfit, Pippi Longstockings.
- [chuckles]
[Salty] Next!
- [growling]
- Get off of me!
Creepy, but I like it.
Next!
Please!
I beg you!
I am not your enemy!
You stole.
Bread.
- For my family.
- What the fuck is this?
Just do the move.
We are. We are.
We're just motivating it with backstory.
There is a law...
There is a law, and you broke it.
And now, you will pay the ultimate price.
Okay, all right. That's it.
Number 30, number 22, thank you.
What?
- Why?
- What do you mean, "Why?"
I gave you basic direction.
You didn't follow it. You're both out.
There are no scenes to read,
no character work,
so, yes, we improvised.
Jesus Christ.
Fucking actresses.
All right. I'm feeling generous.
Sophie's Choice.
Why should I pick you and not her?
Go. Girl fight.
I'm a real actress.
I will work my ass off,
and I will make you believe me
when I do stuff,
even if it's just hair pulling.
Well, that was a very nice pitch.
Very earnest. What about you?
My dad's Goliath Jackson.
Holy shit.
Holy shit, why?
He's a giant. I mean...
he's a legend in the ring,
but he's also literally... gigantic.
And the brothers, too.
Mighty Tom Jackson and Big Kurt Jackson.
No shit.
The Lumberjacksons.
The Lumberjacksons?
It's an honor to meet you.
Thanks.
Hard sell. But I'm gonna have to go
with the dynasty. You're out.
Why? Because my dad
was a high school science teacher
- and not some famous giant?
- Maybe.
Or 'cause I don't like
your face, or your ass.
I don't know.
Maybe I like both of 'em too much.
I don't...
I don't have to explain myself.
That's the beauty of being a director.
You're out.
[sighs]
Move out of my way, fuckwad!
What you smiling at,
you Pert Plus-looking bitch?
Are you guys a band or something?
Fuck that.
We're the Los Angeles Death Squad.
Fuck you, Nancy Reagan.
- Give me that taco!
- Hey, that's my taco!
[stammers] Get your own... Stop! No!
What? That was my lunch and my dinner,
you little assholes!
Fuck! No!
[boy] Bitch.
Give me my keys!
I don't care about the purse!
But just the... Give me my keys!
I need my keys!
[Debbie] Where the fuck are we?
You got jumped by a bunch of children?
No. No.
They were...
teenagers.
They weren't, like...
They were almost teenage...
They were... They were small,
but they were feral. They were,
you know, not well-cared for.
It was...
It was very scary.
It sounds so scary.
Fuck.
My apartment key. Fuck.
Don't swear in front of Randy.
I'm sorry.
Hi.
I'm kidding. Of course you can swear
in front of him. He's a fucking baby.
And I think I still have a spare key
to your apartment in my bag.
- No.
- Yes.
You still have that key?
Oh!
Oh, thank God.
Oh, God. Mark had food poisoning
in that photo from poke.
Lost three pounds, though. Fat fuck.
- Huh.
- Yeah.
You wanna come over for dinner?
No, I can't. I have a scene study class.
Really? You're still going to that?
[sighs] [in Southern accent] Brick.
How much longer does this have to go on?
This punishment?
Haven't I done time enough?
Haven't I served my term?
Can I apply for a pardon?
Oh, right.
Maggie, you're spoiling my liquor...
You know what I feel like, Brick?
I feel all the time like a...
[in normal voice]
Like a cat on a... hot tin roof. Neil!
Why the fuck are you sleeping?
[sobs]
I paid for this scene study class.
This is the only place
I get to do what I wanna do.
I don't have anywhere else to go.
[man over TV]
From Venice Beach, California,
weighing 303 pounds...
The Incredible Hulk Hogan!
[crowd cheers on TV]
[grunting]
Hyah!
Weighing in... at a hundred and...
fifteen pounds...
Yeah!
[man on TV] Mr. Ric Flair.
Premenstrual Syndrome.
She gets moody.
And now she needs a nap.
[grunting]
[yells]
Sleep!
Train, say your prayers,
eat your vitamins.
Chewables and the swallow kind.
I'm coming for you, Hep Cat.
[hissing]
Body slam! [Grunting]
Be true to yourself.
True to your country.
Be a real American. Hoo.
[sighs]
[exhales]
[clears throat]
[sniffles, clears throat]
[Sam] Okay. Five minutes, everybody.
Hey!
- [woman 1] I thought she was cut?
- [woman 2] Yeah.
[woman 3] That's what I thought.
You're wrong about me.
Yeah, I doubt it.
Damn, girl.
[sighs]
How long must this... go on?
This punishment?
Haven't I served my term?
Can't I apply... for a pardon?
You know what I feel like?
I feel... all the time...
like a cat...
[hissing]
On a hot tin roof.
Who has come here...
to save...
you...
and you...
from evil.
[yelps]
Train. Say your prayers.
Eat your vitamins.
'Cause, uh...
- Oh...
- [Debbie] You fucking bitch!
Oh, you fucking cunt!
I should fucking kill you!
- What are you doing here?
- Don't play dumb, homewrecker!
Husband-fucker!
Hold on, hold on, hold on,
wait, wait, wait.
Did you sleep with Mark?
[women gasp]
Don't make me answer that.
[sobbing]
You want me to take him for you?
Yes. Thank you.
I wanna hear you say it.
Uh...
What the fuck kind of friend are you?!
- I don't love him!
- Oh, my God.
Of course you don't.
You don't love anyone.
I know! I fucked up.
You think I don't know that?
[Ruth yells]
How long? How long were you two...
What? While I was pregnant?
- No! God, no! It was one time!
- Oh, what? What about the other night?
That doesn't fucking count?
Mark told me the whole thing!
I know. I told you, I fucked up.
- [gasps]
- [Cherry] Damn.
Oh...
[woman] Here we go.
I don't know...
I don't know what I'm supposed to do.
It just happened.
Haven't you learned anything
from that sad fucking scene study class?
Things don't just happen.
People make choices.
They want things,
and then they go for them.
Can we go somewhere and talk about this?
I don't wanna fucking talk to you.
I wanna... [inhales sharply]
I wanna kick your ass.
And then I never want to see you again.
No!
- Come on.
- I'm not gonna fight you!
Fight her! Do it!
- Come on!
- Debbie!
[grunting]
- [Ruth grunts]
- [women gasp]
[Debbie panting]
I'm sorry.
[Ruth yells]
- [Debbie] Fucker!
- [Justine] Holy shit!
[Ruth yells]
- Is this real?
- Who the fuck cares?
- [yells]
- [screams]
No!
[crowd roaring]
[Journey's "Separate Ways (Worlds Apart)"
playing]
♪ Here we stand ♪
♪ Worlds apart
Hearts broken in two, two, two ♪
♪ Sleepless nights ♪
♪ Losing ground
I'm reaching... ♪
[crowd chanting]
You suck! You suck! You suck!
♪ Feelin' that it's gone
Can't change your mind ♪
[mouths]
♪ If we can't go on
To survive the tide ♪
♪ Love divides ♪
♪ Someday love will find you ♪
♪ Break those chains that bind you ♪
♪ One night will remind you ♪
♪ If he ever hurts you ♪
♪ True love won't desert you ♪
♪ You know I still love you ♪
♪ I still love you, girl ♪
♪ I really love you, girl ♪
[crowd roaring]
♪ No ♪
[Salty] Sam!
- Sam?
- Yeah?
Should we call it?
[Debbie and Ruth grunting]
Yeah. Call it.
[gasping]
One, two, three.
♪ Stir it up ♪
♪ Got to break it up now ♪
♪ When I think about tomorrow, ooh
I can't wait ♪
♪ To stir it up, yeah ♪
♪ Got to shake it up now ♪
♪ If I have to beg or borrow ♪
♪ I'm not gonna take it anymore ♪
♪ So much pressure to keep holding on ♪
♪ Pack my clothes up, baby
I'll be gone ♪
♪ Stir it up
I got to break it up now ♪
♪ When I think about tomorrow
I can't wait to ♪
♪ Stir it up, got to shake it up now ♪