Previously on "How to Get Away
with Murder"...
We immediately
suspend your license.
You can't fire me
because of this.
Without a license,
your tenure gets nullified.
You're an alcoholic.
No, the problem is
you're a little bitch!
Get help.
My name is Annalise Keating,
and I'm an alcoholic.
Nate?
You don't know how long
I've been wanting this
to happen.
My father's dead.
I lied.
My father found Frank.
He's in Coalport.
He killed your father.
Don't tell Annalise.
Dr. Lowell!
She's pregnant.
Oh, my God.
I know her.
sign of hydrops
Good.
And what's taking
the O.B. so long?
Page down to plastics.
We need to debride these burns.
Do they not know that?
There is some concern
with smoke inhalation.
Uh. What does that mean?
Is she gonna die?
Okay, you need
to keep your voice down, okay?
I could get in a lot of trouble
for even telling you this.
I just want to make sure
she's okay.
I'm sorry.
I know,
and I promise you,
I'm gonna tell you
everything I can, okay?
H-Have you thought about
contacting the others?
No. What am I --
I wanted to make sure
we had more information...
Hi.
I'm here.
Just don't worry.
I know. I'm on it.
Please try to trust me.
Laurel's pregnant.
We're happy to plan
whatever you like.
The funeral, flowers,
any burial services.
That won't be
necessary.
Do you need a moment?
No.
Cremate him.
Of course.
Just are you in town
for a bit?
You could pick up the ashes,
or we could mail them.
Can anyone see you calling me
right now?
No, I'm in my car.
Where are you?
Leaving the funeral home.
Oh. How was it?
Lovely.
Stupid question.
Sorry.
Have you seen Frank?
No.
You'll call me
when you do?
If I do.
I'll call you later.
Thank you.
So, Meggy wants to have
a buttload of your babies,
basically?
No.
Mm. You better start saving
for a ring.
Personally, I think anything
under three karats
is a red flag.
What are you guys
talking about?
Waitlist is meeting Meggy's
parents tonight.
Her father's in town.
We're just having dinner.
Oh, that's a big deal.
-It's not.
-It is.
And you need to dump her
before this goes bad.
Meggy's amazing.
Why would he break up with her?
None of us at this table
are fit to date civilians.
That's ridiculous.
No, what's ridiculous is you
dating doughnut-hole here
when the only thing you guys
have in common is murder.
Can we not talk about this
right here?
Maybe I should date
Waitlist.
Or Laurel.
Or we could be a throuple.
I mean, that makes just about
as much sense as you two boning.
Actually, technically,
my hotness and I
are not boning right now.
I'm pulling
a "Bull Durham"
until the arbitration
exam's over.
Hey, guys,
I got a trade opportunity.
Dumbass Gavin over there
hasn't even started
the evidence outline.
Any of you be willing to trade
for my arbitration outline?
Uh...yeah.
I'm doing our evidence outline.
I can get it to you
by Monday
Great.
Did you actually do
the reading for evidence?
No, and I didn't
for this exam either,
so I'm just gonna --
Oh, my God.
What is that?
Uh...
it's a xeroxed ass.
My ass!
Does that
turn you on, Walsh?
This is
sexual harassment.
Why don't you go
tattletale to Mommy then?
Oh, that's right.
She's still suspended.
But your
assistant called and canceled.
I'm so over her.
That's the third time
she canceled at the last minute.
I told her
not to come back.
I ain't trying to deal
with anyone.
Hey, Camila, I get it.
That's right.
It's because of your mouth.
What my mouth got to do
with anything?
You've got a loud mouth.
Don't be dealing with that
all the time.
That's true.
Miss Annalise,
can I get you some champagne?
She's a little lost
in her own world today.
Ain't that right, Annalise?
I'm sorry.
Yvonne asked you if you wanted
something to drink.
You look
like you need it.
We got champagne.
Cheap champagne.
I do not recommend it.
I'm trying to cut back.
Why?
You pregnant?
Oh, please. My eggs dried up
a long time ago.
Then you can't use your period
as an excuse
for this mood you in.
What's wrong? You finally
screw up with the cop?
Since when has my mood
been dependent on a man?
Ooh, does that mean
you done with him?
There she go.
Queen of THOT-land.
Y'all know my radar
perks up
when the conversation
turns to fine-ass sexy men.
If you're talking
about that same guy
that you showed me
in that picture one day,
then I want first dibs.
I got him next.
Ooh, honey, I would love
to take them --
You'd love to what?
Be with a man
who don't cry after sex.
You know what? That's why
I don't tell you nothing, Ro.
Wait. You want to know
what your problem is, Professor?
You're too greedy.
First you're not happy
with the white man,
now you're not happy
with the black man.
Better than being sloppy
like some people I know,
sleeping with their husband's
friends.
But see, it worked,
didn't it?
I found out Tyler
was screwing our neighbor.
Heffa, everyone knew
your husband
was sleeping
with the neighbor.
Well,
how come no one told me?
We did!
We did!                  We did!
See, that's messed up.
What's up, ladies?
Oh, no! Gone, gone!
You know the rules. Out!
We don't want your stuff.
I told his druggy behind
not to come in here anymore.
Y'all know he harmless.
He just down on his luck.
For the last 10 years?
Well, it took me 14
to get my ass clean.
Clean from what?
Oh, Ro didn't tell you
about her crack-den days?
It was cocaine mostly.
Rick wasn't playing when he said
it was a hell of a drug.
But I did the work,
used God and sex
to make me feel good,
throw some AA meetings in there,
and I'm good to go.
She still drinks.
It was that one time.
If you mean by "one time"
every Tuesday and Thursday
down at Jazzy C's...
Why'd you do it?
Which part?
You think this is funny?
Annalise would kill me
if she knew I was here, Frank.
Mm, take a number.
She's probably got
another hit man
on his way here
right now.
I don't blame her
for that.
You shot Mahoney while Wes
was standing right there.
Why?
What? You didn't?
Somebody else
just happened to shoot him?
It was me.
Why take Wes?
I needed to know
she wasn't gonna come after me.
You made him a suspect.
That is why she came after you.
Maybe Sam
was wrong about me.
Don't say that.
None of this
would've ever happened
if they just left me
in there.
Get up.
Why?
'Cause we're
gonna beat your ass.
Kidding.
You got a visitor.
Who the hell are you?
Dr. Keating.
Sit.
Your Aunt Bev knows my sister
Hannah from high school.
She was saying
how worried your family is,
that nobody's
heard from you.
You don't want them
to visit?
I'm in solitary.
Yeah,
but that was before.
You haven't spoken
to your parents
in -- what -- a few months?
Okay, look, I've worked
with a lot of people
in your
similar situation.
Sociopaths?
You've been incarcerated
since you were 13, Frank.
There's tons of research
to show how that
impacts family dynamics.
Good to know.
Truth?
Your parents told me
you were up for parole.
And they want to do
whatever they can
to get you out of here.
I even have
a lawyer for a wife
who I believe
can win your case.
And I can see it in you, too.
Frank -- you want out of here.
Let me
help get you there.
Threatening a guard,
assaulting an inmate,
and that's on top
of attempted murder?
Here's what I think.
You need to say "No"
to your sister
for once in your life.
So...I take it
that's a no?
Well, if you want me
to take a case pro bono,
how about not a white boy
who has violent tendencies?
What?
Well,
how is this different
than you asking me
to help Bonnie?
Bonnie didn't try
to kill her father.
She might've
if we hadn't helped her.
That's a reach.
Just -- Just hear me out.
He's poor,
and his family's hurting.
What's the harm
in just going to see him?
Don't get up.
Before we start,
let me be blunt.
The only way I see you
getting out
is if you admit guilt.
I don't care if it's not true,
if it was an accident.
You got to say
you did it on purpose.
Do I need
to repeat myself?
No, it's just
you're not what I expected.
What does that mean?
Your husband's
kind of vanilla.
And...?
You seem
the opposite of vanilla.
Neither of us
are vanilla.
-You guys got kids?
-Trying.
What's the problem?
His junk not work?
Sexual advance
on a female guard,
inciting a fight
in your cellblock.
Only a moron commits
these kinds of infractions
when you're up for parole.
Or you just don't want out
at all?
Which is it?
I've always been
kind of a moron.
Don't worry.
I'm not looking.
Your phone rang.
Laurel?
No.
You sure
you don't want the ashes?
I mean, we can cook them
into slop,
feed it to pigs,
or just spread them
in the worst place
imaginable.
My sister
might actually take them.
Oh, so your sister
showed up?
Yeah, she's here now.
Oh, then go.
I'll talk to you later.
It's fine.
-How are you?
-Great.
I have the whole house
to myself this weekend.
I'm gonna eat
and watch bad movies.
You still have the list
of AA meetings
I left on your desk?
Bonnie, just go and be
with your sister.
Thanks.
God, grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
courage to change
the things I can,
and wisdom to know
the difference.
Hi, I'm Jonathan.
I'm an alcoholic.
Hi, Jonathan.
Any visitors here
for the first time today?
Hi.
We usually start
by saying our names.
Do I have to?
Annalise.
Hi, Annalise.
Thank you
for joining us today, Annalise.
"Once Middleton was made aware
of the circumstances,
the office of the President
immediately began a review.
As a result, Professor Keating's
duties have been reassigned.
A new instructor
has been assigned
to the Legal Clinic
effective immediately."
Ding-dong,
the bitch is dead.
Can they do this?
Of course.
She pushed too far.
Or they couldn't handle
having a strong woman in power.
Power only works
if you know how to not abuse it.
Okay, we need to storm
the President's office,
do an "Oh, Captain!
My Captain!"
Maybe this just means
we're finally free.
Free of what?
Her.
This is bad, isn't it?
She'll figure something out.
She always does.
I-I could be out of a job,
and I really like this job.
Poor Annalise.
Had to figure I'd run
into someone I know
at one of these
sooner or later.
Professor Erickson?
You think he could do
a better job than me?
I don't think this
is the place to discuss this.
I don't care
what you think.
I'm at this meeting
in order to get my license back.
Is that the only reason
you're here?
I'll sue you.
Remind your board of that.
You think
there's a chance in hell
they would've suspended you
if they thought
you had a legitimate case?
Unbelievable.
You know what?
Stop fighting, Annalise.
It's not cute anymore.
Come home with me.
What?
She needs
to hear you say it --
that Sam forced you
to keep it from her.
I could've told her,
anyway.
You couldn't...
...because Sam
got into your head...
just like he did
to me.
This is a woman
who wants me dead.
Because she blames you
for the baby,
and that's fair.
You know that.
Of course I do.
Then come home
and tell her that.
She'll forgive you.
You just need
to forgive her first.
He was lying to me
in there.
Why? That's your job
to figure out,
but plenty of people
prefer a life on the inside.
Someone feeds you,
tells you where to be
all the time.
Sounds nice to me.
Doesn't make any sense,
though.
And yet,
that's what he's doing.
Commits crimes in jail
so he doesn't have to deal
with the real world.
My job is hard enough
dealing with people
who actually want
to be out.
He wants out.
He's just...
confused.
Come on, tell me you didn't see
what I saw -- the wounded --
I think you saw a boy
in need of a daddy.
That's not fair.
Well, neither is guilting me
into being a mother.
That's not
what this is about.
Everything coming out
of your mouth right now
is about that.
You're reaching,
and you know it.
When's the last time
you touched me?
Ever since I said no
to IVF,
I'm not enough for you --
is that it?
Annie --
You can't stand the idea
of being stuck all alone
in this house with me.
Okay, hey, hey, hey.
Come here. Come here.
Come here.
You're all I need.
And if I haven't made you
feel that way...
I'm sorry.
You...
are enough for me.
♪ ♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪ ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, Oh ♪
Look what I found
in the basement.
One of my dad's
hiding spots, clearly.
I'm not drinking that.
You want to toast
our first night here with water?
♪ Oh-oh-oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
Aw!
Oh, my God, that's the foulest
thing I've ever tasted.
Never again.
Come here.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
Hey, you still up to get dinner
with Dean Foster on Friday?
♪ Let go, let go, let go,
let go, let go ♪
I'll call the doctor.
♪ Let go, let go, let go,
let go, let go, let go ♪
let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go, let go,
let go ♪
Everyone's gonna hate us.
Two Professor Keatings
on one campus.
The new power couple.
They only hired me
as assistant professor.
Well, for now.
You'll get tenure
in record time,
way before me.
Like that was ever a question.
Wow, someone's getting cocky
pretty fast.
Yeah, you love it.
Mm.
♪ Let go, let go,
let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go,
let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go, let go,
let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go ♪
♪ Let go, let go, let go ♪
Where is it?
What are you
talking about?
One of you took my laptop.
Give it back.
-Ooh, this is good.
-This isn't funny!
Unwad your panties,
bro.
I went to the bathroom.
It was right there.
I came back,
and it was gone,
and I will call security
if I have to.
-I dare you.
-Ain't afraid of no po-po.
Okay, open your bag then
and prove you don't have it.
Hey!
It is illegal to do
an unlawful search and seizure
of someone's belongings.
This isn't funny.
That computer was expensive
and I don't have money to blow
like the rest
of your spoiled asses.
-Spoiled?
-Oh, you think we don't know
that you're just here
playing at law school
until you can swap
a rich daddy
for a rich husband?
Go anywhere near my bag
or anyone else's
in this room
and your laptop
won't be all you're missing,
you spineless, tiny-balled,
whiny excuse of a man!
Walk away.
So, Wes, where you from?
Ohio originally, but I, uh,
I moved around a lot.
Oh. Army brat?
Uh, Dad, can you just
let him eat?
This is not
an interrogation.
All right,
maybe just a little bit.
I get it.
But, no, not an Army brat.
So, what do
your parents do?
Dad.
How is that
not a fair question?
Wes' mom died of cancer
and he never met his father.
I apologize.
It was
a really long time ago.
What kind of cancer?
Oh, my God.
I'm just trying to bond
with the boy, Meggy.
It's okay. Stomach.
Brutal.
Yeah.
♪ These are the days
in your life ♪
♪ When the price of time
is free ♪
♪ Like your daddy said,
the world is yours ♪
♪ So let it flow naturally ♪
♪ All the season's changes,
score them with a kiss ♪
♪ Yes, hey, girl ♪
♪ And welcome
all life's tricks ♪
♪ So eat the peach
out the pit ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ We were reckless,
but so precise ♪
You reached Nate Lahey.
Leave a message.
I knew
you weren't gonna pick up.
But I was calling to say
you're lucky I sent you away
because now you don't have
to deal with this mess anymore,
and I got a lot of it.
Like I need to tell you.
Um.
You can thank me
next time you see me.
♪ Oh ♪
You up?
Yeah.
I can't go back.
Even if she says
she'll forgive me,
she can't.
And maybe
I don't have to go back.
Maybe neither of us do.
Run away with me.
You're not happy in that house.
Nobody ever is.
But you...out of all of us
deserve to be.
Find some boring town.
Get normal jobs.
Make a family.
We'd have cute babies, no?
I'm only teasing.
You mind
if I turn on the TV?
Go ahead.
Everything
you know, life escalates.
But when you're young,
love, life is very complicated.
My wife's a hard sell,
Frank,
but her bull detector's
pretty good.
But I think I can get her back
to your side.
Yeah, you did your best.
Don't worry about it.
I do worry, though.
You're scared to get out.
No, that's stupid.
Then why do you keep screwing up
in here?
Because the only reason
I can think of
is that you can't forgive
yourself for what you did.
It was an accident, Frank.
My parents tell you that?
"No way he could've pulled that
lever himself."
He took the TV
out of my room...
yelled at me when I didn't
help out around the house,
as a dad should do.
And still, I thought it was
worth killing the guy over.
You were 13.
You didn't know
what you were doing.
I planned it for weeks.
Waited for
the perfect moment.
Looked forward to it.
And when it was over
and he was under that car,
screaming like an animal
in a trap,
my only thought was,
"You idiot, Frank.
You couldn't even kill him
right."
Now tell me
I should get out of here.
You should.
Then you're even more
of a sociopath than I am.
Sociopaths don't cry
over what they did, Frank.
Hey.
You have good in you. Okay?
Just like all of us.
And I'm here
to finally help you see that.
You have good in you.
Wake up.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Your dad?
How about Oregon?
They have these beach towns
with giant sand dunes and trees,
and it rains a lot, too,
so we won't feel bad
if we stay inside all the time.
And when it's nice,
we can go for hikes.
Can't imagine you on a hike.
That's the point.
We'd do things
that make us forget.
...but
the 4th Circuit's opinion found
Rule 17-A applies
to only those asserting a claim,
that people can sue
whoever they want,
so why did the Supreme Court
find in favor of the respondent
in Vaden v. Discover Bank?
Castillo.
What was the question?
Ms. Vaden failed
to disprove the presumption
that she received a binding
arbitration clause in the mail,
and therefore agreed
to the contract.
Now say it
with a Southern twang.
What are you talking about?
Your hillbilly came out when
you were bitching out Simon.
It did not.
It did.
It was pretty thick.
It happens in sex sometimes,
too, P.S.
So, I can never quite
put my finger on it.
It's like a cross between,
like,
Louisiana alligator wrestling
and Georgian peach picker.
We just broke up.
♪ Glass empty or full ♪
♪ Quench my thirsty tongue,
I'm drinking it ♪
Hey, come on.
Come on.
Come on in. Ooh.
Dance with me, Wes.
Ooh!
Ooh! Mm-mm-mm.
♪ Oceans old and new ♪
I'm just fooling around
with you.
♪ It's your decision ♪
♪ I'm already lost ♪
♪ Lost, lost ♪
Mm.
♪ Don't try to reason ♪
♪ By the time I inhale, exhale,
I'm back again ♪
What's wrong?
I thought you weren't
supposed to be drinking.
Oh.
There's a lot of things
I'm not supposed to be doing.
Hey!
This is my song!
♪ No, no, no, ah ♪
...lucky I sent you away
because now you don't have
to deal with this mess anymore,
and I got a lot of it.
Everything okay?
Like I need to tell you.
Family drama.
I know how that goes.
Oh.
Every woman in my office
would stone me
if they found
where I was right now.
You can't tell anyone
about us.
Oh, we are consenting
adults, Nate.
I'm serious.
Didn't turn out so well
last time I slept with a lawyer.
Oh, let's be clear --
I'm no Annalise Keating.
You heard that woman's calling
herself an alcoholic now, right?
That's how she's getting out
of her suspension.
It'll probably work, too.
That's how life rolls
for that woman.
The lady's got nine lives.
You got to see this.
What are you doing here?
I asked Oliver for a favor.
What kind of favor?
I hacked Simon's laptop.
You stole his computer?
Nope, that was me.
Michaela.
You're insane.
Who are you? Seriously.
You some sort of hillbilly
klepto all of a sudden?
Okay, you're all gonna be happy
I did this
when we get
his arbitration outline.
Couldn't find the outline.
Check again.
I found something better.
Oh, my God.
What the --
I knew it.
Here.
Listen.
So much for
that 100% Indian hair.
Go!
Go away.
Go away!
Just --
No.
I'm dis-- I'm disgusting!
I'm disgusting.
No. Here.
You shot me.
You wanted me dead.
I saw it in your eyes.
You hate me.
That's not true.
You protect me.
And I just want to do
the same for you.
Ohh.
How's -- How's Meggy?
Huh? Huh?
Is she good to you?
Very.
Oh.
Too good?
'Cause Nate's too good
to me.
I tried to be okay with it.
I really did.
No.
You need some water?
Parole cases
are time-consuming and tedious,
but my husband seems to like you
for some reason,
and I tend to think
that my husband has good taste.
He picked me, after all.
So, if I help you,
you can't lie to me again.
Understood?
Yeah.
Okay, you got yourself
a lawyer.
Now, we need to go over
the details
of what happened
to your father, all right?
I got the police report
right here.
I need to...
You okay?
You need to tell me
your side of the story.
Spare no details.
You pregnant or something?
Boy, right?
How'd you know?
Don't marry a lawyer.
Take him!
I just had a feeling it was him.
He's always so aggro
about you
and that he's never gotten
to be first chair,
and -- and with your job
on the line,
I just thought maybe I should
just look through his computer.
She stole his computer
for the arbitration outline.
We can't give it to
the university, though, right?
Otherwise they'll know
that Michaela stole it.
I can lie, say I found it
somewhere in the quad.
No one's ever gonna believe
that.
No one has to lie.
I'm not gonna show it to anyone.
You're just gonna let him
get away with this?
I didn't say that.
Go and prep for your exam.
What are you gonna do?
Make that weenball pay.
Honestly, you sure?
Yeah.
I mean, the D.A.'s office
could've put these up
or anyone who knows
what we've done,
but it wasn't any of them.
It was just some sad,
pathetic lost boy.
We're safe.
We're still safe.
Mind if I come in?
What's going on?
Stop!
What are you doing here?
I came to return this.
Somebody put that there,
planted it.
Don't lie to me!
Slander, defamation,
hate crime if you want
to bring race into it,
and it all leads to your
expulsion or worse -- prison!
What are you gonna do?
That's up to you.
Mr. Gibbins,
give us an example
of procedural versus
substantive unconscionability.
Uh...it was
unconscionable 'cause --
Wrong. Mr. Millstone?
I object, Your Honor.
I object to the question,
I object to your tone,
and I object
that we don't have
a cool pitcher of
sweet, home-brewed lemonade
to get us through
these proceedings.
Are you done?
Do you think
it's more of, like, a --
like a Beyoncé Southern
or a "Deliverance" Southern?
We have an exam tomorrow.
Come on,
just tell us
where your accent's from.
Is it your birth parents
or adopted parents?
It's none of your business.
Uh, we're boning.
I think it's my business.
The people who raised me
are trash.
I am who I am
not because of them
but in spite of them.
They are not worth my breath
or time,
especially when
we have an exam,
so let's never speak
of them again
or I'll cut you all
into little pieces.
Hey.
It's the arbitration outline.
We good now?
What the hell
just happened?
I don't know.
Does it matter?
I'm gonna go make copies.
What's wrong?
I need to break up
with Meggy.
Dinner with her dad
went that well?
I'm sick of lying to her.
Think I should stay
with her?
No. Do what you want.
We're all so messed up.
Annalise, especially.
But you...
I'll break up with Meggy.
Frank's gone.
Frank isn't gone.
Frank?
Hi.
I wanted you and your board
to have a chance
to review my lawsuit
before I file.
Retaliation by the university
for speaking my mind,
gender, race,
age discrimination,
a hostile work environment,
wanton breach of contract,
neglect.
Neglect?
The fliers.
It's been weeks, and your
investigation has found nothing.
Instead, you've devoted
university resources
to having me disbarred,
the legality of which is
questionable in its own right.
$50 million?
Go big or go home.
What do you want?
A truce.
Reverse my suspension.
I go back to teaching
the clinic.
You still don't have
your license --
That's being taken care of.
Because you went
to one AA meeting?
This is not up
for negotiation.
Either give me
what I want
or wake up tomorrow to a lawsuit
that will color the entirety
of your short run
as university president.
Fine, I'll make the calls
right now.
Thank you.
Annalise.
How are you? Really.
You can't get better alone.
Believe me, I've tried...
and failed enough times
to know.
Make those calls.
Stop, please.
At least let me warn Bonnie.
Bonnie lied.
Fine, then you tell her.
I just -- I can't.
Oh, I'm not in the mood
to see your needy faces.
Laurel needs to tell you
something.
She can't speak
for herself?
That's not the Laurel I know,
letting a man speak for her.
Please just listen.
All right.
Fine. What?
Say something.
It's about Frank.
What?
He's in Coalport
with Bonnie.
He called me
when I was with my dad,
and he told me
that you tried to kill him.
Is it true? Did you?
Is that true?
Can you tell us the truth
for once?
Laurel.
I'm here.
I know. I'm on it.
Please try to trust me.
Laurel's pregnant.
I had no idea.
Just stay here, okay?
I promise
I'll keep you updated.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Pick up.
Please pick up.
Please pick up, please pick up,
please pick up.
This is Connor.
You should text me.
Connor, pick up, please.
Please pick --
Hello?
Who's this?
Trishelle. Who's this?
Oliver. Were --
I'm looking for Connor Walsh.
Is that
whose phone this is?
I just found it
in my daughter's sofa cushions.
Darn thing was vibrating
my booty.
Mom!
Someone named Oliver
looking for Connor.
I don't know where he is,
Oliver.
Are you sure?
Yeah, what's wrong?
You haven't heard?
Heard what?
Annalise's house burned down.
The cops arrested her.
Laurel was inside,
but they found her.
What?
She's pregnant, Michaela.
Laurel.
Did she tell you?
Congratulations.
You've each been chosen for my
very first criminal-law clinic.
In here,
you're not just students
but actual practicing lawyers.
You finally get to be me.
Thursdays on ABC...
At least they chose
a good photo.
...brace yourself for a mystery
so killer...
This could destroy us all.
...not everyone is gonna
make it out alive.
No!
"How To Get Away With Murder."
Thursdays,00,00 Central
on ABC.
What are you
looking for?
It's right here.
Well, damn.
13 seasons
of fun.
Gimme, gimme, gimme.
13 seasons of drama.
This act
was a felony.
It was nice knowing you.
Shut up.
13 seasons of twisty turns...
It's bad.
You're falling
for me.
I slept with him.
...like only "Grey's"
can deliver.
Damn right.
"Grey's Anatomy."
Thursdays on ABC.