Do you have to do that right now?
Well, if you want to eat at 1pm, yes.
I'm going to do the crossword puzzle.
- Hey, mum.
- Alright, my teddy bear?
Did you sleep well?
So, you roll battered chicken in it.
I know, flour!
1 point for Odile.
Old-fashioned?
- Old.
- Decrepit?
- No, 8 letters.
- Outdated.
Ridiculous.
Obsolete.
You guys are rubbish!
I'm going for a swim.
Anyone coming?
No, thanks!
I really don't know why I ask.
It's going to rain!
So?
You're doing it on purpose.
- You like chicken!
- I'm eating.
I'll go on, "Unbearable".
Odile.
Ha! That fits!
Of course that would fit!
It's made just for you!
Life turned upside down
Lunch is ready!
Can you give that to me? Thanks.
Where's Mum?
Mum!
Mum, lunch!
Did you see her come back
from the beach?
No, she didn't come back.
Has no one seen her
since this morning?
People saw her go into the water,
but not come back out.
Is that not her dressing gown there?
Shit, we have to call for help!
Yes, a blond woman, thin,
in a black swim suit.
She was wearing
a flowery red swim cap.
And a red flowery swim cap.
Right, I'll tell the family.
Thanks.
They found her on Antifer beach.
She's fine, don't worry.
She's in the hospital in Le Havre.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Yes, OK.
No, I'll call you back.
Stéphane sends his love.
Hello.
Are you Mrs Ardant's daughters?
Yes.
She is tired but well.
She can leave now.
Did she tell you what happened?
The current was strong,
she got tired and disorientated.
That's weird, she knows
the coast by heart.
She has swum there for 40 years.
Maybe she was faint
or had hypoglycaemia.
That's it, she ate
almost nothing today.
- Doctor!
- Yes.
- Can you come?
You should get her checked out.
Can you make
an appointment with her GP?
- Thanks a lot.
- Good bye, doctor.
It's still strange.
The main thing is we found her.
How are you feeling, Mum?
I'm fine.
I'm a bit tired, that's all.
That's normal.
What an adventure!
- Were you scared?
- Well, yes!
Really!
My hair must look awful.
No, you look fine.
You're beautiful.
Let's go home then.
Let's go!
I can't stand hospitals.
And you didn't know where you were?
I wonder if my name
has affected my life.
Sorry?
I was wondering whether
my name has affected my life,
my person, my personality.
Claire,
from "clear",
like something transparent,
something not seen or looked at.
Since I was little, I've felt clear.
In fact, when my husband
asked me to marry him,
I took time to believe it.
When he left me,
I found it all rather expected.
I'm the only one like that
in my family.
Perhaps it's because
I'm the middle child.
What time shall we meet this evening?
I can't this evening,
my in laws are coming for dinner.
I just found out, I'm sorry.
But if you want, I'll try
to get free tomorrow.
- OK.
- Alright?
Bye.
- Hello?
- Yeah, it's me.
Mum just wrote a cheque
of 30,000 euros to Mélenchon.
30,000 euros!
Yes, to Mélenchon.
To the left front,
can you believe it?
No, the cheque bounced.
You know that
she doesn't have 30,000 euros.
I called her,
but god knows what she's doing,
her telephone just keeps ringing.
I didn't write this.
Mum, it's your signature.
Perhaps it's my signature,
but I didn't write it!
Don't you think I would remember?
So who did it then?
Can I have some water?
You three accusing me like this
is making me angry.
Can you get a glass, please, Claire?
We're not accusing you,
but if you didn't write it, who did?
- Where's your cheque book?
- I don't know.
In any case,
it couldn't have been me!
I hate politics
and I don't even know the guy.
- Mélenchon?
- No, I don't want melons.
Mélenchon! He's a revolutionary.
He's on the TV,
brown hair and angry. He wants
to send everyone to gulags.
He's different.
You like him like every other idiot.
Well, he's better than the BNP!
- Because I like the BNP!
- I do wonder.
Go and fight elsewhere.
I can't do this anymore, I'm tired.
How did they contact you?
Did they come here or call?
Stop this now!
You're pissing me off!
Can't I do what I want with my money?
That's what you mean, say it!
Calm down.
Well, can you come
into the kitchen now, please?
Warden
Please ring
Hello, Mrs Perreira.
Please, excuse our interruption.
We were wondering if you're still
cleaning our mother's flat.
Oh no!
She doesn't want me over anymore.
Really? Since when?
For about a month.
She wasn't paying me anymore either.
She's been muddled with her cheques.
- How much does she owe you?
- 430 euros.
If you don't mind me saying,
she's got a little problem.
Sorry?
She has said odd things
to others in the building.
What things?
Sexual things!
Two days ago, she spoke to
Mrs Lelievre about "broche"!
About what?
About fellatio.
About fellation.
She said she likes it and
that it was important to do
and that she has done it a lot.
Can you finish writing the cheque?
It was our mother who spoke to
Mrs Lelievre about fellation,
is that right?
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- Good bye.
- Thanks, Mrs Perreira.
Well I never!
I can't stand that woman,
she's always lurking on the stairs
and talking shit.
She can't have made
that fellation stuff up!
Can you imagine Mum talking
about fellation to that lady?
- She doesn't know what it is!
- Apparently she loves it.
That's enough, Claire.
Fellation aside, Mum has a problem.
She's getting old.
She's not getting old, Odile,
she's losing it.
What are you saying?
She's not the same
and it didn't start today.
It was already happening
this summer in Etretat.
I think she's finding it hard
to remember words
and she speaks to us
more often in German, right?
- No.
- Yes, she does!
- Perhaps it's depression.
- You don't get depression at 68!
Of course it happens.
I can ask about that.
She's better off seeing a specialist.
Who do you want to go see?
I don't know anybody.
Vincent's cousin
is a prof of neurology.
I can ask him to make
an appointment for us.
I've got to go.
- Do you want it?
- No.
What are you doing with the rubbish?
I don't know.
She has messed up
with money before.
This summer,
she gave me 500 euros and said:
"Here's 500 francs, darling,
but share it with your sister."
You gave the money back, I hope.
That's really dishonest, Guillaume!
What happens if your aunts find out?
Don't worry.
Don't ever do that again!
Is that understood?
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
Did you get my messages?
Yes, but it's been non stop
this morning. What's going on?
I need an appointment with
your neurologist cousin.
My mother has a problem.
Oh shit!
- What age is she?
- 68 years old.
Listen,
I think Francois is very good,
but the problem is,
he's not my cousin,
he's my wife's cousin.
Can't you just
recommend me to him?
That bothers me because of my wife.
Do you understand?
Give me his details
and I won't mention you.
You won't get an appointment
before 6 months,
he's hard-pressed.
You know what hospitals
are like these days.
I don't have his number.
I'll call you with it.
I'll find someone else,
it'll be easier.
If you want to.
Another coffee?
Yes, I'll take care of it.
OK, bye.
So, Julie's neurologist
is not going to work out.
Her boyfriend was supposed
to get us an appointment.
You can find someone else.
Yes, I will find someone else.
It's always the same
because I'm the one
who doesn't work.
Tell your sisters if it bothers you.
No, it doesn't bother me.
Now the kids have gone,
I've got time.
Call Cyril Ferney, his mother
had the same problem.
They ended up putting her in a home.
Father Kaplan has gone gaga too.
He wanted to celebrate
Christmas the 14th of July.
That's horrible.
It seems like there's
more and more of them.
We're just at the age where
our parents are getting ill.
It'll be our turn next.
Yeah, already!
Should we eat out tonight?
It'll be good for you.
I'm not in the mood for that.
I've got to solve this first.
Till tonight.
- It's still not over?
- They're doing tests.
What tests?
I have no idea.
Tests.
- How did it go?
- Very well.
I don't know what I'm doing here.
I just need her 5 mins more.
We're going to take some blood.
Alright?
I'm not deaf.
- So?
- That's it.
- What's it?
- Alzheimer's, Claire.
It's not chicken pox.
She said that it was 2040,
that she only has 2 girls
and that David Pujadas
hits on her during the news.
Which one of us did she forget?
It must have been me.
Oh, and by the way,
Dad is no longer dead.
Well, at least there's
some good news.
Did you understand
what was said, Mum?
You'll need to take
some medication.
Every day, it's very important.
But I don't need medication!
I'm fine.
I'm just a bit tired, that's all.
It's no big deal.
We'll see when you're my age.
We need to find someone
to help you at the house.
You can't stay alone.
No, I don't want anyone at mine.
She's annoying!
It won't be Mrs Perreira,
we'll find someone else.
I want to be left alone,
I don't want anyone at mine.
It'll be someone nice and discreet.
Alright.
But I don't want anyone coming.
I don't want anyone at my house.
Don't you want those?
Thanks.
Can you do an internet search
for home helpers, please?
Choose a few people,
but only those with references.
Thanks.
Hello?
Ah yes, yes, that's right.
What's your name?
Di...
Oh! Diallo, OK.
Do you have references?
References.
No, references.
Letters that show you've already
done this type of work.
Sorry, but this won't work,
I'm looking for someone
who speaks some French.
Hello?
She hung up on me.
That's nice!
Yes, yes. Hello?
Yes, that's right, yes.
Can you speak French? Good.
Reliable person needed
for elderly confused person.
References required.
Hello.
That's 40% off.
"Confused",
does that mean she's crazy?
I think it's Alzheimer's.
Does it pay well?
I don't know.
The family has found someone.
So I'll put this away.
It must be horrible,
looking after old folk.
Feeding them, changing
their nappies and all.
- Hello, there.
- Hello.
Well, good bye.
This isn't great.
Do you like it, Nina?
It's not bad.
Not her.
Not her either.
Is there only sardines?
There's 34 tins left,
we can't throw them away.
So, there's about 3
that look alright.
Odile's one,
my one and Claire's little one.
Did you check her out?
No, her reference left the country.
She's lying, she has no references.
Why say that?
She looks honest.
My one has brilliant references.
Your one wants to declare
3,000 euros a month.
That's twice what I earn!
You do the job.
Where's your CV?
They have to declare it all.
What if they dob on us?
Well, if they declare the salary,
then we pay double.
Perhaps you can pay a bit more,
but not Claire and I.
- I can't at all.
- Me neither!
The kids' studies aren't free!
So we can't declare it all.
Some of it, yes, but not all of it.
What about Dad's life insurance?
No, Mum wants to keep it for Etretat.
The roof needs redone
and the boiler is on its way out.
How much does yours want?
Well...
2,000 euros but it's negotiable.
She wants to declare as little as
possible to keep her benefits.
She's taking advantage!
For once it's helping us out.
What's her name?
Corinne Berthier.
50 years old,
she seems responsible.
We'll have to introduce her to mum.
If she doesn't like her...
It's nice of Guillaume to stay
the night here from time to time.
What bothers me is that mum
tried to kiss him on the mouth.
She was convinced that he was dad.
Are you worried
he'll lose his virginity?
After the whole fellation incident,
I'm just concerned.
I'd like to pass my driving test.
I'd like my own car and to go
where I like, when I like,
no need to depend on anyone.
Do you get me?
Yes, I do. It's called autonomy.
That's what I want
my psychiatrist to look at.
- Is it working out?
- I don't know, she never talks.
It must be part of the therapy.
Why don't you learn to drive?
It's hard enough for the youngsters
so imagine old me.
Stop putting yourself
down all the time!
You're not more stubborn
or more incapable than others.
You're uglier though!
But that never stopped
anyone from driving.
Do you want to come up?
Vincent's waiting.
I know what you think.
I'm stupid, I'm worth more
and he'll never leave his wife.
Well, I'm the right person to know
that a husband can leave his wife.
Right, I'm off.
Can you look at me walking
to see if I'm thinner?
I've totally stopped eating cake.
OK.
Vincent!
I can't stay,
my daughter's in hospital.
Shit! What's wrong?
Peritonitis.
They're operating now.
Do you want me to take you?
Yes, I'd like that.
Thanks.
"Little jug."
7 letters.
I've no idea.
Pitcher!
You know it's very good for the...
She's late.
I hope the negotiations
weren't too much.
Ah! The phone.
Tell me something about yourself.
What do you like to do?
You like walking,
going to the cinema, museums.
Right, mum?
Me too, I like walking.
If you like, we could go on
long walks after lunch.
A little cake?
So you told us you like
to cook a lot as well.
Ah yes, cooking is one
of my little indulgences.
Do you like to cook?
Mum doesn't cook a lot
but she likes good food.
You like that.
Well, we should get along,
I'm rather greedy with food!
Me too.
So for example,
what do you like to cook?
Fish, vegetable gratins, soups...
I can also make cakes,
quiches, pancakes.
Pancakes?
Yes.
Would you like me to make you some?
You can tell me if they're good.
Yes, OK.
- Where's the kitchen?
- Over there, on the left.
What do you think?
She won't win a beauty contest.
She seems nice though, right?
Yes, she's OK.
She arrives early,
she takes care of my mum all day
and she leaves when she's asleep.
I think my mum likes her.
It's a real relief for us.
She's just a little
authoritarian, that's all.
Let's stop there.
It's your turn, mum.
I know!
- Scrabble!
- Oh no!
There you go.
- Isn't that good?
- Bravo, Nina!
So tell me, darling,
how many points is that?
So, that's 12 plus 6 plus 7,
plus a triple word score,
plus 50 for the Scrabble.
- That's 147 points.
- There, you got 147.
That's not my last word!
You're leading.
This isn't happening!
Mum, what are you looking for?
Are you looking for something?
Me?
Isn't that my cheque book?
Yes.
I'm taking care of your bills.
You know, the water,
electricity, phone.
I can do it myself, I'm not crazy!
I know, mum, but as sometimes
you mess up the numbers,
we said I would write your cheques.
What are you talking about?
Are you going crazy?
- Shit!
- Don't get angry.
If you like, I'll fill in the cheque
and you can sign it.
OK.
I'm not crazy.
This is the cheque for EDF,
and you've only got to sign it.
Just here, mum.
I know.
Can I have it?
Mum! Stop!
Stop, mum! Stop!
Nina, Nina.
Sorry.
So, show me.
I don't know what I did,
but it's certain, I annoy her.
It's just because
you're there more often.
I irritate her as well.
She's only happy seeing Corinne.
They chat, they do stuff.
Sometimes I feel I'm bothering them.
Luckily we found her,
can you imagine if we hadn't?
She's great.
Just a little authoritarian.
"Can you go and get some bread?",
"Go hoover the living room."
She asked you to hoover?
She didn't ask you?
No.
That's strange.
It's her job to clean.
Don't give in like that!
I know,
but as she's also said stuff...
Said what?
Like where she worked before
there was a cleaning lady.
Perhaps they had a cleaning lady,
but for 1,800 euros a month,
she can lift a finger!
I dare her to ask me to hoover!
Well, it only happened
once or twice.
It's not worth discussing.
Since she arrived,
I've got my life back.
And I can sleep again.
So I walked, I walked...
Yes, mum, you walked in the street.
But you must go back to bed.
Yes, you've walked a lot,
but now you must sleep.
Just listen to me!
Yes, we're listening, mum.
Tell us then, you walked...
In dog shit!
There you go.
What happened?
Mum was found in the street
in pyjamas at 2am.
She didn't know where she was.
A homeless man
took her to the police.
- Hi, Stéphane.
- Are you OK?
Then she remembered her name,
the cops called Mrs Perreira
who gave her Julie's number.
Tomorrow everyone will be gossiping!
Who broke the lock?
It must have been Mum.
Corinne locks it.
It smells of shit.
Yeah, can you deal with the door?
To make things worse,
she trod in shit.
There's something shinny inside,
she must have put a knife in.
Can you get me a plucker
from the bathroom, please?
- Not now?
- Yes, I can get it out!
No, you can call
a locksmith tomorrow.
I'll do it, seeing as you won't.
That's enough!
I woke up at 2am to help,
you could at least be nice.
Well, that was a first for you.
Oh, I see!
Sort things out by yourself then.
Go home.
Me and Claire can stay.
No, he aggravates me.
He's like all men.
The second things aren't about him...
How did it go at school?
Very well, mum. Don't worry.
Good night.
Wait, we haven't said prayer.
Prayer now at 3am!
Quickly then,
because we've got school tomorrow.
Our father who are in heaven...
Really?
Whisky or vodka?
- Whisky!
- Vodka!
They've taken a hell
of a whack already!
I wonder whether Corinne
has a wee dram sometimes.
Do you think so?
Maybe mum's drinking them.
Can you imagine?
We reckon she's got Alzheimer's
but maybe she's just tipsy.
Whisky?
Isn't it bad to mix liquors?
If it were, it would be well known.
Well then!
To us!
To life! To love!
To the end of my relationship
with Vincent.
Don't pretend to be disappointed.
We're not disappointed,
we're surprised.
Well, don't act surprised.
It was always going to happen.
And how's it going?
Fab! It's the first day...
- Yeah.
- "The first day"?
Of the rest of my life.
That's the way.
My Alzheimer's is starting.
We're laughing,
but apparently it's hereditary.
Apparently.
We're heading straight there,
all of us!
The only thing I want
is to be ill first.
I don't want to hand you
over crutches.
You'd tell me right, if I...
Like we'd hold back!
Well, seeing as
you're talking about it,
the other day in your sleep,
you talked a lot about sodomy.
- You like it a lot.
- You do it a lot.
- It's important to do.
- You've always done a lot of it.
How surprising, I hate that.
Really?
That's not what Stéphane told us.
I'm telling you, I'm not surprised.
Every time I leave
and I lock the key in the door,
I wonder what I'll come back to
in the morning.
That's why we were wondering
if you could stay
for nights as well.
No, no.
I've got a life too, my husband...
It would just be 2 nights.
We can do the rest.
No, it's not possible.
It's already difficult
and hard work for me.
You know, doing the shopping,
the cleaning and taking care of her,
it's all very tiring.
You'll have to find
someone else for nights.
Corinne!
Hello, Nina.
What was the young one called
that didn't have any references?
Aicha.
80 euros.
70.
No, 80.
What about 75?
Listen, the price is
100 euros a night.
80 euros is good.
Right.
Yes, but as you won't declare it,
you won't pay any tax.
Neither will you.
Yes, but if we get caught,
we'll have problems and not you.
I understand.
It doesn't matter.
Right, it's fine for 80 euros
but you arrive at 7.45 pm
and you leave at 8.15 am.
Except for Monday and Thursday,
when I can't get there before 9pm.
And we agree,
I'm not working weekends.
On the weekends,
we'll rotate between us.
But you start on Sunday night.
No problem.
So, 80 times 5, that's?
5,347.
You've made a mistake.
OK.
80 times 5, that's 400 a week.
So for a month that's 1,600,
plus Corinne's 1,800 euros,
plus 450 euros of tax, equals...
I wonder how poor people do it.
They keep the sick at their house,
like a long time ago.
5 people to look after mum,
it's becoming an industry.
Hello! It's Odile!
It's me!
It's Corinne!
Sorry, I'm a bit late.
Bye, Nina.
Have a good weekend, till Monday.
Sorry.
- Did it go well?
- Very well.
What about Aicha?
Well, we'll manage with her.
Oh, and the nails have
nothing to do with me.
- Have a good weekend.
- You too.
Good evening, mum.
Good evening.
Look at that.
That's soft!
I sell these in my shop.
Do you want to try it on?
Yes.
It suits you.
It's yours, if you want it.
Thanks, darling.
Thanks a lot.
Well, it's nothing,
I'm happy to give it to you.
You're nice.
You were always the nicest
and the most gentle.
My little girl.
I love you so much.
No, don't be sad.
My little darling, don't be sad.
I'm not sad.
My sweetness.
- Oh, mum.
- Yes, darling, I'm here.
I think it's the first time that
mum told me she loved me.
Odile says she doesn't know
who she's talking to anymore.
I think she's just jealous.
I'm sure that my mother was
really speaking to me yesterday.
I'm the one she loved.
We'll stop there.
It's Odile!
Hello, Corinne. All OK?
Yes, yes, all's fine.
Do you have 5 minutes?
I'd like to speak with you.
Yes.
I've got a problem with Aicha.
- What's going on?
- She doesn't speak nicely to me.
There's hardly ever a nice hello.
She doesn't tidy.
When I arrive in the morning, I have
to clear away her breakfast.
She doesn't rinse the bath,
your mum's bed is never made,
and at night she's always late.
She says I'm not her boss,
but I'm not her housewife!
Is it an organisation problem?
Perhaps you can decide
together who does what
and each of you can try
to respect that.
Well, that's not all.
I suppose she didn't tell you
that she brings her boyfriend.
What should we do now?
We go up and say we've come
to get something, like a file.
Why don't we speak to her
instead of catching her out?
We will speak to her, don't worry!
Good evening.
I think she understood.
With what you said,
she won't stay long.
She brings a guy over to mum's
and I'm the mean one?
You are completely looney!
We're nice to have not fired her.
We didn't fire her
because we need her!
She gave me a bad feeling
from the start.
Why?
Because she's called Aicha?
Yeah, right, call me a racist!
Stop it, you're too much!
We could let Aicha breathe for 2 days
and get someone else?
So we're paying her now to breathe?
Stop making it all about money!
But of course, I'm racist,
I'm tight, everyone knows!
I'm sure money is not
a problem for you.
What are you trying to say?
When you go twice a week to
a shrink, you've got the money.
I go once, not twice,
and it's none of your business.
You can talk, you've never worked.
Just because you play
the saleswoman...
That's enough!
Is this the best time to fight?
Isn't it hard enough right now?
You're pissing me off
with your good wife crap!
Don't you want a lift home?
These t-shirts are very good,
very comfortable to wear.
- There you go.
- Here.
That's perfect.
- Thanks. See you soon.
- Thanks.
Hello.
Are you free for lunch?
I saw an Italian on this street.
Right, I'm sorry about what I said.
You've got to stop bullying everyone.
We're lucky there's 3 of us
and mum has some money.
- Can you imagine other people?
- OK!
I said I was sorry.
Corinne and Aicha aren't  perfect,
but it works.
Enjoy it.
It'll last for as long as it must.
That's very pretty.
- How much is it?
- 85 euros.
I'll take it.
Do you want the matching bag?
It's Corinne!
Nina!
Aicha!
Oh well, it didn't last long.
What?
The non-perfect couple that works!
So?
I spoke to her, she said she just
went out to do some shopping.
Well, of course.
We go food shopping at 2 am too.
She wants us to pay her
holiday leave as well.
Does she think we're stupid?
- No, just you.
- What?
She said you were a stupid racist
and if we don't pay, she'll send
her boyfriend over to hurt you.
Did she say that?
Mum!
How do you feel?
I want to go home.
I'll call Corinne to tell her
to take her holidays
and she can come back at the end
of August, when mum will be back.
Let's not keep lying to ourselves.
Mum can't go back to her flat.
What are you saying?
Well, surely you can see
we can't manage.
Aicha was the straw.
Even Corinne is hard work,
always complaining.
Managing 2 people is a nightmare.
That's not counting a 3rd person
for weekends.
Well, having said that...
What do you suggest then?
She'll need to go into
a special care home.
A place for people like her.
Are you talking about
the ones in wheel chairs
who spend their days
whining and dribbling?
Can you see mum with those people?
She's sick, Odile.
She doesn't even see
what's happening anymore.
She's lucid enough to realise that
we're leaving her in an asylum.
The flat is all she remembers now.
If we take that away...
Odile,
it's difficult enough as it is,
try not to make it more complicated.
- Have you decided?
- Not yet.
- I'll give you more time.
- Sorry.
So obviously you're OK with this.
I would like there to be another
solution, but I don't see one.
So that's it.
So you've got together on this one.
With everything mum has done for us,
the exemplary way
she brought us up,
and this is how you thank her?
By putting her in a hospice?
She's not going to a hospice!
Why would you say that?
- We'll find a nice place.
- Does one exist?
Claire, have you heard
what they say on TV?
They stuff people with tranquilisers
and they tie them to beds.
I'm ashamed of you.
If dad could hear or see you,
he would turn in his grave.
I'll take care of her.
- What are you going to do?
- Take her to mine.
You know why she's doing this?
To make us feel guilty!
She's always acted like this,
the perfect girl who does
everything perfectly.
I'm sorry, but she's got
an issue with mum.
It's not normal to put
herself out this much.
It must be a childhood thing
that she can't get over.
Maybe it's because
her kids have gone.
She doesn't speak about it, but...
You know what?
She should get a psychiatrist.
And go at least 3 times a week!
God, what will the menopause be like?
I know one person who'll be happy
when he gets the good news.
Do you understand
what you're asking me?
But you won't see her a lot.
When you get back, she'll be asleep.
You'll only see her the weekend.
We'll never be alone again.
She doesn't bother anyone.
You know, she barely speaks anymore.
When the kids left the house,
I was hoping for something else.
Like what? What did you want?
Well, not to be a care home.
I love your mum,
but that's not really the point.
In any case,
it won't be until September.
In a week she'll be out
and we'll go to Etretat.
I'm sorry, Odile,
but I'm not OK with this.
What are you doing?
I'm going to mum's,
seeing as you don't want her.
Let go of me!
I would have looked
after your parents.
I would never ask.
They won't dry, it's too humid.
She's finished them all.
Don't throw them out,
we can reuse them.
When are we going to go swimming?
You can't go swimming mum,
you've got a plaster cast.
She's said that 100 times.
When are we going to go swimming?
Why can't we take her?
With her plaster cast?
Don't be stupid.
She really wants to, right, my Nina?
Well, I want to jump off
a cliff to fly away.
We don't always get what we want.
You could try,
with that wind outside.
What if we protected
the plaster cast,
and were careful?
What if water gets in?
Do we take it off and dry it?
When are we going swimming?
Well, rolling up kitchen roll
is a lot less risky.
When you look after
your grandmother like us...
I'll take care of her, don't worry.
Where's the bin bags?
- No, I can't do this.
- Hold on, Nina!
Go in, come on.
Come and sit down.
Do you want to drink something?
Are you OK, mum?
Are you tired?
I'm fine.
Are you happy to be here?
I want to go home.
You're home, mum.
This is your flat, can't you see?
I want to go home.
You were
the best daughter possible, Odile.
You did all that you could.
I know.
You were the best out of us.
Even if you're the most annoying.
I know.
We'll find her a great care home.
A place to put her furniture,
her valuables and her memories.
- We'll go and see her a lot.
- OK.
You've got to stop crying
otherwise we'll all start.
Wisteria Retirement Home
Put your leg to the side
and lift your arm.
Pinch me, I'm dreaming!
Hello, M'am.
This is unreal,
there must be a catch.
The beautiful star
1,300 euros per month?
Oh no, Madam, per week.
That's not including medical charges
and the hairdressing
and other services.
Of course.
Yes?
Excuse me, Mr Farina
has come for his father's file.
Ah, yes.
- Excuse me.
- Please go ahead.
So we found the catch.
You can cut her hair.
I'll take care of her feet.
Without all that, it still costs
5,000 euros a month!
We'll say we're interested
and we'll discuss the price later.
Do you want to think about it?
There's no need, we're interested.
I'll put you
on the waiting list then.
Are there no openings?
No, we're full. Spots open up
when someone dies.
And how long can that be?
From a few weeks to a few months.
How much will we get
without the flat rent?
1,052 euros.
It's a rent deal from 48.
I can help out,
I've asked to do more shifts.
I can work on Saturdays.
We've got to find a long term
solution. Mum is young.
It's nice of you.
The only solution I can see
is to sell Etretat.
Oh no!
No, not Etretat!
Etretat is our whole life,
our childhood.
Mum will be done with.
Etretat will be over.
Everything will be over.
Look at that,
they're taking air and chatting.
They have no desire to die,
I'm telling you!
Some cyanide in their food
and we're sorted.
Stop it, I don't want to laugh.
Odile is upset to sell Etretat.
She's attached to the past.
When Julie has decided something,
she goes straight ahead.
Curiously, for me,
I don't feel a thing.
In any case, not as much
as I would think.
I even think
that it could help me turn a page,
to leave the past behind.
- Grow.
- We'll stop there.
Did you hear what I said?
Wasn't it important?
I've come here for a year
and told you everything
and you just sit there
and look at me.
When I pay you,
would it hurt a little to say thanks?
Driving School
And how are things?
I've had easier periods in my life.
Odile is very unhappy, you know.
But she's stubborn as a mule.
Proud as a peacock.
But she's nice deep down.
You know her as well as us.
Yes.
Have you managed to chat a bit?
Yes, yes, things are calming down.
It's been good for us to be apart.
I think she needs to really go
the extra mile with your mum.
We're going through a rough patch,
but it'll get better.
Did you know we found a care home?
Yes, I know.
I know you're selling Etretat too.
That's why I wanted to see you.
Would you be OK
if I bought the house?
That way it'll stay in the family,
you can still go there,
it'll still be your home.
Is Odile aware of this?
I wanted to speak to you first.
We're OK with that.
In any case, I'm OK with that.
You just need to know something.
It's going to cost you!
There you go, mum.
If you're too hot,
take off the top cover.
OK?
Did you look under the bed?
Last night, I was attacked by foxes.
Really? By foxes?
They made a din
like you wouldn't imagine.
They ran all over the room,
they even knocked over the lamp.
Listen, I can't see anything.
They must have left.
I was attacked by a fox
when I was little.
At your grandmother's
in Salzburg, right?
Look.
So, you, who are you?
Well,
I'm Odile, mum.
I'm your little girl.
Oh, right.
So you're not Mrs Perreira?
Really, do you think I even have a
vague look of Mrs Perreira about me?
Well, now you've said it...
I'm off, someone's here.
Good evening.
Can I come in?
Yes, of course, come in.
I had Juliette on the phone.
She did well in her exams.
Yes, I think she was happy.
No, go ahead.
Yanis said he was coming home
on the 10th.
Will you be free?
The 10th? Yes, yes.
Good.
I asked your sisters
if I could buy Etretat.
I thought
that you could perhaps
come back to the house
with your mum, until she moves.
I think it's going to be
a big shock to leave here,
I think we should stay here
till the end.
Yes, OK.
But thank you!
Hello?
Yes?
- Good bye.
- Till Thursday.
- Till Thursday, yes.
Yes, hello?
That's it, there's a free spot.
It's better this way, you know.
Don't take the cashmere.
They said only machine washable
and preferably non-iron clothes.
She can't just wear acrylic things.
Yeah, you're right.
We'll wash
her nice clothes ourselves.
When you were small,
I could watch you from here
going to school.
Before going round the corner,
you would always wave.
You should have told me of the risk.
When women have sex with men,
they can get pregnant, Vincent.
You haven't just learned
that today, I hope.
When men don't want that hassle,
they wear a condom.
I'm as guilty as you,
that's not what I'm saying.
What are you saying then?
Sophie is pregnant.
She'll give birth in 3 months.
But, if you need me to...
To get an abortion?
No, I don't need you.
Well, it's your choice.
Are you sure
you don't want to keep it?
Alone, with my work?
You could get a nanny,
with references,
and partially declare the money.
A Corinne for babies.
Seriously, can you imagine me
with a baby?
Good bye and good day.
So?
I heard its heartbeat.
Did he say when it was for?
The 15th of July!
Your tights are very flashy.
I like them, don't you?
Yes, but they're very flashy.
I'm hot!
Oh!
You're expecting a baby?
Well, yes, mum.
I told you, it's a little girl.
I've got 3 little girls too.
Oh yeah?
What are they called?
I don't know that.
In any case, they're very pretty.
Everyone compliments me.
Are they well behaved?
The two small ones, yes.
The oldest one has some character!
I always have to tell her off.
I know her,
she's as stubborn as a mule.
She looks like Mrs Perreira,
doesn't she?
Yeah. Are you sure it's Saturday?
OK, then. No problem.
I did it!
What?
My mum passed her driving test.
Is it heavy? Should I carry it?
No, of course not.
You're crazy, cherries?
She doesn't like them.
Hello.
There's a problem with your mum.
Have you looked in all the rooms?
Yes, we searched
all the buildings and annexes.
This has never happened before,
I don't understand.
Where did you see her last?
She bathed at 8 am, she had
breakfast with the orange group,
then she painted.
This never happens.
Are you sure she went to paint?
Yes, but she disappeared
before returning.
It was at lunch
that we realised she had gone.
This never happens!
Yes, Madam, it's happening now!
Did she have visitors?
Her grandson, Guillaume Pelletier.
Hello?
Yeah, she's here next to me.
Very well.
We took the train then a coach.
We've just arrived at Etretat.
Swimming, mum.
Remember, it's her birthday.
No, don't hand me over to Odile.
Hello?
I'm off, Odile.
It's cutting out.
Shit! They're pissed!
You'll have to stand up for me.
You're not keeping
the right distance from that car.
You should stay two car lengths away.
Look twice before overtaking, Odile.
The blind spot. Sorry,
but I can't let that one pass.
One more comment, and you're out.
Have we gone past the toll?
- Where is she?
- I don' t know.
I went quickly to buy water.
I asked her to wait.
When I came back, she had gone.
I think she's in the water!
What the hell, Guillaume!
Are you happy, little moron?
Don't touch my son!
It's my job to shout at him!
Shout then!
Why are you waiting?
I'm sorry.
Look!
Mum!
Nina!
She's crazy, she's totally crazy.
Ah! This one's for you, mum.
The capital of Germany?
That would be nice
but with some milk.
We're here!
Hello!
Look who's here, mum!
- Hello, mum.
- Hello.
Hello.
How's it going?
This is my little girl.
She was born the same day as you.
Put her in her arms.
- Really?
- Yes, we're here.
Wait, wait.
Here, mum.
You're so pretty!
You understand.
Subtitles: Eclair Group