Richelieu: Glory and Blood
Madame!
Give back the handkerchief, sir.
I'll do no such thing.
If you are an honorable man,
give me that handkerchief.
My honor is at the point
of my sword, sir.
Removing your sword
in front of Cardinal
de Richelieu's palace is bold!
Don't you know
duels are punished by death?
Where are you from?
I cannot reply to your mockery.
The cardinal waits for me.
But I will satisfy you
and give the disputed object
to the only person
with any claim to it.
Forgive my boldness, Madame.
It seems I'm forbidden to keep this.
I'm devastated.
To whom do I owe the honor?
Henri d'Effiat, Marquis of Cinq-Mars.
At your service, Madame.
I'll remember that.
And I will not forget you.
To the Louvre!
Tell me, friend,
the name of that lady?
Marie de Gonzague, sir.
Duchess of Nevers.
What do I hear, Henri?
You took out your sword?
Don't you know that dueling
is now a crime against the king?
Forgive me, your Eminence.
A lady's honor was at stake.
"A lady's honor,"
especially this duchess's,
is not worth losing your life.
I don't want nobles
killing each other over trifles.
My edicts apply to everyone.
More illustrious names than yours
have paid dearly for such acts.
I won't forget, your Eminence.
Here is a letter from my mother.
I don't need to read it.
I can refuse nothing
to the son of my old friend,
the late Marshal d'Effiat.
Your father was
of great service to the state.
I expect you
to follow the same path.
That is all I desire, your Eminence.
Fargeau, write a note
recommending Mr. de Cinq-Mars
to Mr. de Tréville.
You'll be suited
to the musketeers.
I know you're brave
and a fine swordsman.
Go prove yourself.
You know my affection for you.
Don't disappoint me!
I'm at your service,
your Eminence.
That young man will turn heads.
I'm counting on it.
Why the musketeers instead of
your own guards?
I have my reasons.
Let's get back to business.
Despite the measures
we have taken,
the queen continues to inform
her brother, King of Spain,
of all the court's goings-on.
I also suspect her
of plotting with Gaston d'Orléans
and trying to harm me personally.
The queen will be furious,
I couldn't convince the cardinal.
How much longer will she be
locked up in the Louvre?
He won't forgive her letters
to Madrid.
Who denounced her?
Does the cardinal have a spy?
He wouldn't dare.
Open your eyes.
His Eminence will do anything
to protect his interests.
Damned cardinal!
I'll be avenged.
He defies me,
but one day he'll beg me for mercy.
Then I will crush him.
Your words are unwise.
Mr. de Thou is right, your Majesty.
Your words may be repeated.
I know it all too well.
I'm surrounded by spies
trying to ruin me.
They must be uncovered.
Whoever they are!
Let them go tell this false Christian
that his guile makes me sick.
I'm the daughter and sister
of kings, and queen of France!
He will pay for forgetting it.
Well, Monsieur de Cinq-Mars...
Show what you can do.
Monsieur de Chambord.
He won't last 2 minutes.
Touché, Monsieur!
Monsieur de Beaumont!
Our honor is at stake.
Who is this young officer
fighting off an army?
The Cardinal's protégé.
Marquis of Cinq-Mars.
Touché!
You impressed
Mademoiselle de Hautefort,
the King's mistress.
Congratulations, sir.
With your sword,
the King is very well-guarded.
With your beauty, Madame,
his Majesty is very well-loved.
I hope to have the pleasure
of seeing you again.
I share your hope, Madame.
To the King, musketeers.
I'll see you later, Mademoiselle.
Come, your Eminence.
I'm late, I know.
Our prey escaped,
but I didn't want to give up.
Your Majesty.
3 hours of hunting for nothing.
That beast was clever.
Maybe it knew we were coming.
I must speak to you
before the council.
New trouble has broken out
in Berry, Champagne, and Poitou.
The cities are rebelling
against our intendants,
the peasants are stirred up.
In Paris, attempts on my life
are rumored.
This isn't new. You are easy to hate.
I only govern,
but France is not an easy child.
It rebels against each edict
and rejects reform.
By God! That isn't new either.
Govern, my dear minister.
You have my trust.
Your enemies are my enemies.
Protect yourself as needed.
Haven't I given you guards?
Yes, Sire.
Not to mention the spies
you have all over
France and Navarre.
Take off this vest, La Chesnaie!
It's too tight.
Don't give me these garish colors.
You know I like moderation.
I'm worried by the loss
of Mr. de Comons,
my dresser.
He was so wise.
Who at the court
can take on this duty?
The Marquis de Cinq-Mars, Sire.
Henri d'Effiat has taste and wit.
Is he related to
the Marshal d'Effiat
who served us so well?
He's his son, your Majesty.
Ready to serve you like his father.
Really?
Well, let's see!
As always,
I trust your good feelings for me.
Places, gentlemen. The King arrives.
Henri! Henri, come.
Let me introduce you to his Majesty.
Let me introduce you to
the young man I spoke of.
Henri d'Effiat, Marquis de Cinq-Mars.
Stand up, Monsieur.
Glad to meet the son
of our friend the Marshal.
His memory is dear.
We owe him a great deal.
I owe him just as much.
And I'll serve you as eagerly,
if you'll give me the chance.
We'll give it to you. Certainly.
I like your idea, your Eminence.
This young marquis speaks
openly and honestly.
Congratulations, your Majesty.
Your decisions at the council
were very wise.
Isn't he a bit young
for this position?
On the contrary, Sire.
You need new blood.
He's a proud horseman
with whom I'll enjoy hunting.
One more thing, Sire,
if you'll allow.
Well?
I'm worried about
your brother's intentions.
My spies tell me he's in Paris
although we banned him from the city.
You won't deny that Gaston d'Orléans
plots against us?
My brother is a scatterbrain
who wants the throne.
But who cares,
since your spies watch him?
There's way to crush
his claim to the throne.
And what is that?
Give an heir to France.
It's not for lack of trying.
Can I help it if the queen
is not fertile soil?
And I've lost interest in trying.
Your Highness!
You're late.
Well! Will the cardinal
see his mistress tonight?
She told me so.
Marion De Lorme
will receive no one else.
His Eminence will use a carriage
with no crest or escort.
His discretion will be his ruin.
The cardinal is yours.
If your assassins are successful,
your fortune is made.
He's a dead man, your Highness.
Well, Madame!
What news?
Good news.
The storm washed out the road.
The king will spend
the night at the Louvre.
His Majesty will share
the queen's bed.
Thank heaven and pray
that we'll soon have an heir.
What else?
The king was in a very good mood
about his new dresser.
A certain Marquis de Cinq-Mars
that no one's heard of.
You'll hear of him soon.
Did you see the Spanish ambassador
with the queen recently?
The Marquis de Mirabel came
to see her yesterday at nightfall.
I brought him to her study.
They stayed there
for almost an hour.
I checked this morning.
The letters that his Majesty had
written to his brother weren't there.
Thank you for your precious aid.
Go back to the Louvre
and I'll take care of your interests
as you take care of mine.
- All is ready, your Eminence.
- Perfect.
Take them alive.
So they tell us
everything they know.
Don't kill him! No!
I wanted him alive!
I want prisoners!
No! Don't kill him!
Don't kill him!
Viva Espana!
The Devil take it!
I wanted them alive!
I needed them to name
Gaston d'Orléans
and his co-conspirators.
How can I prove his betrayal
to the king?
How can I know if the queen
was part of this plot?
Where can they be?
We should've already heard.
Calm down, your Highness.
You'll make me doubt you.
Do you know what I found out?
The king is sleeping
with the queen tonight.
Who cares!
He won't impregnate her
after 22 years of childlessness.
Flee, it failed.
- Impossible.
- The cardinal was warned.
His men were everywhere.
I'm ruined.
- Do they have prisoners?
- No.
None survived.
Goodbye, Marie. Goodbye.
I'm leaving for Lorraine.
Stay!
You're safe
with the queen's confessor.
We must kill the cardinal.
- How? He's the devil.
- We can't give up.
Stay! The queen will help us.
I must speak to his Eminence.
What's going on?
Is it true?
His Majesty wants me to dress him?
It's true, congratulations.
Why congratulations?
I was born to serve with my sword.
Do you know how many soldiers,
counts, and barons would be honored
by this position?
With all due respect,
I have no interest
in the king's trousers.
I want to be useful.
And I want you to obey.
The king wants it,
and that's enough.
Haven't I always helped you, my boy?
Didn't I get you a spot
in the military academy?
Haven't I, since your father's death,
advised your mother
on raising you?
Of course.
Then trust me,
and be glad to see
the most powerful
man in the kingdom every day.
He makes and breaks
men's destinies.
If he likes you,
your fortune is made.
I'm offering you more than a career.
A destiny.
You'll serve me well near the king.
How so?
We're at war, Henri.
Spanish forces threaten
our borders, in Flanders
and in the south, in Roussillon.
Will we let the king of Spain
invade the kingdom,
on the pretext that his sister,
queen of France, and the Pope in Rome
consider Philip IV of Spain
more Catholic than us?
- No. Of course not.
- Then we agree.
Now it happens that...
the king is smitten with
Mademoiselle de Hautefort.
Very pious like him,
she criticizes my alliances
with the protestant states
of Sweden and Holland.
Well,
I expect you
to get rid of
this harmful woman for me.
How? You think
I'm more powerful than I am.
You're wrong there, Henri.
You're clever and attractive.
That's what the king likes.
You don't think he'll wear this?
Why not?
The king only wears black,
or gray on New Year's Eve.
He'll give up this austerity.
He's not a protestant
as far as I know.
Oh, my Lord!
You speak of the king, sir.
Really?
Well, hello, Monsieur de Cinq-Mars.
Well! Where is my suit?
Here, Sire.
Are you joking, sir?
What's this gold, these frills?
Do you think I'm a marquis
trying to be fashionable?
I think
you're the greatest of monarchs,
the king of France,
who must impress.
You're judging me, Marquis?
I'm saying, Sire,
that the world will judge you
by your clothes.
You are France.
Your subjects expect
you to represent them
with the splendor
and magnificence they deserve.
They'll be proud
to see you in something
elegant and worthy
of the power you embody.
I forgive your insolence,
as youth is your excuse.
But it's not my nature
to be ostentatious.
"Don't judge a book by its cover,"
sir.
My power is not in my clothes.
Don't expect me to wear this outfit.
His Majesty the King.
Your Majesty,
France has never been
so brilliantly represented.
Light has arrived with you, Sire.
Well, Madame!
You say nothing?
There would be too much to say, Sire.
Congratulations, Henri.
François!
My friend.
What joy to see you again.
What is this masquerade?
You're the laughingstock
of the Court.
Will you pray in this outfit?
Have you forgotten
to whom you speak, Madame?
It befits the king of France
to appear in all the splendor
of his power.
I expect you to remember that.
Sire, this isn't like you.
This Marquis de Cinq-Mars
is making you ridiculous.
A man beholden to Richelieu!
Be quiet!
Not another word.
The Marquis de Cinq-Mars
has my full confidence.
Treat him with respect!
I don't recognize you, Sire.
You've always scorned
the vanity of the world.
Where's the man I love
who fears the Lord?
That man has long been
too indulgent with you.
He is annoyed with your manners
and asks you to change them.
Alas, your Majesty!
I cannot share
your favors
with that fop you're infatuated with.
That's enough!
Since you do not share
my affections, leave the Court.
Otherwise, you'll regret it.
Farewell!
And get married!
I'll give you 1,000 crowns.
Well, sir!
Your star is rising quickly.
Be careful or the sun will burn you.
There is no sun here but you.
Your sparkling eyes alone
endanger a heart that burns for you.
That is very chivalrous, sir.
And you are very convincing.
You showed it
by turning the king into a sovereign.
His Majesty the King!
Stay with me, Marquis.
Leave the women
and let's be friends.
First, I'll teach you
the customs of the Court.
No need, Sire.
The king determines the customs
and I'm honored by your friendship.
You have an answer for everything.
I like that.
I won't get bored with you.
Leave, ladies.
Leave!
If Mademoiselle de Hautefort
is out of favor,
we've lost a friend to our cause.
It's a victory for the cardinal.
Certainly, your Majesty.
But I have an idea.
If the king is friends
with this Marquis,
let's have him join our cause.
That will be difficult, your Majesty.
He is the cardinal's protégé,
and son of the Marshal d'Effiat.
Oh, yes!
That's true.
But I hear he's young
with charming manners.
He may be charmed by you.
Come on, Duchess!
The idea appeals to you.
Why not try it?
Your weapons are much more powerful
than those of Mr. de Richelieu.
Your Majesty,
Monsieur de Thou is here
with the Marquis de Cinq-Mars
whom he'd like you to meet.
Perfect timing.
Bring in the gentlemen,
Mademoiselle.
What a nice surprise!
Thank you for seeing us,
your Majesty.
I'd like to introduce my friend,
Marquis de Cinq-Mars,
who is in charge
of the king's wardrobe.
Here's the man all Paris
is talking about.
I'm charmed, Monsieur.
It's a huge privilege,
your Majesty.
I'm at your feet.
What do you think, Duchess?
He's the most handsome man.
Don't compliment him too much,
your Majesty.
He might get the wrong idea.
Mademoiselle de Hautefort
is disgraced?
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely, your Eminence.
The king has been charmed
by the Marquis
and wants him to follow him
everywhere.
That's better than I hoped, Chavigny.
Cinq-Mars is even better
than I thought.
It was a brilliant idea,
your Eminence.
As long as Mr. de Cinq-Mars is loyal.
What do you mean?
He was welcomed by Mr. de Thou,
the queen's devoted advisor.
They're childhood friends.
Where's the harm?
I also saw him courting
the Duchess de Nevers.
Henri is too smart
to be snared by her.
And at 30,
the ex-mistress of Gaston d'Orléans
is not a threat.
I'm not sure.
She's already shown
her boundless ambition.
I tell you she won't corrupt
Henri d'Effiat.
What's happening?
Did his Holiness Urban VIII
breathe his last?
Your Eminence, it's a miracle.
The queen is pregnant.
The queen is pregnant!
About time!
Let's pray she'll give
the king an heir.
The queen is pregnant!
Your Majesty.
Did your quarry escape?
A deadly dull hunt.
- Where is Mr. de Cinq-Mars?
- In Paris, Sire.
What? What's he doing there?
Doesn't he know he's in my service
and I must change after hunting?
I want to see him.
Go find him, right now!
Monsieur de Tréville!
I don't know why
I yielded to you, Monsieur.
Curiosity, I suppose.
"Curiosity," Madame?
Yes.
I admit you intrigue me.
I'd like to know
how you charmed the king.
In the same way
you've charmed me, Madame.
I loved you at 1st sight.
My heart beats only for you.
Please, sir.
Get up and be reasonable.
What do you hope for?
That you'll love me as I love you.
My God! Only that?
I'm moved, I admit. But...
Monsieur de Cinq-Mars!
What is it?
I have orders to bring you back.
What does he want now?
The king's orders aren't questioned.
Go!
Don't make his Majesty wait.
When will I see you again?
That wouldn't be wise.
I don't want to be wise. When?
Tonight. I'll be waiting.
That's an eternity.
Don't forget that I love you.
Well, Monsieur de Cinq-Mars!
Is this how you serve me?
Didn't I say
you should never leave me?
What do say you to that?
I thought you were hunting, Sire.
And that I should greet the queen.
She doesn't need your greetings.
You're mine.
I want you to stay at my side.
The truth, sir.
Whom were you seeing?
No!
Don't tell me.
It was a woman.
What woman could resist
this angelic face?
Don't compromise yourself
with one of those marquises
looking for a mate.
That's not my intention, Sire.
My ambition is to serve you,
rest assured.
Well!
How do I look?
Handsome as Apollo, Sire.
To Mr. de Richelieu,
who brought you to me.
who has let me serve you.
Come, now!
Don't speak of serving me,
I want us to be friends.
Open your heart to me.
I'll do the same.
My heart is yours, Sire.
Is it true that you sent
Miss de Hautefort away?
There's much gossip here.
Don't believe it.
You were just an excuse.
She had irritated me
by criticizing the cardinal.
She used our time praying
to be the voice of
the queen and the Pope.
It takes a low opinion of the king
to think the cardinal's policy
is not approved by me.
Good night, Henri.
I had a nice evening.
Good night, Sire.
Every moment with you is glorious.
I'm eager to see you tomorrow.
You've taken a great risk, Marquis.
Is it worth it?
If necessary, I would've sacrificed
my life to see you.
I don't have enough words
to express my love.
This is too much.
Your passion scares me.
You are clever and
the king loves you.
It would be mad
to compromise your position.
What does the king matter
if you love me?
Say the word
and I'll marry you, Madame.
My God! Then I would be
unreasonable.
Do you know the difference
in our positions?
You're a marquis.
But I'm a sovereign duchess.
The king will not consent.
The king will ignore it
because he loves me.
The king will have you killed
because he loves you.
Is there no way?
There's a way to reduce
the distance between us.
Really? Speak.
Do you remember the falconer
whom the king loved so much?
Well?
Didn't the king make him duke
and Lord Chancellor?
You could reach such heights.
Then you could claim my hand.
You've brought me back to life,
Madame.
What is this play with 3 duels,
Mr. Corneille?
This is scandalous.
That's not my intention.
But The Cid required them.
I require you to rewrite it.
I didn't give you 1,500 pounds
to copy a Spanish play.
I was just inspired by an event.
Indeed! We're at war with Spain.
It's not the time to boast
of an enemy's exploits.
But your niece liked it very much.
I know. It was clever
to dedicate it to her.
Take this down: "I forbid
the play The Cid
"to be performed again...
"until the Academy
has given its opinion."
Go, sir!
My deep respect, your Eminence.
Wait!
Here.
It's another comedy of mine
that you can develop as you like.
Just improve it
without changing the plot, please.
His play has ideas
that offend the state.
See that the Academy rejects it.
We must leave, your Eminence.
You'll be late for the council.
Dismounting!
Your Eminence!
Your Eminence, I must speak to you.
Just a word, please.
I'm in a hurry, Henri.
And I don't like the way
you show up like this.
I'm sorry, but it's important.
Come with me,
tell me on the way.
Are you mad?
I'm completely against it, Henri.
I'll never agree to it.
Nor will the king, or anyone else.
So Chavigny was right.
You've given in to the evil
charms of that conniving woman.
Is it possible
to be so blinded by passion?
This woman manipulates you, Henri,
and mocks you.
She has but one goal:
using you to hurt me.
Why else would she agree
to marry beneath her?
You will not plead my cause?
Never!
Don't say a word to his Majesty.
You're just a simple gentleman
elevated by me,
you exist only through me.
I order you to forget her
and devote yourself
to your mission: serving me.
You'll pay for this,
Monsieur de Richelieu.
The ingrate threatens me!
What have you done by introducing
me to the Marquis de Cinq-Mars?
I wanted only your happiness,
Sire.
Does the devil hide
behind his beauty?
He's afraid of nothing.
His insolence has no limits,
he's unaware of the respect
due a king.
You'll soon forget him, Sire.
Our armies must attack.
Portugal has risen up
against Madrid.
The Catalan ambassadors
are in Paris and ask you
to liberate their province.
I must congratulate you, sir.
Your patience has borne fruit.
I'll lead this expedition.
We'll push Spain back
across the Pyrenees.
I'll forget the disappointments
of Mr. de Cinq-Mars,
who is never where I seek him.
He's impulsive, but completely
devoted to you, your Majesty.
Don't refuse him your favor.
He takes advantage of my favor.
He takes advantage.
Monsieur de Cinq-Mars!
His Majesty has been looking
for you for hours.
- He's in a bad mood.
- That's not your concern.
Your horse!
Never mind. Here's his Majesty.
Leave us!
What is going on?
You're remiss in your duties.
I cannot put up with it.
Mr. de La Chesnaie told me
you ran off to the duchess.
She was my brother's mistress.
Is it true?
Yes, your Majesty. Are you going
to preach like Mr. de Richelieu?
What do I care
what the cardinal said!
Here's what the king says.
Give up this woman.
You'll gain honor
and not be drawn into
dastardly plots.
Can't I serve you and love her?
I won't tolerate it.
I don't want her to destroy you.
Forget her.
To console you,
if you promise to break it off,
I'll give you 1,500 crowns
and make you First Squire.
What do you say?
As Wardrobe Master,
this duty does not raise my status.
Then what will satisfy you?
Make me Grand Squire,
your Majesty.
Aren't I the son
of a marshal of France?
That is one of the most
prestigious titles, Henri.
Many illustrious men seek it.
But I'll grant it to you.
Be worthy of it.
I'll ride with you to Perpignan
which we'll besiege
together to take
Roussillon from the Spanish.
I'll fight to the death
beside you, Sire.
So I swear before God.
Stand up,
Grand Squire,
it's not about dying, but living.
Alive or dead, I'm yours, Sire.
And I give you my heart.
And I promise
no other will share it.
Well! What is it?
Be glad.
We will soon be joined
by the sacred bonds of marriage.
The king made me
his Grand Squire.
Tomorrow, I'll be a duke
and a French peer.
Congratulations, Grand Squire.
The king must love you.
Perhaps he'll make you
duke and supreme commander.
You forget the man
who won't let us marry.
I know, the cardinal.
He refused. He hates you
as much as you hate him.
I hate him
because he is ruining France.
Because he's made the king
his servant,
because he attacks the queen
and kills good Christians.
He has blood on his hands.
- We must stop him.
- How? The king trusts him.
But the king loves you.
You can tell him
the cardinal spies on him
and makes him a puppet.
He must know
who really controls the country.
Did I hear you right, Madame?
You ask me to betray
the man who helped me
and gave me the chance to meet you?
What loyalty do you owe
a man who forbids you to love?
Will we never be happy?
Must he tyrannize us
as he tyrannizes France?
The cardinal is using you, Henri.
You're just a pawn in his game.
And your happiness will last
only if you serve his plans.
Believe me.
By fighting him,
you'll avoid inevitable disgrace.
It's doomed to fail.
The king's faith in
the cardinal can't be shaken.
Then we must take other action.
How?
Do you love me, Henri?
Can you doubt it?
I love you too.
And in love,
the means do not matter.
Hurry!
The time has come, my friends.
The king leaves Paris tomorrow
with the army,
leaving the cardinal
to his dirty dealings.
This time, we won't fail.
The cardinal must not know...
I bring you a man
who is on our side, gentlemen.
You put us in great danger, Madame.
It's madness to bring
the cardinal's creature here.
He works for Richelieu.
Do you doubt my word?
That's enough.
Put away your swords.
I vouch for Mr. de Cinq-Mars.
It's true that the cardinal
aided in my happy destiny,
but he has asked for
too much in return.
I refused to spy on the king
and his ways disgust me.
I see that there is
too much blood spilled,
too many taxes,
and too much poverty.
Welcome, Grand Squire.
What do you think of
a pension of 40,000 crowns
from his Majesty Philip IV of Spain?
I think it sounds very good.
Consider it done.
I knew you'd join us.
Here's where things stand.
Fontrailles will leave
tonight for Madrid
with our treaty offer
for the king, stating that,
when the cardinal's death
is announced,
9,000 horsemen in Roussillon
will invade the kingdom
at my orders.
This is agreed by her Majesty
Queen Anne of Austria.
Don't speak the queen's name.
He's right.
The queen must never be
implicated in our actions.
Have no fear.
No one will leave
without swearing an oath.
Your swords, gentlemen.
Swear by the Holy Virgin
to always keep our plot secret
and never reveal our names
or that of the queen.
I swear!
If it's true that Cinq-Mars
has joined my enemies,
he'll pay for this betrayal.
- Should we arrest them?
- No.
I want to know what they're plotting
and catch them in the act.
How many are there?
About a dozen.
I recognize the queen's advisor.
He'll pay for it with his life.
For now, watch them
and keep me informed.
Your Eminence.
I never should've brought Henri
d'Effiat into the king's service.
I acted upon foolish emotion.
In politics,
you can't trust your feelings.
Wait before blaming him.
Perhaps he's working for us.
No. He's betrayed me, I know it.
And yet you warned me.
How could I imagine
he'd fall in love
with Marie de Gonzague?
My worst enemy.
He's in her power.
And Henri isn't Rodrigue.
His passion defeats his honor
and he'll betray me.
I can't believe it.
Your Eminence.
Your Eminence!
The viscount de Fontrailles was seen
in Orléans, disguised as a monk.
He's going to Spain.
How do you know?
His squire.
- He spoke but will speak no more.
- Very good.
Is Mr. d'Orléans still hiding
at Saint-Sulpice Abbey?
He hasn't left, your Eminence.
Let him stay there!
He can't pray enough
to save his soul.
Watch him.
My lord.
If Gaston d'Orléans' damned soul
runs to Madrid,
it's to tell our enemies
of our plans.
Places, gentlemen.
His Majesty arrives.
Well, Grand Squire!
What do you want?
His Majesty asked me
to attend the council, your Eminence.
You don't belong here,
Grand Squire.
Withdraw.
But the king...
I order you to leave, little marquis!
My orders suffice.
This is not the king's council,
it's a war council.
You're not an army officer
as far as I know.
War is not your concern.
For the last time,
leave this place immediately.
Where are you going?
Isn't it time for the council?
What's wrong?
You're so pale...
It's painful for me
to refuse you, Sire.
I wouldn't help you
by meeting with the captains
who lead your armies.
I don't have their knowledge
or experience of war.
I recognize
your pure and loyal heart.
We'll gather our troops here,
in Narbonne,
before entering Roussillon
at his Majesty's orders.
Go on, Monsieur de Richelieu.
I invited the Grand Squire,
but he thought himself unworthy.
We should praise his wisdom
and discernment.
I will tell him.
Well! How does our expedition look?
Very good, Sire.
Our forces are stronger.
The Duke d'Olivares
holds the fort of Rivesaltes
that we must take
before reaching Perpignan.
That could cause heavy losses.
Couldn't we count on some turncoats?
If we give pensions
to some townspeople,
they'll open the gates.
You read my mind, your Majesty.
My agents are working on it.
Gentlemen,
The French crown has an heir.
Long live Louis,
dauphin of France.
Marie!
Marie! It's decided.
I'll kill the cardinal myself.
Quiet. Do you want to go
to the Bastille?
- What fury!
- You will hear of it.
From rumors, alas.
I swear it.
He'll pay for insulting me.
Calm down!
No. I don't want calm,
I want revenge.
Not so rash.
The king loves you,
have him banish the cardinal.
Or better yet:
get his blessing to kill him.
Blessing or no blessing,
Richelieu will die.
I leave with his Majesty
for Narbonne.
I'll wait for the cardinal and do it.
Let his Highness know.
I fear for you, Henri.
Let the assassins
of the king of Spain do it.
You don't understand, Marie.
Not satisfied with
refusing our marriage,
Mr. de Richelieu besmirched my name
in front of the lords.
I won't be worthy of you
until I've killed him.
May God protect you!
If you succeed, Henri,
a great destiny awaits you.
Awaits us, Marie.
Never doubt my love.
I miss you already.
Come back safe and sound.
I can't take it anymore.
My legs are stiff as logs.
A 5-hour ride!
At this rate,
we'll be there in 1 week.
When does the cardinal leave Paris?
Tomorrow morning.
His rheumatism makes him
break up the trip.
He'll sleep here tomorrow,
at the mayor's,
inside the city walls.
Isn't he too old
to manage the government?
What do you mean?
You gave him this position
18 years ago.
Aren't you tired of these rebellions?
Of the blood he spills
for his own glory?
Such talk could land you
in the Bastille,
Henri.
I love you, so I speak my mind.
I'm not one of those flatterers
who talk behind your back.
That's true.
That's why I love and forgive you.
I know my prime minister's flaws
better than anyone.
I know his love
of the money he's amassed.
I know his vain pretentions
to write plays.
It's amusing to see him enraged
at Corneille's success
while he has The Cid banned
by his Academy out of jealousy.
I laugh at his ambition to build
an ideal city
named after himself:
Richelieu.
He prefers matters of state
to those of the church
and skips saying mass
to go see his mistresses,
the most beautiful women in Paris.
What is there to add?
That he likes shedding blood.
and cutting off the heads
of great nobles.
And killing your soldiers
on the battlefield,
and massacring your peasants
who rebel against poverty.
What is there to add?
That he likes spying
on everyone for better control.
Starting with his king.
The cardinal spies on me?
Your valet, Mr. de La Chesnaie,
goes to his palace on Tuesdays
to tell him
all your words and actions.
If that's true, his Eminence
must explain himself.
But have you by any chance
become his enemy?
Can't I both criticize
and love him, Sire?
Be careful.
Attacking him means attacking me.
You don't know what ruling
France is like.
The kingdom consists
of many peoples:
Normans, Bretons, Basques,
Burgundians, Picards, Provençals...
Making them agree to
a common destiny called France
and putting them under
a single authority:
that's the cardinal's ultimate plan.
Why give him so much power?
Aren't you the king?
With such an intelligent
man who wants France's glory
in my service,
I must step back, Henri.
But nothing is done
without my agreement.
The cardinal tells me what he does
every day.
We decide together.
And because of his good judgment
and trust in you
I can open my heart to you
without fear.
It's shameful!
How can a cardinal
make alliances with heretics
to fight my brother,
the very Catholic king?
Mr. de Richelieu's only religion
is serving the state.
Your Majesty, the Marquis de Mirabel
is here and would like to see you.
Show him in and leave us,
please.
Antonio. What news?
Here's the treaty
signed by the king, your brother,
your Majesty.
You and Gaston d'Orléans alone
have a copy.
Does he accept our conditions?
All of them, your Majesty.
God is with us.
Only one thing is lacking.
What is it?
The cardinal's death.
Have you lost your head,
Mademoiselle?
Coming here in the daytime.
Something is going on.
The queen has been agitated
for days.
She can't sleep
and is easily irritated.
You want to tell me
of the queen's moods?
That's not all.
Yesterday, the Marquis de Mirabel
came to see her.
Later that night,
her Majesty wouldn't let me
undress her for bed.
Well?
She must have been hiding
a document on her person
that she hid in her trunk
in the secret drawer.
Thank you for telling me this,
Mademoiselle.
Go back to her.
A plot is afoot.
And I suspect Anne of Austria
is part of it.
How can we be sure?
By attacking.
That's the best defense.
Your Majesty, his Eminence
would like to see you.
My God!
What can he want?
Don't make him wait.
Excuse my intrusion, your Majesty.
I came to pay my respects
before leaving to join the king.
I'm touched.
I know your time is precious
and your work is heavy.
Nothing would be possible
without the king's trust.
Yes.
I pray for his victory every day.
But it breaks my heart to see
so many Catholics kill each other,
when my brother offers peace.
I have a request, your Majesty.
"A request," your Eminence?
Before this journey
from which I may never return,
I'd like to greet the dauphin.
Of course.
Mademoiselle de Chémerault!
Your Majesty?
Ask Madame de Lansac
to bring the dauphin Louis
to the cardinal.
Right away, your Majesty.
I'll pray for your safe return,
your Eminence.
I'm sure that your fervent
and sincere prayers
will protect me.
May God protect your Highness!
Enjoy him before the king returns,
your Majesty.
What do you mean,
your Eminence?
Before he left,
the king told me
he won't let you
bring up the prince.
But why?
His Majesty is fed up
with your plotting
with France's enemies.
You understand he cannot
stand for the queen of France
to share intelligence
with those he is fighting.
Some at the Court even call it...
treason.
Take away my son?
I couldn't bear it.
A sign of good faith
would make his Majesty
give up this plan,
which he is reluctant to carry out.
You will have it,
Monsieur de Richelieu.
Father! Father!
What's going on?
You must save me, Father.
The king and the cardinal
suspect me of treason.
They threaten
to take away my child.
Calm down, your Highness.
No one will talk.
We all took an oath.
Oaths are worth little in prison.
You must help me, Father.
- What can I do?
- Here.
Take this document.
Get it into the cardinal's hands.
- How?
- It doesn't matter.
No one must know
how he came by it.
Or it's death for you.
Trust me.
How can I refuse you, your Majesty?
At dawn, I'll send
one of my monks.
He won't speak, for he's mute.
God bless you, Father.
Bishop's Palace in Narbonne
Welcome, Count.
Thank you, your Excellency.
Victory!
Long live the king!
Take care of the wounded.
Come, let me kiss you.
I've never seen such courage.
- I only did my duty.
- More than that.
But promise
you'll risk your life no more.
I can't lose you.
My life doesn't count, Sire.
Think only of your glory.
How I love you! Come.
Let's celebrate your exploits.
Count, here you are finally!
Where's my prime minister?
Resting in Narbonne.
His rheumatism pains him.
He'll be happy to see you
if you go there.
We'll go, Count.
Let's celebrate the Grand Squire,
who took the fort of Rivesaltes,
an incredible feat.
Congratulations, Monsieur.
You should've seen his energy
as he led his men.
He seemed immortal.
Alas, we suffered losses.
The essential thing is that
you're alive.
Monsieur de Chavigny,
tell his Eminence we'll come see him.
I want to tell him of our victory.
If Henri d'Effiat shone in battle
as you say,
we should be glad, Chavigny.
It was time he did something.
Indeed.
The king showers him with praise
and has never been so taken with him.
What is that?
A mixture of frog and bat secretions
that a Jewish doctor recommended.
Fine. We're a step away from heresy.
Who are you?
Wait.
Stop him!
By the devil's horns!
He's dead.
Well, Chavigny!
Did you see the devil?
Almost, my lord. Look at this.
The seal of the house of Austria.
- What is this?
- I don't know.
It was given to me by a monk
who killed himself
rather than be taken.
He must've had a good reason
to prefer hell to heaven.
By the Holy Spirit!
It's impossible.
Well?
This is high treason, Chavigny.
A conspiracy as never seen in France.
What exactly?
A shameful treaty
signed in great secrecy
between the king of Spain
and Gaston of France.
To stab us in the back.
The traitor sold
the kingdom to our enemies.
All the names are here:
Duke de Bouillon,
Count de Fontrailles, and guess who?
The Marquis de Cinq-Mars.
A serpent that I raised myself.
An ingrate given glory
who kisses the king
even as he kills him.
It's an unspeakable crime.
We must take action.
We will, Chavigny. Don't worry.
I'd like to know
who brought us this evidence
for the upcoming trial.
Should I take it to the king?
No. I must show it to him myself.
Otherwise you'd be in danger.
In danger?
He is so blinded by his passion
for Cinq-Mars
that he'll call you a liar
and have you killed.
Your Majesty.
What joy to see you,
my dear minister!
Have you heard the news?
Thanks to the Grand Squire,
the way is clear
for the siege of Perpignan.
I'm glad, your Majesty.
My warmest congratulations,
Grand Squire.
His bravery was so outstanding
that I gave him
the command of our army.
That's not appropriate, your Majesty.
Excuse me?
Why not?
Many generals with titles
grander than that of marquis
will be insulted.
Their titles are not titles of glory.
Do you seek to anger me?
Am I king, yes or no?
Do you doubt my ability to decide
who should lead our army?
Don't insist, Sire.
Mr. de Richelieu thinks I'm unworthy
of dying on a battlefield.
I judge you for what you are,
Mr. de Cinq-Mars.
Explain yourself, your Eminence.
I have nothing to say to you. Leave.
I must speak to the king.
My word, your Eminence!
Believe me, your Majesty.
I must speak to you now
of an extremely important matter.
This is the last time
you show me the door, sir.
Finally, something we can agree on.
Henri!
I'm very displeased, your Eminence.
You know my affection for him.
Why treat him that way
in front of me?
Here's my answer, your Majesty.
It's not possible.
This is a crude forgery.
Alas, Sire.
Those are indeed
the signatures of Philip IV
and your brother.
And the seal
is from the house of Austria.
"It is decided that
his Majesty Philip IV
"will deal only with his Highness
Gaston of France
"and that Spain will recover
all the forts that
"King Louis XIII has..."
If this treachery is real,
it's the most vile treason.
What did I do to my brother
that he should plot against me?
You reign, your Majesty.
He was always my mother's favorite.
Marie de Medici
made him unreliable,
a fickle man who fucked
all the women of my Court!
Finish reading, your Majesty.
You don't yet know all.
"150,000-crown pension
for his Highness Gaston d'Orléans,
"20,000 crowns
for the viscount de Fontrailles,
"40,000 crowns
for the Grand Squire..."
No.
It's impossible.
This is not true.
It's another one of your schemes!
I won't be fooled.
This time you've gone too far.
What do you accuse me of,
your Majesty?
Of adding his name
to this shameful conspiracy.
You hate him
because he won't serve you.
He told me so.
You're capable of such deception,
sir.
Accusing Henri d'Effiat
of high treason
when he just risked his life
at Rivesaltes...
it makes no sense.
That's possible, your Majesty.
I'd like to believe it.
But the kingdom is at stake
and you must not hesitate.
You must sign prison orders,
so our soldiers
can seize these traitors.
We can release the Grand Squire
when he proves his innocence.
But if he's guilty, he will flee.
Let's keep my brother
from doing more harm.
He's the soul of the plot.
It won't be easy.
But knowing his vanity,
we've perfected a trap
that will bring him to us.
I'll kill him!
I tell you, I'll...
I'll kill him tonight.
You should've done it just now.
In front of the king?
That's impossible.
But I'll do it tonight.
I'll smother him in his sleep,
and no one will miss him.
From someone who wishes you well.
"You're in danger. Flee."
Big news.
You're mad!
It's the king's handwriting.
Why not the Pope's?
Good God, save yourself!
Don't you see you're in danger,
despite the king's friendship?
I don't fear the cardinal.
We found him in a tavern.
The king will punish you
for this humiliation,
Cardinal.
Tonight you'll be taken
to Lyon and secretly put
in the royal fort of Pierre-Encise,
until your accomplices join you,
Grand Squire.
What accomplices?
What are you talking about?
Take him away!
Wait. What do you accuse me of?
Your Eminence! Answer.
I want to see the king.
I want to see Louis.
Château of the Duke de Lorraine
You here?
Greetings, your Highness.
I've ridden for 6 days
to bring you an order from the king.
From my brother? I'm listening.
He wants you to command
the army of Champagne
to defend our borders
against the Spanish.
Here's his letter naming you general.
I will heed my brother's call.
I'll saddle my horse
and come with you. My sword!
Thank the duke, gentlemen.
And safe travels.
Your Highness, please,
give me your sword.
What, Count?
Upon the king's order,
I arrest you!
Your Majesty, Mr. de Thou
needs to speak with you urgently.
We've been betrayed.
My God! How is it possible?
A copy of the treaty
fell into the cardinal's hands.
It's a betrayal.
"A betrayal"?
By whom?
Will we ever know?
Farewell. I must leave
France before I'm arrested.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, open up!
King's orders.
It's too late. Farewell, Madame.
I love you
and will never reveal your name,
even under questioning.
Thank you, my friend.
May God protect you!
Your Majesty!
I have orders to arrest Mr. de Thou.
Well, go ahead, captain! Go ahead!
I'm yours, Monsieur d'Artagnan.
Perpignan is ours, Sire.
The admiral's ships
have destroyed the Spanish fleet.
And the people opened the gates.
The Spanish are fleeing
for the Pyrenees.
That's good, Tréville.
What news of the Grand Squire?
"The Grand Squire"?
He was arrested, Sire.
"Arrested"? Arrested, you say?
His Eminence took him to Lyon
to be tried.
Maybe that's best.
He'll soon be declared innocent.
It cannot be otherwise.
To your horses!
To Lyon!
Royal Prison of Lyon
How you've disappointed me.
As you have me, my lord.
Your insolence won't save you.
I'm not the king.
That's certain.
You have neither his imagination
nor his deep soul.
You don't know me well.
I know your heart is barren
and that's enough.
What are you made of?
Is there blood in your veins?
Enough that I believed in you,
but you're not what I hoped.
You did not inherit
your father's moral values.
I forbid you to speak
of my father or of morals.
The game is over, Henri.
No more indulgence.
You're in the hands of justice.
What "justice"?
Yours?
Which condemns before the trial?
I'm only guilty of loving a duchess
and being loved by the king.
Very little indeed.
How could you get involved
in this conspiracy
betraying France to Spain?
Was it love
for the Duchess de Nevers
or hatred for me,
though I treated you like a son?
"A son"?
You deceive yourself, sir.
You know nothing of a father's love.
A father wants
only his child's happiness.
But you, charitable soul,
want to have spies everywhere
and people to serve you.
Bringing you into the sublime
workings of my politics
was my greatest sign of love.
Is politics everything to you?
Farewell.
The chancellor will question you.
I have nothing to say to him.
Think it over.
Your life is at stake.
His Majesty will free me.
He knows what love is.
I was impressed by the ruse
you used to offer me these...
lovely lodgings,
Monsieur du Plessis.
What does my brother accuse me of
this time?
Something that threatens
your very life.
You have committed
a crime against the state
that cannot be pardoned.
Impossible, your Eminence.
As God is my witness, I've always
been loyal to France and the king.
Do you know this treaty?
It's signed by you
and King Philip IV of Spain.
Who gave you this?
The only way to save yourself
is to make a full confession.
I'll tell all, your Eminence,
if the king will pardon me.
The names of those who took part
in this high treason?
Yes. Starting with the Grand Squire
who is the mastermind.
I expected more nobility
from the son of Henri IV.
It's true that you've
already sold many of your friends.
I said only the truth, as you asked.
To each his own truth, your Highness.
What do you mean?
I'm a prince of the blood.
The king alone can judge my actions!
Your Majesty!
I must speak with you.
In private.
What is it?
We must save the Grand Squire.
The cardinal has arrested him.
Are you in love with
Mr. de Cinq-Mars? I can't believe it.
It doesn't matter
whether or not I love him.
I don't want him to die.
You're losing your head, Marie.
The king loves him too much.
He'll never let the cardinal
go so far.
I already told his Eminence
I have nothing to say.
It doesn't matter.
Here's the statement
of his Highness, Duke d'Orléans.
He accuses you of many crimes.
Another of the cardinal's tricks.
Read it yourself.
And see the signature at the bottom.
Does a prince's oath mean nothing?
I believed in him
and he sends me to my death.
You cannot trust the powerful,
Marquis.
They play with our lives.
But you can save yours.
Tell us how and why
you got involved in this crime.
Where is he? I want to see
the Grand Squire right now!
That's impossible, Sire.
The chancellor is questioning him
now in prison.
He'll go free. Henri is innocent.
My respects, your Majesty.
Well, sir,
have you released the Grand Squire?
He's guilty, Sire.
That's impossible.
He just admitted his crimes.
Look, Sire.
These are lies!
Henri couldn't betray me.
I know him.
He's a pure soul led astray
by my cunning brother.
You're the guilty one.
You can't forgive him
for loving me more than you.
Your resentment isn't motivated
by the kingdom,
but by your bitter heart.
You want revenge against this child
whom you pampered
but whose love you lost.
Isn't that true,
Monsieur de Richelieu ?
You are confused, Majesty.
My only concern
is for your safety and glory.
You couldn't stand him leaving you
or me loving him.
Or that he's free as a bird.
You rejected him,
humiliated him,
made him desperate.
And you'll condemn him
to make him disappear forever.
I want the king's justice
to punish
those who threaten state security.
Mr. de Cinq-Mars,
along with Mr. de Thou,
is guilty of high treason.
He must die.
My only mistake
was introducing him to you.
So you're as guilty as he is.
I demand the Grand Squire
be set free.
In that case, Sire,
you must free me
of my government duties.
What? You'll put
your ministry at stake?
Have I any choice?
A king must prefer justice to pity.
Henri d'Effiat must die
for betraying you and France.
No!
I won't have it.
I won't allow it.
Others have died for less.
Do you know no pity?
You would compromise
all that we've built for years,
your Majesty.
Will you put your authority
and the unity
of the kingdom in danger?
Forget your heart
and its passions, Sire.
Sign,
and think of your subjects
who want justice
to protect them from traitors,
even those who are handsome,
young, and charming. Sign.
Be strong with me.
As we've always been.
Sign.
You know I'm right.
Will I never have peace?
Only the peace of the kingdom
counts, Sire.
By signing,
you aren't striking a head,
but raising your throne.
Are you satisfied,
Prime Minister?
You have your enemies' head.
I have no enemies
but those of the state, Sire.
Where are you going?
To Paris, your Majesty,
where the university leaders
wait for me
to inaugurate the new Sorbonne
we have built.
It's not a humane task
to rule France, Chavigny.
You've given France your all
for 18 years, your Eminence.
It's never been so powerful.
There's still much to be done.
And my remaining time is short.
Positions!
Lift!
March!
Leave!
Get out, all of you! All!
No.
I want to die with my eyes open.
God knows I loved that child.
Subtitles: Eclair Group