Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www.addic7ed.com
- Stupid changeling.
- Think fast!
Get out the trash.
Only an Impure would be stupid
enough to raise Angor Rot.
Gunmar can't save him now.
Not so tough without
your assassin, are ye?
- Guilty changeling!
- Fire!
- You throw like a sloth-kin.
- Stupid changeling.
Let's get him down from there
and really have some fun.
Jim? Jim! James Lake Junior!
She allowed Angor Rot
to obtain a Horngazel.
The very key past
Trollmarket's defenses?
It's not Claire's fault, it's mine.
I should've gone to the
school for the incantation.
I should've faced Angor Rot. Not them.
It was in my purse. Toby and
I were dangling off the roof.
He cut it off and left.
It was a great everyday
purse. It went with everything.
We might have time. Angor Rot
rarely attacks during the day...
Angor Rot is unpredictable at best.
And if there isn't anything to stop him
from creating havoc in Trollmarket...
then you have just put more
than yourselves at risk.
Trollhunter! Help!
- Get out of our way, Aaarrrgghh!!!
- No.
Let us discuss this matter
like reasonable trolls!
Ruffians! Who threw that?
Where's Jim? He gave me his word!
Put him down! He helped save my mother.
- He's with me.
- He tried to release Gunmar!
Get him out of here!
Changelings ain't right in Trollmarket!
Get rid of him!
It's not going to make a
difference. Angor Rot wants me too,
and the protective
barrier won't stop him.
Hmm.
- What do you mean?
- He has a Horngazel.
Look, you have a right to know!
Let's throw them both out!
It's time the amulet calls for another!
- Jimbo!
- It's not his fault!
- Throw them out!
- When you finish throwing them out...
- What's he doing?
... come back and throw me out, too.
Yes, the boy has made grave errors.
But he's come through for us more
times than I give him credit for.
Trollmarket is in danger...
and our greatest defense has
always been our Trollhunter.
He's earned my trust. He
should have earned yours.
- You can throw me out, too!
- And me.
Us too, though technically,
we don't live here.
- I'm just sayin'.
- Same for me.
I've always stood with our Trollhunter.
Okay, yeah.
- I have to admit, it's true.
- Mm.
What now, our infallible leader?
Now, we get ready to give Angor Rot...
the fight of his life!
- Pile them as high as you can!
- More gnomes!
Don't worry, just stay indoors.
Not everyone has to fight.
Whatever.
- Toby, we have to tell Jim.
- Tell me what?
Tell who what? Nothing to see here.
Chompsky? No way! When did he get out?
A little while ago.
We were gonna tell you,
but with everything and your mom...
Why would you hold back the great
news? He escaped the Darklands!
Uh, technically, he didn't.
Gunmar let him out to deliver a message.
Jim, Gunmar knows you killed his son.
And he promises to make a river...
no, an ocean of blood
from your loved ones.
And he's gonna make a throne.
with their... I think he said bones.
His words. Not mine.
And... and he included a list.
Tobias. Claire. Barbara. Blinkous.
We knew what we were getting
into. After we find the last stone,
we'll find my brother and
end this once and for all.
Draal. Coach Lawrence.
It goes on for a while. You
don't need to listen to this.
It's like you said, we shouldn't
be focused on the fight tomorrow
but the fight today.
It's too bad we've been wasting our
time collecting stones to kill Gunmar
and not Angor Rot.
Or so you think.
Maybe you do have a stone. Angor's eye.
You're saying I can
use this in my amulet?
Jim, you're gonna level up again!
- If cut with the proper guidance.
- Show me where to cut.
Unlock its dark power, and you'll
be able to ward off his magics.
Cleave here, ever so gently.
Ah-ha!
Stubborn hammer!
We're supposed to be on the same team!
Ah!
Uh!
Follow that facet there.
Careful now, you only
have one chance at this.
Angor Rot? What's that
old fossil gonna do?
There's three of us and one of him.
I'm gonna break him over
my knee. Back breaker!
And then when he's trying
to get up, power bomb! Boom!
And then he's like, "No,
stop!" I'll be like...
I am not afraid of death, Father.
For in the afterlife,
I shall see you again.
Are you sure there isn't
anything more I can do?
The other trolls don't
trust fighting alongside you.
And honestly, neither do I.
You kept your word. And
after everything I've done.
Once again, you've proved why you are...
the hero, and I am...
- Someone who can change.
- Your idealism is nearly contagious.
- My gratitude cannot be enough.
- Gee, a friendship rock?
After you're done with Angor's eye,
I thought you could use Gunmar's.
You need the last Triumbric
stone to defeat Gunmar.
I've been holding onto it for centuries.
I kept it close in case you drove
a hard bargain to protect me.
But if I kill Gunmar...
Save the children? Yes,
if you rescue my familiar,
then I'll be trapped in
my troll form forever.
But there's nothing left
for me in the human world.
It's not like I'll ever
have a future with your mo...
Don't.
- I have overstayed my welcome.
- Thank you.
You may not believe me, Young Atlas...
but I do wish you luck and
hope we meet again one day.
Goodbye, Mr. Strickler.
Hurry! Protect yourselves! Everyone!
Is he knocking? Is that some
sort of troll war etiquette?
I believe he's attempting
to intimidate us.
He's expecting us to hide. I
say we take the fight to him.
Draal, hold the stairs. Blink,
Claire, Tobes, protect Trollmarket.
- Aaarrrgghh!!!, Not Enrique, with me.
- I'm rather comfy where I am.
Ya brute!
Huh?
For the glory of Merlin,
Daylight is mine to command.
We're not letting him past
us! What the... Watch out!
Wowza, big guy, let's keep
it PG. Where's Angor Rot?
It's a diversion! He must
be coming in another way!
- Other way?
- The Gyre Station!
What happened? Where's Angor Rot?
- There he is! Let's do this, boys!
- Back breaker!
Power bomb?
- Angor!
- Hmm?
Trollhunter, I have some
friends I'd like you to meet.
- What's that noise?
- It's an earthquake!
You handle Angor. We got this.
There's so many of them!
When will you learn that
Daylight is mine to command?
No!
Guess I should thank you
for giving me the stink-eye.
My eye!
- Shh!
- Huh?
Feel the wrath of the Warhammer!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Watch out!
Uh...
Oops! Sorry!
No!
Excellent work, pudgebag.
Oy! No one lays a hand
on my sister! Ya brute!
- You saved my life, bro.
- Let's not get sentimental.
You destroyed my soul, Hunter...
now I shall harvest yours!
Oh, I enjoy this horn!
It's not "Hunter," Angor.
- It's "Hunters"!
- Eat chrome!
Got him!
I drove! Did you see? I
drove a human automobile!
What a thrill!
Blinky.
Out of the way! Out
of the way! Incoming!
You thought I could be
defeated that easily?
That your human
contraption could kill me?
Where are they all coming from?
We're surrounded!
There's too many of them!
Aaarrrgghh!!! We require your strength!
No! Stop it! Please, don't!
Toby!
No!
Aaarrrgghh!!!
- Aaarrrgghh!!!?
- Wingman.
Aaarrrgghh!!!
- We are still in battle.
- Aaarrrgghh!!!
Oh, no.
I'm going to kill you!
I destroyed your soul! Your
fight is with me! Not them!
As you wish, Trollhunter.
Clever Hunter!
Just you and me now.
The Hero's Forge.
More like a coward's grave.
Enough of your games.
Do you ever wonder how
you've lived this long?
- Master Jim!
- No! Let us in!
The only reason you're alive
is because you've let your
loved ones fall in your place!
Your teacher, the
changeling! Your mother!
No! Jim!
And now your simple friend,
Aaarrrgghh!!!, is dead!
No!
But where are your
loved ones now, Hunter?
Up here, Rot Head!
Angor Rot is defeated!
Trollmarket is protected once again!
Jim!
- Is he really gone?
- He better be.
Yeah. He better be.
- Finally.
- Our souls are free.
We return to our brethren.
What... I mean, who are they?
These are the spirits
of our fallen brethren.
Trollhunters who lost both
soul and life to Angor Rot.
Our brothers and sisters shall
take their proper place in the void
and rest in peace.
Thanks to you, James Lake
Junior, and your friends.
You were right, you
are stronger together.
We are in your debt.
But the day will come, Trollhunter,
when you must finish the fight alone.
Father?
My son, I am so sorry
for pushing you away.
I am so proud of you.
Father.
Father. Father!
Return to our brethren.
Our souls are free!
Toby, hold onto that anger.
Save it for the Darklands.
Jim.
In darkest tide, when
Daylight darest wane...
the Myrddin Wylt
obscured a shadow's bane.
Three forces elemental thou must seek.
In marshland, caverns
deep and mountain's peak.
Where worthy perish,
ye'll prevail in night.
And eclipse all who
quarry with thy might.
For the doom of Gunmar,
Eclipse is mine to command!
Master Jim!
Dude, what are you doing? Jim, don't!
Jim, no! You promised we'd go together!
The amulet chose me. I
can't lose any more of you.
Maybe I can manually override the lock.
Whoa.
Come on, Jimbo! We're
a team! Don't do this!
I'm sorry. I have to finish the fight.
Alone.
But the amulet chose me.
- Jim!
- I'm sorry.
No! Jim!
Jim!
Master Jim, what have you done?
Get ready, Gunmar.
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www.addic7ed.com